[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "Which type of database management system is MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Object-oriented",
            "b) Hierarchical",
            "c) Relational",
            "d) Network"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MySQL is a ‘relational’ DBMS. It is efficient at relating data in two different tables and joining information from them. Hierarchical and Network DBMS are based on parent-child relationships of records. Object-oriented DBMS use objects to represent models."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "What is data in a MySQL database organized into?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Objects",
            "b) Tables",
            "c) Networks",
            "d) File systems"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since MySQL is an RDBMS, it’s data is organised in tables for establishing relationships. A table is a collection of rows and columns, where each row is a record and columns describe the feature of records."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "What represents an ‘attribute’ in a relational database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Row",
            "c) Column",
            "d) Object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL is free and open source. It’s source code is available for use and is freely downloadable. It includes the MySQL Server, the world’s most popular open source database, and MySQL Cluster, a real-time, open source transactional database."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "What represents a ‘tuple’ in a relational database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Row",
            "c) Column",
            "d) Object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Each column in a table represents a feature (attribute) of a record. Table stores the information for an entity whereas a row represents a record. Object has no relevance in an RDBMS."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "How is communication established with MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL",
            "b) Network calls",
            "c) A programming language like C++",
            "d) APIs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Each row in a table represents a record. A tuple is a collection of attribute values that makes a record unique. A tuple is a unique entity whereas attribute values can be duplicate in the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "7. What does ‘name’ represent in the following SQL code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> student\n   <span class=\"br0\">(</span>\n       name <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n       roll_num <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n       address <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n       phone <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">12</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n   <span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) A table",
            "b) A row",
            "c) A column",
            "d) An object"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SQL is the standard language for RDBMS systems like MySQL. SQL queries facilitate quick information retrieval from tables and other elementary operations required to maintain an RDBMS system."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "Which is the MySQL instance responsible for data processing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MySQL client",
            "b) MySQL server",
            "c) SQL",
            "d) Server daemon program"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘name’, ‘roll_num’, ‘address’ and ‘phone’ are the attributes in the table ‘student’. The CREATE TABLE construct in SQL creates a table, assigns a name to it and its attributes, and specifies the type of fields used in the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "The MySQL server used in its client/server architecture is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqla",
            "b) mysqlb",
            "c) mysqlc",
            "d) mysqld"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL uses client-server architecture. The MySQL server program runs on the machine where databases are stored. SQL is a query language used for querying the tables and information retrieval."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "In MySQL databases, the structure representing the organizational views of the entire databases is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Schema",
            "b) View",
            "c) Instance",
            "d) Table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: mysqld is the MySQL server program. It serves the incoming client requests by accessing the database. The others are not valid MySQL programs. MySQL implements a client/server architecture wherein mysqld is the server program."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "Which of the following clauses is used to display information that match a given pattern?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIKE",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) IS",
            "d) SAME"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘LIKE’ clause filters information that match a given pattern. ‘WHERE’ clause selects information that is specified by a condition. ‘IS’ is used to match the exact condition specified. "
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "2. What column names are displayed when this SQL command is executed?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SHOW</span> <span class=\"kw1\">COLUMNS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> tbl_name <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> <span class=\"st0\">'%name'</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) suffixed with ‘name’",
            "b) prefixed with ‘name’",
            "c) suffixed with ‘%name’",
            "d) prefixed with ‘%name’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The wildcard ‘%’ is used to indicate that any number of characters can replace it. All column names that end in ‘name’ are displayed. Additional information of columns like type and size are listed."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "The special database that always exists after setting up MySQL in a computer is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sampdb",
            "b) mysql",
            "c) information_schema",
            "d) readme_db"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: After installation of MySQL, ‘information_schema’ is the special database that always exists. ‘mysql’ can be seen depending on access rights. It holds the grant tables. ‘sampdb’ and ‘readme_db’ do not exist by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "4. In the following SQL code, InnoDB is __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> student <span class=\"br0\">(</span>\n\t\tname <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\tstudent_id <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\t<span class=\"kw1\">PRIMARY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">KEY</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>student_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n\t<span class=\"br0\">)</span> ENGINE <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> InnoDB;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) database name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) reference engine",
            "d) storage engine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘InnoDB’ is the name of the ‘storage engine’ for the above table. The ‘ENGINE’ clause is used to specify the name of the storage engine that MySQL should use to handle the table being created. MySQL has several storage engines with its own properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "5. Identify the table name in the following SQL statement.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> student <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'Kyle'</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">'M'</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Student",
            "b) Values",
            "c) Kyle",
            "d) M"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘INSERT INTO’ clause here inserts a row in the table named ‘student’. The table has three fields. The first field or attribute value in the row/tuple is ‘Kyle’. The second attribute value is ‘M’ and the last attribute is set to NULL."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "6. What is ‘xyz’ in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> abc <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> xyz;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) table name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SELECT clause is used to retrieve information from some specified tables. It follows a specified format for information retrieval. Here, ‘abc’ can be a column name. It must be present in the table ‘xyz’."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "Which operator is used to perform integer divisions in MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) /",
            "b) \\",
            "c) DIV",
            "d) //"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The operator ‘DIV’ is used to perform integer divisions in MySQL. ‘//’ is used in languages like Python to do the same. The operator ‘/’ performs floating point divisions and ‘\\’ is facilitates escape sequences."
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "The NULL value also means ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) value equal to zero",
            "b) unknown value",
            "c) negative values",
            "d) a large value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The NULL value in MySQL is a special value. It represents ‘no value’ or an ‘unknown value’. A NULL value can’t be compared like normal known values since it gives undesirable results."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "What does comparing a known value with NULL result into?",
        "Options": [
            "a) zero",
            "b) a positive value",
            "c) a negative value",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, NULL is not comparable to other known values. It will result in a NULL when compared to any value. The following statement would result in four NULLs: ‘SELECT NULL = 0, NULL < 0, NULL <> 0, NULL > 0’."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to sort query elements?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GROUP",
            "b) GROUP BY",
            "c) ORDER",
            "d) ORDER BY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An ‘ORDER BY’ clause specifies the sort order. The data is sorted in ascending order by default. To sort in descending order, the keyword DESC is appended to the ‘ORDER BY’ clause. ‘GROUP BY’ is used to group the query results according to the criteria."
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "2. The number of attributes in the following SQL table is ______________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> employee <span class=\"br0\">(</span>\n\t\temp_name <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\temp_id <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span>\n\t<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 30",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL operates using a client/server architecture. It is the server that runs on the machine and not the client. The clients connect to the MySQL server to request information from the database(s). "
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "Which of the following options tells mysql to ask for entering the password?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -e",
            "b) -p",
            "c) -u",
            "d) -h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The name of the table created is ’employee’. It has two attributes, namely, ’emp_name’ and ’emp_id’. The attributes are the columns in a table. emp_name is of type string and emp_id is of type integer."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "4. What is the host name in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>h cobra<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>snake<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>net <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>u sampadam</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) cobra.snake",
            "b) cobra.snake.net",
            "c) sampadam",
            "d) cobra"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The command ‘mysql -p’ (alternative form: –password) prompts for the password. ‘-h’ (alternative form: –host) specifies the host where the MySQL server is running. ‘-u’ is for specifying the username."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "5. What is ‘tamp’ in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>h xyz<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>host<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>try<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>net <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>u tamp</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) user name",
            "b) password",
            "c) host name",
            "d) table name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘-h’ option specifies the hostname of the server. The ‘cobra.snake.net’ is the complete host name. The ‘-p’ option prompts for the account’s password and ‘-u’ specifies the user name."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "The query ‘SELECT NOW()’ shows the current _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) table",
            "b) time only",
            "c) date only",
            "d) date and time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘tamp’ is the name of the user. The user will be prompted for password due to the ‘-p’ option. ‘xyz.host.try’ is the host name here. The entire command specifies the host-user pair and prompts for password to establish the connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "Suppose you want to select a database named ‘sampledb’ as the default database. Which of the following commands do you use?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT DATABASE()",
            "b) SELECT DATABASE sampledb",
            "c) USE DATABASE sampledb",
            "d) USE sampledb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SELECT NOW() is an SQL query. It shows both the current date and the current time. It is generally displayed in the format ‘yyyy-mm-dd hh-mm-ss’. For example, 2009-04-21 11-51-36."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "8. What does ‘abc’ & ‘xyz’ specify in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> abc <span class=\"br0\">(</span>xyz<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) table name and column specs",
            "b) column specs and table name",
            "c) table name and number of columns",
            "d) table name and number of rows"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘USE sampledb’ selects sampledb as the default database. Initially, ‘SELECT DATABASE();’ command displays ‘NULL’, since no database is selected by default. The other two are not valid commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "To see the table structure, which of the following SQL commands is issued?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESCRIBE tbl_name",
            "b) VIEW tbl_name",
            "c) SELECT TABLE tbl_name",
            "d) SELECT tbl_name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘CREATE TABLE’ construct’s syntax is ‘CREATE TABLE tbl_name (column_specs)’. ‘tbl_name’ indicates the table name. ‘column_specs’ provides the specifications of the table attributes."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "The command to move the cursor to the beginning of line in MySQL input editor is?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ctrl-A",
            "b) Ctrl-E",
            "c) Ctrl-D",
            "d) Esc-a"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Control-A moves the cursor to the beginning of the line. Ctrl-E moves the cursor to the end of the line. Control-D deletes the character under the cursor whereas Esc-a is not valid."
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "What does Control-_ do in MySQL input editor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) copies to clipboard",
            "b) pastes from clipboard",
            "c) undoes last change",
            "d) deletes the current line"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Control-_ undoes the last change that was made. This can be repeated. The mysql input editor has a variety of commands to facilitate editing while providing inputs to the command line itself."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "On UNIX, statements entered in ‘MySQL’ are saved in which file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .mysql_queries",
            "b) .queries",
            "c) .mysql_history",
            "d) .history"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Statements entered in ‘MySQL’ are stored in the file named ‘.mysql_history’. This file is located in the home directory itself. The SQL statements can be directly pasted into this file."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "Suppose run_me.sh is a script file. Which command is used to make it executable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) chmod +e run_me.sh",
            "b) chmod +a run_me.sh",
            "c) chmod +y run_me.sh",
            "d) chmod +x run_me.sh"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL is capable of reading input from a file in batch mode. This is also known as the non-interactive mode. A lot of typing and time can be saved when commands are stored in a file and executed from a file. "
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "To execute the contents of a query file ‘exec.sql’ by feeding it to mysql, which command is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql exec.sql > sampdb",
            "b) mysql sampdb < exec.sql",
            "c) mysql exec.sql",
            "d) mysql exec"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The command ‘chmod +x file_name’ makes a script file executable. mysql supports reading from a script file and executing queries from it. Before a script is run, it is necessary for it to be made executable."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "Which option prints output in table-format when MySQL is run interactively?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -t",
            "b) -tf",
            "c) -p",
            "d) -pf"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mysql queries can be run after placing the queries in a file, and then executing it by feeding it to mysql. By default, mysql prints output in a tab-delimited format when it is running in noninteractive mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "The clause that enables mapping a short command to a long command is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) map",
            "b) direct",
            "c) label",
            "d) alias"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL produces output in tab-delimited format when it is run in batch mode. Suppose a table-format output is desired, the -t option is used along with the mysql command. -tf is not a valid option."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "In UNIX, the name of the option file is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) .my.cnf",
            "b) .my.ini",
            "c) .my.opt",
            "d) .my.opc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the shell program permits an alias, a short command can be mapped to a long command. This reduces the time taken by typing long commands frequently. An alias is defined by the keyword ‘alias’ followed by the short and long commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "The system variable in MySQL server that enables to configure the SQL mode is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sql_config",
            "b) sql_mode",
            "c) sql_server",
            "d) sql_enable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The system variable ‘sql_mode’ is used by the MySQL server to configure the SQL mode. It has an impact on various aspects of the SQL statement executions. The other variables do not exist in the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "How do the STRICT_ALL_TABLES and STRICT_TRANS_TABLES mode values deal with bad data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) reject them",
            "b) accept them",
            "c) change them to the closest legal value and accept",
            "d) change them to the closest legal value and reject"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The MySQL server system variable ‘sql_mode’ can be set up globally. In this way, individual clients would have the ability to change their connection to the server. This variable can affect several aspects of statement executions."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "Which mode tells the server to recognize double quote as an identifier quoting character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANSI_DQ",
            "b) ANSI_QUOTES",
            "c) ANSI_RECG_QUOTES",
            "d) ANSI_RECG_DQUOTES"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘STRICT_ALL_TABLES’ and ‘STRICT_TRANS_TABLES’ are the MySQL server mode values that deal with bad data in a ‘strict’ manner. They do not make any change to the data. It is simply rejected."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "Which mode tells the server to recognize || as the string concatenation operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PIPES_AS_CONCAT",
            "b) ORS_AS_CONCAT",
            "c) DOUBLE_PIPE_AS_CONCAT",
            "d) LOGIC_OR_AS_CONCAT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘ANSI_QUOTES’ is the MySQL server mode value stored in the system variable which directs the MySQL server to treat the double quote character as a quoting character for identifiers. The others are not valid mode values."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "Which of these modes is a composite server mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMPOSITE",
            "b) COMPOSITE_MODE",
            "c) COMPOSITE_SERVER",
            "d) ANSI"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘PIPES_AS_CONCAT’, one of the many MySQL server mode values stored in the system variable would direct the server to treat the pipe characters as the standard SQL string concatenation operator rather than the logical or. The rest mode values are invalid."
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "Which of the following commands sets the SQL mode as TRADITIONAL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –sqlmode=’TRADITIONAL’",
            "b) –sql_mode=’TRADITIONAL’",
            "c) –sql-mode=’TRADITIONAL’",
            "d) –sql.mode=’TRADITIONAL’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘ANSI’ mode value is a composite mode. It turns on several other mode values like ANSI_QUOTES, PIPES_AS_CONCAT. This makes the server behave much like standard SQL than the default mode."
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "Which statement can be used to specify the sql_mode system variable at runtime?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SPECIFY",
            "b) SET",
            "c) ASSIGN",
            "d) CHANGE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL server mode values stored in the system variable are not case sensitive. So it does not make a difference if you accidentally store the mode values in lowercase or uppercase."
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "10. When no modes are enabled, what does this SQL statement return?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> @@<span class=\"kw1\">SESSION</span><span class=\"sy0\">.</span>sql_mode;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) empty value",
            "b) zero",
            "c) a negative value",
            "d) a garbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When the server starts, the command –sql-mode=’TRADITIONAL’ can be used to set the SQL mode as ‘TRADITIONAL’. This can be stored in an option file or can be directly executed on the command line."
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "Which of the following characters is illegal in naming an unquoted identifier in SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) _",
            "b) $",
            "c) 2",
            "d) ."
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An identifier is used to refer to a database or its elements. These elements can be entire tables or attributes. The names of these identifiers follow some set of rules, so they have a set of legal characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "How are identifiers quoted in MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) single quotes",
            "b) double quotes",
            "c) backticks",
            "d) can’t be quoted"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Identifiers are allowed to start with any legal character. So it may begin with a digit. The special characters in the identifier characters consist of the ‘_’ and ‘$’. The other characters are the alphanumeric characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an illegal unquoted identifier name?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 123_id",
            "b) 123id",
            "c) id1",
            "d) 123"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: An identifier is quoted within the backtick characters ‘`’. This allows use of any character except a byte with value 0 or 255. Single quotes and double quotes are not allowed when quoting identifier names."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "Which server mode value enables use of double quotes to wrap identifier names?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANSI",
            "b) ANSI_QUOTES",
            "c) TRADITIONAL",
            "d) PIPES_AS_CONCAT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the quoted and unquoted identifier names have differences in the level of restrictions imposed on them. An unquoted identifier name can’t have all digits since it would be impossible to distinguish it from an integer constant."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "Which server mode value disables use of built in function names as identifiers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANSI",
            "b) IGNORE_FUNC",
            "c) TRADITIONAL",
            "d) IGNORE_SPACE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, use of double quotes is enabled when the server SQL mode ‘ANSI_QUOTES’ is set. The use of backticks is still allowed. For example, SELECT TABLE “my table” is a statement that is allowed."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "What is the maximum length for alias names in terms of characters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 64",
            "b) 128",
            "c) 256",
            "d) 32"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Server SQL mode value ‘IGNORE_FUNC’ is used to restrict the identifier naming conventions. When this is enabled, the names of built in functions can no longer be used as identifiers."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "What does a fully qualified table name consist of?",
        "Options": [
            "a) only the table name",
            "b) only the database name",
            "c) table name followed by database name",
            "d) database name followed by table name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The identifiers in MySQL have a maximum length of 64 characters. However, the alias names for identifiers can have the number of characters up to 256. Aliases can also be quoted or unquoted."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "Which of the following MySQL statements is valid if ‘`sampledb`’ is a database and ‘`tbl`’ is a table in it?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM `sampledb.member`",
            "b) SELECT * FROM `sampledb`.`member`",
            "c) SELECT * FROM `member`.`sampledb`",
            "d) SELECT * FROM `member.sampledb`"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MySQL identifiers use qualifiers. An element of a database has a fully qualified name. A database table in MySQL has the fully qualified name as the database name followed by the table name."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "2. What is true about the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> table_1;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) invalid",
            "b) display contents of table_1",
            "c) improper case being used",
            "d) display only column names in table_1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The case sensitivity rules in SQL statements are different for different statement elements, depend on what is being referred to and also on the machine’s operating system on which the server is running."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "The default case sensitivity of database and table names depends on ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL server",
            "b) Server SQL mode",
            "c) Operating system of machine",
            "d) Does not depend on anything"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The keywords and function names are not case sensitive in SQL. They can be named in any letter case. So, the above statement is correct and legal. It retrieves information from the table ‘table_1’."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "Which of the following is case sensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored function name",
            "b) Stored procedure name",
            "c) Trigger name",
            "d) Event name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The default case sensitivity imposes a dependency on the operating system of the machine on which the MySQL server is running. Windows does not treat database and table names as case sensitive unlike Unix."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "Which variable is used to set table alias names as non-case sensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lower_case_table_names",
            "b) lower_case_all",
            "c) lower_case_alias",
            "d) lower_case_aliases"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The stored functions and stored procedure names in MySQL are not case sensitive. Event names are also not case sensitive. Unlike the standard SQL, the trigger names in MySQL is case sensitive."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "Which case does InnoDB store database names in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lower",
            "b) upper",
            "c) mixed",
            "d) random"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, by default the alias names are case sensitive. An alias can hence be specified in any letter case, upper, lower or mixed. If the variable ‘lower_case_table_names’ is non zero, the alias names of tables are not case sensitive. "
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "Which of the following is case sensitive in MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Event names",
            "b) Logfile group names",
            "c) Column names",
            "d) Indexes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In InnoDB, all the database names as well as all the table names are stored in lowercase internally. There is no random case assignment to the database elements when the engine is set as InnoDB."
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "Which property determines whether a database object is a case sensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COLLATION",
            "b) ATOMICITY",
            "c) COLLABORATION",
            "d) NORMALIZATION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A database or table name must be referred to using the same lettercase throughout a given query. This is regardless of the fact whether it is case sensitive on the system or not."
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "What is AI in terms of database collation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Accent Insensitive",
            "b) Augment Insensitive",
            "c) Articulate Insensitive",
            "d) Addition Insensitive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Column names and indexes are not case sensitive on any platform and neither are column aliases. Unlike the standard SQL, the names of the log file groups are always case sensitive."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "What is the maximum collations a character set can have?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) more than 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The MySQL server allows simultaneous use of multiple character sets. A given character set is allowed to have one or more collations. It can be chosen according to the need of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "Which clause can be used to sort string values according to a specific collation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SORT",
            "b) GROUP",
            "c) FILTER",
            "d) COLLATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, Unicode character set support is provided by the utf8 and ucs2 character sets. There are further additional character sets available as of MySQL version 6.0.4."
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "Which MySQL statement is used to find out which character sets are available?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW CHARACTER SET",
            "b) SHOW COLLATION",
            "c) SHOW CHARACTER SETS",
            "d) SHOW COLLATIONS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘COLLATE’ operator can be used to sort the string values according to a specific collation. For example, ‘SELECT col FROM tbl ORDER BY col COLLATE latin1_swedish_ci’ sorts by swedish collation. "
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "5. Which collations does this MySQL statement list?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">SHOW</span> COLLATION <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> <span class=\"st0\">'utf8%'</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) names beginning with utf8",
            "b) names ending with utf8",
            "c) names containing utf8% anywhere",
            "d) names ending in utf8%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is simple to determine the character sets and collations that are available in MySQL. ‘SHOW CHARACTER SET’ shows the character sets while ‘SHOW COLLATION’ shows the collations."
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to show the server’s current character set and collation settings?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW CONSTANTS",
            "b) SHOW CONSTRAINTS",
            "c) SHOW VARIABLES",
            "d) DISP VARIABLES"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The character set ‘utf8’ is used for the Unicode character set 8. The ‘LIKE’ keyword does the job of narrowing the search space to refer to only those names that begin with ‘utf8’."
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "What does UTF stand for int utf8?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Universal Transformation Format",
            "b) Unicode Transformation Format",
            "c) Universal Transformation Formula",
            "d) Unicode Transformation Formula"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The statement ‘SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘character\\_set\\_%” displays a table consisting of two columns, ‘Variable_name’ and ‘Value’. Replacing characer\\_set\\_% with collation\\_% shows the collation variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "Prior to MySQL 6.0, utf8 was ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 bytes",
            "b) 4 bytes",
            "c) 8 bytes",
            "d) 9 bytes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the utf8 character set in MySQL, the characters are represented in one, two or three bytes. ‘UTF’ stands for ‘Unicode Transformation Format’. Unicode support prior to MySQL 6.0 was different."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "Post MySQL 6.0, utf8 was ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 bytes",
            "b) 4 bytes",
            "c) 5 bytes",
            "d) 6 bytes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘UTF’ stands for ‘Unicode Transformation Format’. Unicode support prior to MySQL 6.0 was different from that post MySQL 6.0. The older utf8 was of three bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "What is generally used as a synonym for CHARACTER SET?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CSET",
            "b) CHSET",
            "c) CHARSET",
            "d) CHCSET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Unicode support prior to MySQL 6.0 was different from that post MySQL 6.0. The older utf8 was of three bytes. The newer utf8 is now of four bytes. This is applicable to MySQL 6.0 and above."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to select a default database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) USE",
            "b) CREATE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) SCHEMA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL has the facility to use various statements specifically at the database level. For selecting a default database, the keyword or clause used is the ‘USE’ statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "Which keyword is the synonym for DATABASE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TABLE",
            "b) OBJECT",
            "c) DB",
            "d) SCHEMA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In any statement where the word ‘DATABASE’ occurs, the keyword ‘SCHEMA’ can be used as a synonym in place of it. In the literal sense, SCHEMA refers to the structure of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to create a database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) SET",
            "c) SETUP",
            "d) LINK"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In order to select a database as the default database for the MySQL server using the ‘USE’ statement, some access privilege for the database needs to be granted or attained."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "The file created by the server to store the database attributes is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.otp",
            "b) dp.zip",
            "c) db.opt",
            "d) db.cls"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement ‘CREATE DATABASE database_name;’ is used to create a database with the name ‘database_name’. A database qualifier should be used to specify the full name of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "To create a database only if it doesn’t already exist, which clause is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IF EXISTS",
            "b) IF NOT EXISTS",
            "c) CREATE EXISTS",
            "d) EXISTS IF"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Whenever a database is created in MySQL, the MySQL server creates a directory with the same name as the database. It creates the file db.opt to store the attributes."
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "MySQL stores the database character set and collation attributes in the file _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) dp.opt",
            "b) db.opt",
            "c) db.sv",
            "d) db.zip"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘CREATE DATABASE’ statement supports many optional values. To create a database named ‘my_db’ only if it doesn’t already exist, we write ‘CREATE DATABASE IF NOT EXISTS my_db’."
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to see the definition for an existing database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW CREATE DATABASE",
            "b) SHOW DATABASE",
            "c) SHOW CREATE",
            "d) SHOW CREATE DATABASE TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When a database is created, the ‘CHARACTER SET’ and ‘COLLATE’ values are specified. When ‘CHARACTER SET’ is given without ‘COLLATE’, the default collation is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "Which statement makes changes to the database’s global attributes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHANGE",
            "b) ALTER",
            "c) ALTERNATE",
            "d) UPDATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The file named ‘db.opt’ is of a great significance to MySQL, espectially the MySQL server. It stores the database attributes along with the db charset and collation attributes."
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to remove indexes on tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP INDEX",
            "b) DELETE INDEX",
            "c) REMOVE INDEX",
            "d) FLUSH INDEX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL provides statements to change the structure of tables. To add or remove the indexes on the existing database tables, the ‘CREATE INDEX’ and ‘DROP INDEX’ tables are used."
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "Which storage engine is not available in MySQL 5.0?",
        "Options": [
            "a) InnoDB",
            "b) ARCHIVE",
            "c) Falcon",
            "d) NDB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: All of the storage engines given are available in MySQL versions 5.0 and above, except ‘Falcon’. MySQL supports many storage engines or table handlers that have a specific set of properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "The default storage engine used is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) EXAMPLE",
            "b) ARCHIVE",
            "c) MyISAM",
            "d) NDB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MySQL comes with multiple storage engines. The default storage engine used is ‘MyISAM’. ‘EXAMPLE’ is the stub storage engine, NDB is the storage engine for MySQL Cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "What is the name of the format file for a table named my_tbl?",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_tbl.fmt",
            "b) my_tbl.frm",
            "c) my_tbl.fmr",
            "d) my_tbl.ftm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Every time a table is created in MySQL, it creates a disk file containing the format of the table. It has two components, namely, base name (here, ‘my_tbl’) and an extension (here, ‘frm’)."
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to create a table as a temporary copy of itself?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TEMP",
            "b) TEMPO",
            "c) TEMPR",
            "d) TEMPORARY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Suppose a table is created using the following statement: ‘CREATE TABLE my_tbl (…..) ENGINE = InnoDB;’. The engine name ‘InnoDB’ used is always case insensitive."
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "Which storage engine enables to access tables from a MySQL server managed by another server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) InnoDB",
            "b) EXAMPLE",
            "c) MyISAM",
            "d) FEDERATED"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘CREATE TABLE’ clause has a very vast formal format, although its usage is extremely simple and intuitive. One of the many ways is to create a table as a temporary copy of itself."
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "The default index type for MEMORY tables is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) HASH",
            "b) SPATIAL",
            "c) FULLTEXT",
            "d) UNIQUE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are many storage engines that are used in MySQL. By default, MyISAM is used as the storage engine unless specified otherwise. FEDERATED enables access to a foreign MySQL server."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "The statement to change the table name is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHANGE",
            "b) CHANGENAME",
            "c) CHANGENM",
            "d) RENAME"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To drop a table, all that is required is the table name. No additional information like table format or type is necessary. Multiple tables are dropped in the same DROP TABLE statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "The general term for information about databases and the objects in MySQL is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) datum",
            "b) info",
            "c) record",
            "d) metadata"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are various ways in which MySQL facilitates the methods to obtain information about databases and the objects in them. For example, ‘SHOW’ statements and ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to determine the storage engine for individual tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW STATUS OF TABLE",
            "b) SHOW STATUS TABLE",
            "c) SHOW TABLE STATUS",
            "d) SHOW DEFAULT STATUS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MySQL provides a method to determine the storage engine for each table with the ‘SHOW TABLE STATUS’ statement. The output of this statement is the name of the storage engine indicator."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "Which disk data does FILES table in INFORMATION_SCHEMA store?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NDB",
            "b) NBD",
            "c) NBK",
            "d) NCD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is another way to access information about the databases and its objects (metadata). It is based on the ‘SQL standard’, although some content is MySQL-specific."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "The information about table index characteristics is stored in which table of INFORMATION_SCHEMA?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FILES",
            "b) STATISTICS",
            "c) SCHEMATA",
            "d) VIEWS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is a method to access information about the databases and its objects known as metadata. It has various tables that can be viewed with ‘SHOW’ statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "Which table in INFORMATION_SCHEMA stores information about storage engines and server plugins?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ENGINES, PLUGINS",
            "b) FILES, PLUGINS",
            "c) ENGINES, FILES",
            "d) PLUGINS, STATISTICS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘STATISTICS’ table in the ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ stores information about the table index characteristics. ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is responsible for storing database metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "Which table stores information about the threads executing within the server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PROCESS",
            "b) PROCESSLIST",
            "c) LIST",
            "d) THREADSLIST"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is a very useful in MySQL. It has many tables each serving its individual purpose. The storage engine information is stored in ENGINES and plugin information in PLUGINS."
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "The command which lists databases managed by the server is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqld",
            "b) mysqlshow",
            "c) mysqllist",
            "d) mysqldb"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is a method to access information about the databases and its objects known as metadata. Its content is MySQL-specific which makes it more portable."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "The option in mysqlshow to show information about indexes in a table is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –no-data",
            "b) –indexes",
            "c) –keys",
            "d) –flag"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The table ‘PROCESSLIST’ is responsible for storing all the information about the threads executing within the server. The other tables are not valid tables in the INFORMATION_SCHEMA."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "SELECT select_list FROM table_list WHERE row_constraint GROUP BY grouping_columns; Which of these is not optional?",
        "Options": [
            "a) select_list",
            "b) table_list",
            "c) row_constraint",
            "d) grouping_columns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Given above was a basic syntax of the SELECT statement. Everything in the syntax is optional except the ‘select_list’ option. All the others are free to be omitted, and will work fine."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "The join where all possible row combinations are produced is called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INNER JOIN",
            "b) OUTER",
            "c) NATURAL",
            "d) CARTESIAN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The inner join is a form of join in MySQL that is used to combine the result of concatenating the contents of two tables into a new table. In inner join, result is produced by matching rows in one table with rows in another table."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "The clause that filters JOIN results is called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) SORT",
            "c) GROUP",
            "d) GROUP BY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In ‘cartesian product’, each row of each table is combined with each row in every other table to produce all possible combination. This produces a very large number of rows since the number is the product of rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "CROSS JOIN and JOIN are similar to __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INNER JOIN",
            "b) NATURAL JOIN",
            "c) OUTER JOIN",
            "d) CARTESIAN JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sometimes the result of a join is very large and is not desirable. In these cases, the results can be filtered with the help of the ‘WHERE’ clause which is followed by a set of condition(s)."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "The left and right joins are also known as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INNER JOIN",
            "b) NATURAL JOIN",
            "c) OUTER JOIN",
            "d) CARTESIAN JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The joins ‘CROSS JOIN’ and ‘JOIN’ types are exactly similar to the ‘INNER JOIN’. The statements containing ‘INNER JOIN’ can replace it with ‘CROSS JOIN’ or ‘JOIN’ to get exactly the same result."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "What is joining a table to itself called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMPLETE",
            "b) SELF",
            "c) OBSOLETE",
            "d) CROSS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The comma (,) operator can be used to join the tables as well. It joins them in the ‘INNER JOIN’ type. It is not desirable to use the comma operator since it has different precedence rules."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "In which join all the rows from the left table appear in the output irrespective of the content of the other table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RIGHT JOIN",
            "b) LEFT JOIN",
            "c) INNER JOIN",
            "d) OUTER JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘inner join’ only deals with rows where a match can be found in both tables. The ‘LEFT JOIN’ and ‘RIGHT JOIN’ types are ‘OUTER JOIN’ types which differ from inner joins in this sense."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "The join in which all the rows from the right table appear in the output irrespective of the content of the other table is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CARTESIAN JOIN",
            "b) CROSS JOIN",
            "c) INNER JOIN",
            "d) RIGHT JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Joining a table to itself in a database is called ‘self-join’. When a self-join is being performed, the table is being used multiple times within the query and a table name qualifier is unnecessary."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "The facility that allows nesting one select statement into another is called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) nesting",
            "b) binding",
            "c) subquerying",
            "d) encapsulating"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘subquerying’ support provided by MySQL is a capability that allows writing one ‘SELECT’ statement within parentheses and nesting within another. This allows logically selecting content from tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "Which subquery returns a single value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) scalar",
            "b) column",
            "c) row",
            "d) table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The subqueries in MySQL can return different types of information. A scalar query returns a single value. Column subquery return a single column and row subquery returns a single row."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "Which operators are used when a subquery returns multiple rows to be evaluated in comparison to the outer query?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IN and NOT IN",
            "b) EXISTS and NOT EXISTS",
            "c) OUTER JOIN and INNER JOIN",
            "d) LEFT JOIN and RIGHT JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The usage of aggregates inside ‘WHERE’ clauses is not allowed. For example, the following statement will not work : ‘SELECT * FROM my_table WHERE attribute_name = MAX(attribute_name)’, because the MAX value is not known yet. "
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "The ALL subquery performs which operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) row",
            "b) column",
            "c) table",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When there is a need to evaluate multiple rows in comparison to the outer query, the ‘IN’ and ‘NOT IN’ operators are used. They are used for testing whether a comparison value is present in a set of values."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "Which of these operators perform similar operations like ALL and ANY?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SOME",
            "b) MANY",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) GROUP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operators ‘ALL’ and ‘ANY’ are used to perform operations on columns. They are used in conjunction with a comparison operator in order to test the result of a column subquery."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "Which operators test whether a subquery returns any rows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IN and NOT IN",
            "b) EXISTS and NOT EXISTS",
            "c) PRESENT",
            "d) ABSENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The operators ‘SOME’, ‘ALL’ and ‘ANY’ perform operations on columns. They can filter column results. They are used in conjunction with a comparison operator in order to test the result of a column subquery."
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "Which subquery cannot be executed by itself as a separate statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Correlated",
            "b) Uncorrelated",
            "c) EXISTS",
            "d) NOT EXISTS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operators ‘EXISTS’ and ‘NOT EXISTS’ operators only test whether a subquery returns any rows. If it returns a row, ‘EXISTS’ results into true and ‘NOT EXISTS’ results into false."
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "Which of these operators does not perform relative-value comparisons?",
        "Options": [
            "a) =",
            "b) ==",
            "c) <=",
            "d) >="
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL has two kinds of subqueries, namely, uncorrelated subquery and correlated subquery. An uncorrelated subquery does not contain any reference to the values from the outer query."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "To combine multiple retrievals, we write several SELECT statements and put the keyword between them. What is the keyword?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMBINE",
            "b) CONCAT",
            "c) JOIN",
            "d) UNION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘UNION’ operator is used for combining the results of various ‘SELECT’ queries into one. For example, ‘SELECT a FROM table1 UNION SELECT a FROM table2;’ produces the results from tables table1 concatenated with that of table2."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "2. What is ‘xyz’ in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> table1 <span class=\"kw1\">UNION</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> table2;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) table name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘SELECT’ queries can be combined together using the ‘UNION’ operator to produce the concatenated results from two or more tables. The data type of the columns is not taken into account."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "Which keyword used with UNION does not retain duplicate rows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALL",
            "b) NARROW",
            "c) STRICT",
            "d) DISTINCT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Even if the columns ‘xyz’ and ‘def’ have different data types, the results from these columns are placed into the column ‘xyz’. The data types can be determined from the values in the columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "Which keyword used with UNION retains duplicate rows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALL",
            "b) NARROW",
            "c) STRICT",
            "d) DISTINCT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The keyword ‘DISTINCT’ used along with ‘UNION’ is synonymous with just the ‘UNION’ statement. It produces only the distinct rows from the combination of the two tables in the SELECT query."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to sort a UNION result as a whole?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIMIT",
            "b) ORDER BY",
            "c) GROUP BY",
            "d) SORT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The keyword ‘ALL’ used along with ‘UNION’ is not synonymous with just the ‘UNION’ statement. It produces the duplicate rows, if they exist, from the combination of the two tables in the SELECT query."
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "Suppose it is desired that UNION operation should return not more than 3 rows. Which keyword is used for this?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIMIT",
            "b) RESTRICT",
            "c) COUNT",
            "d) SORT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When there is a mixture of ‘UNION’ or ‘UNION DISTINCT’ statements with the ‘UNION ALL’ statements, any distinct union operation takes precedence over any ‘UNION ALL’ operations to its left."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "Which table is used to run a UNION-type query on MyISAM tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRADITIONAL",
            "b) MERGE",
            "c) SERVELET",
            "d) UNITE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘ORDER BY’ clause is used along with the ‘UNION’ statement to sort a ‘UNION’ result as a whole. It is placed after the last ‘SELECT’ statement which is kept in parentheses. "
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "SELECT on a MERGE table is like _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) UNION ALL",
            "b) UNION",
            "c) UNION DISTINCT",
            "d) JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When there is a need to put a limit to the number of rows returned by the ‘UNION’ operation, the statement ‘LIMIT’ is appended to the ‘SELECT’ queries which are joined by the ‘UNION’ operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "Which of these is also known as a virtual table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SCHEMA",
            "b) DATABASE",
            "c) JOIN",
            "d) VIEW"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, a ‘View’ is also called a virtual table. It does not contain any data but only appears as a table. It is an alternative way to show or describe a table similar to the original table."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "3. What is xyz in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VIEW</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> t;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) table",
            "b) column",
            "c) view",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, a ‘View’ is used to present a table in the database. It is a virtual table. It is also used to present a subset of the columns that are present in the original table of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "4. What is abc in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VIEW</span> xyz <span class=\"br0\">(</span>abc<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> a <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> t;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) view",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A ‘View’ is created in MySQL by writing the clause ‘CREATE VIEW’ followed by the view name. Then follows the list of column names of the table that are to be presented as the view."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "A view can refer to multiple tables via __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) UNION",
            "b) JOIN",
            "c) GROUP",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Column names for a view can be explicitly provided in the ‘CREATE VIEW’ clause itself. It presents the table view with the aliased column names instead of the original column names."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "A view can be deleted using the command __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) REMOVE",
            "b) DELETE",
            "c) CLEAR",
            "d) DROP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a ‘View’ can refer to multiple tables. This makes it a lot simpler to execute the queries involving joins. When a selection is made from the view, the join is executed producing the results."
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "What cannot be done on a view?",
        "Options": [
            "a) display",
            "b) filter",
            "c) index",
            "d) drop"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, some ‘Views’ are updatable. The operators ‘INSERT’, ‘DELETE’ and ‘UPDATE’ can be used. They can be operated on the ‘Views’ to make changes to it. A table can be created and set as a view."
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "What can be used to check for views that have been invalidated by DROP or ALTER operations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE TABLE",
            "b) VERIFY TABLE",
            "c) DETAILS TABLE",
            "d) CHECK TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, ‘Views’ act as virtual tables. Many operations can be performed on views like the operations on tables. A view can be created, displayed and dropped. They can also be used to perform calculations."
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not support a materialized view?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MySQL",
            "b) Oracle",
            "c) PostgreSQL",
            "d) SybaseSQL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, ‘Views’ act as virtual tables. It is not possible to create indexes on a view. However, they can be used for the views that are processed using the merge algorithm."
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "To perform a delete on a single-table, how is the name of a column qualified?",
        "Options": [
            "a) qualification not necessary",
            "b) column name",
            "c) table name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, performing the operations ‘UPDATE’ and ‘DELETE’ on a single-table does not require qualifying the column name of the table in the database with the table name of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "2. What is xyz in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> abc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) row name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operation being performed in the statement is the ‘DELETE’. The table name is ‘xyz’ and column name is ‘abc’. When this statement is executed, rows having abc value equal to 5 get deleted."
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "4. What is abc in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> abc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) row name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, a multiple table ‘DELETE’ operation can be performed on the tables combined using any kind of ‘JOIN’ operation. The syntax also allows for deleting rows from multiple tables at once."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "5. What is x in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> x <span class=\"kw1\">USING</span> x <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> y <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>col <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>col;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) server name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Here, the operation that is being performed in the statement is the ‘DELETE’ operation. The table name is ‘xyz’ and column name is ‘abc’. The rows having abc value equal to 5 get deleted."
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "7. What is the value of val2 in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">UPDATE</span> t <span class=\"kw1\">SET</span> val1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> val1 <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> val2 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> val1;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) previous val1",
            "b) updated val1",
            "c) unchanged",
            "d) val1 + 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘DELETE’ operation is being performed in the statement. The table names are ‘x’ and ‘y’. The column name is ‘col’. The rows from left join of x and y get deleted according to the condition given."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "UPDATE statement is a DML statement. What does DML stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data Manipulation Language",
            "b) Data Manipulation Level",
            "c) Data Markup Language",
            "d) Data Markup Level"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When it comes to single table ‘UPDATE’ and ‘DELETE’ operations, the qualification of a column name with the table name is not necessary. So the table name qualifier can be omitted."
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "Which keyword in the UPDATE statement is used to assign values to columns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ASSIGN",
            "b) SET",
            "c) MARK",
            "d) GET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The second assignment here (val2 = val1) sets the value of val2 to the updated val1, that is, previous val1 incremented by two. ‘t’ is the name of the table here. ‘val1’ and ‘val2’ are columns. "
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to delete all the rows from the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRUNCATE",
            "b) REMOVE",
            "c) DELETE ALL",
            "d) CLEAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘UPDATE’ statement in MySQL is a ‘Data Manipulation Language’ statement. It performs edits on real tables present or loaded directly from the stored database. It is used in similar lines with ‘DELETE’."
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "What is known as the set of SQL statements that either executes successfully or none of them have an effect?",
        "Options": [
            "a) joins",
            "b) transactions",
            "c) filters",
            "d) deletions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a transaction is a set of SQL statements that are run as a single unit. They can be canceled when required, but they can either execute successfully or neither of them executes."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "What is generally done after the transactions are executed successfully?",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) rollback",
            "c) commit",
            "d) update"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In a transaction, either all the statements are executed successfully or neither of them are successful. This is facilitated by the commit and rollback capabilities. Commit is made after a transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "What is generally done if an error occurs during the transaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) rollback",
            "c) commit",
            "d) update"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Whenever an error occurs during a transaction, it is generally taken to the state prior to the beginning of transaction execution. This is known as rollback. It is a set of undo operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "What does ‘A’ stand for in the ACID property of transactions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Availability",
            "b) Accuracy",
            "c) Adjustability",
            "d) Atomicity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the transaction systems have an important set of characteristics in common. This is known as the ‘ACID’ property of the transaction. It refers to the four elementary characteristics of a transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "What does ‘C’ stand for in the ACID property of transactions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compound",
            "b) Concrete",
            "c) Collision",
            "d) Consistency"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The elementary characteristics of a transaction are known as the ‘ACID’ properties. ‘ACID’ is the acronym for the four basic characteristics that a transaction must have for smooth processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "What is the isolation property of transactions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) statements form a logic unit",
            "b) database remains consistent",
            "c) one transaction does not affect the other",
            "d) transaction effects are recorded permanently"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘isolation’ property of a transaction is one of the four elementary characteristics that are expected for a database transaction to maintain throughout. The others are Atomicity, Consistency and Durability."
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "What is the command to disable autocommit and launch a transaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INITIATE TRANSACTION",
            "b) START TRANSACTION",
            "c) DISABLE AUTOCOMMIT",
            "d) TRANSACTION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By default, MySQL runs in the autocommit mode. This means that the changes performed by individual statements or operations on tables are automatically committed to the database immediately."
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "What is the durability property of transactions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) statements form a logic unit",
            "b) database remains consistent",
            "c) one transaction does not affect the other",
            "d) transaction effects are recorded permanently"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A transaction can either execute successfully or it can be rolled back to the point of initiation. Once a transaction completes, changes are recorded with commit. If it fails, changes are rolled back."
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Transactional processing is a Compound process. The statements and the state of the database need to be kept track of during the execution of the transaction. This means CPU cycles need to be reserved."
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "Which key declares that an index in one table is related to that in another?",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) foreign",
            "d) cross"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, a foreign key is the one which facilitates index relations across tables. It declares that an index in one table is related to that in another and place constraints."
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "Deletion of an employee from table also deletes that employee from another table. This kind of delete is called ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) transparent",
            "b) concrete",
            "c) elaborate",
            "d) cascaded"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A foreign key is the one which declares that an index in one table is related to that in another and place constraints. It is useful for handling deletes and updates along with row entries."
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "Which storage engine in MySQL provides foreign key support?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRANSACTION",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) MyISAM",
            "d) MEMORY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, a cascaded delete and update is possible where records can be deleted from multiple tables. These tables are related with the help of foreign keys. Foreign keys make table updates flexible."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "The property of InnoDB that enforces foreign key relationships stay intact is called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) atomicity",
            "b) durability",
            "c) consistency",
            "d) referential integrity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are a list of storage engines to choose from. Each storage engine provides its own set of facilities. The foreign key facilities are provided by the InnoDB storage engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "Which clause names the parent table and the index columns in the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) REFERENCES",
            "b) ON DELETE",
            "c) CONSTRAINT",
            "d) FOREIGN KEY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The storage engine responsible for providing foreign key support is InnoDB. It enforces that the rules guarantee the foreign key relationship stays intact with no mismatching of data."
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to remove a foreign key constraint?",
        "Options": [
            "a) REMOVE",
            "b) DELETE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) EXCLUDE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL foreign key definition syntax, there are various components, namely, FOREIGN KEY, CONSTRAINT, REFERENCES and ON DELETE. The REFERENCES clause names the parent table and the index columns in the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to specify the foreign key after the table is created?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SETUP",
            "b) SET",
            "c) ALTER TABLE",
            "d) SPECIFY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The foreign key support is exclusively provided by the storage engine named InnoDB. Without its inclusion, foreign keys cannot be used. However it is possible to implement with application logic."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "Which clause in the SQL standard controls how NULL values in a composite foreign key are handled when comparing to a primary key.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SET",
            "b) MATCH",
            "c) ON DELETE",
            "d) ON CASCADE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL foreign key definition syntax, there are various components. A foreign key links one table to another table in the table. To remove a foreign key constraint, the ‘DROP’ clause is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "In which mode of search is the search string parsed into words and the search looks for rows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural language",
            "b) Boolean mode",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, a full text search capability is provided, which enables to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations. There are three kinds of full text searches."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "The indicator of presence or absence of a word in search is used in which mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural language",
            "b) Boolean mode",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A full text search capability is provided in MySQL. It facilitates to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations. Boolean search is one of the three modes."
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "Which search mode uses natural language search as a subroutine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural language",
            "b) Boolean mode",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The query expansion search occurs in two phases. The natural language search is applied in the first phase. Query expansion search is one of the three modes of fulltext searching."
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "FULLTEXT indexes can be created only for ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) MEMORY",
            "d) TRANSITION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Full-text searches are based on the FULLTEXT indexes. They can be created for MyISAM tables only. In MySQL, a full text search enables to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to search through natural language fulltext?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MATCH",
            "b) AGAINST",
            "c) SEARCH",
            "d) FIND"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a full-text search is based on the FULLTEXT indexes. A FULLTEXT index can be created both for a single column and for multiple columns. Searching is possible across columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "7. What is xyz in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> my_table <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">MATCH</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>abc<span class=\"br0\">)</span> AGAINST<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'xyz'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) search string",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, fulltext searches are carried in three modes. Natural language fulltext search is carried out using the MATCH and AGAINST clause. MATCH keyword specifies the column to be searched."
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "8. What is abc in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> my_table <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">MATCH</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>abc<span class=\"br0\">)</span> AGAINST<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'xyz'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) search string",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The natural language fulltext search in MySQL tables is carried out using the MATCH and AGAINST clause. The MATCH clause is used to specify the column and AGAINST specifies the search string."
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "Which parameter determines the shortest words to index in FULLTEXT indexes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ft_min_word_len",
            "b) ft_min_len_word",
            "c) ft_word_min_len",
            "d) ft_word_len_word"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The MATCH clause is used to specify the column and AGAINST specifies the search string in the natural language full text search syntax. It is one of the three modes of full-text search."
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to access an existing Database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use",
            "b) use database.name",
            "c) USE databasename;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "The “Mysql command line tool” format  the results in which of the following format?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rectangle",
            "b) Square",
            "c) Sphere",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "The “Mysql command line tool” formats are bounded by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) +-|",
            "b) +-*",
            "c) +-/",
            "d) +-}"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "Which command is used on Mysql command line tool to return to window command shell?",
        "Options": [
            "a) exit",
            "b) exit;",
            "c) exit()",
            "d) exit();"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "Which command is used in Mysql command line tool to return to window command shell?",
        "Options": [
            "a) exit;",
            "b) quit;",
            "c) both exit; and quit;",
            "d) only exit;"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "Which command is used for taking “server side help” in Mysql command line tool?",
        "Options": [
            "a) /h",
            "b) /c",
            "c) /e",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: /h represents help contents for Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "Which authentications are required for login into Mysql command line tool?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Username",
            "b) Password",
            "c) Only Username",
            "d) Both Username and Password"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "Mysql command line tool is used to show “how many rows are returned and how long SQL command took to execute”.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Undetermined",
            "d) Depend"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "Which command is used for showing current date and time in Mysql command line tool?",
        "Options": [
            "a) select now()",
            "b) SELECT now();",
            "c) SELECT now()",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct syntax for creating table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE TABLE name;",
            "b) CREATE name;",
            "c) CREATE TABLE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "What is the role of “CONSTRAINS” in defining a table in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Declaring primary key",
            "b) Declaring Foreign Key",
            "c) Restrictions on columns",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "Which command is used for the table definition in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESC  table_name;",
            "b) DESC table_name",
            "c) DESC",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct syntax for defining “Constraint Check” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) gender  char(1)  check( gender IN (‘M’, ‘F’)),",
            "b) gender char (1) check,",
            "c) gender char (1) check ( gender ),",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Check constraint constrains the allowable values for a particular column.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "Which data type character merges the “Check Constraint” into a data type definition?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ENUM",
            "b) ENUM1",
            "c) ENUM2",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct syntax for defining “ENUM” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) gender ENUM (‘M’, ‘F’),",
            "b) gender ENUM,",
            "c) gender ENUM ( ),",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "Which among the following are the correct definitions for “NULL” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Absence of value",
            "b) Unknown",
            "c) Empty set",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "8. Find out the logical error in the following MySQL code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> person\n   <span class=\"br0\">(</span> person_id <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n    Name <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n    Address <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n    Mobile_no  <span class=\"kw1\">SMALLINT</span> \n    <span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lesser number of columns",
            "b) Incorrect definition",
            "c) Primary key is missing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: Primary key is an essential attribute for each table declared in Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “REFERENCES” in table definition?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Primary key",
            "b) NULL",
            "c) Foreign Key",
            "d) A ”foreign Key” belong to this particular table"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: When “Foreign Key” declared in a table then it necessary to define the name of the table to which it belong with help of constraint “REFERENCES”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "What default value gets stored in columns of the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NULL",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) -1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: NULL is the default value as it stands for “Absence of value”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "Which Statement is used to insert the values in the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INSERT INTO",
            "b) Insert",
            "c) INSERT",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "Is it necessary to insert the value in each column of the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the server",
            "d) Depends on the usage of the table"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: It is not necessary to insert the value in each column because there always a default value is inserted by the server “NULL”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "3. In the following SQL query, what does “person” stands for?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> person\n    <span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n    <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’S’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’P’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Composite attributes",
            "b) Multivalued attributes",
            "c) Table name",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "4. In the following SQL query, what  does “person_id” stands for?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> person\n   <span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_ id <span class=\"kw1\">SMALLINT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">UNSIGNED</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   fname <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   lname <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">CONSTRAINT</span> pk_person <span class=\"kw1\">PRIMARY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">KEY</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Normal attribute of the table",
            "b) Super key",
            "c) Composite key",
            "d) Primary key"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Primary key is also termed as a super key.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "Which statement can be used for modifying the definition for an existing table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER",
            "b) Modified",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) FROM"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "Which feature is used for the automatic increment of the column?",
        "Options": [
            "a) AUTO_INCREMENT",
            "b) AUTO",
            "c) INCREMENT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct syntax for modifying the definition of an existing table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER TABLE person MODIFY person_id SMALLINT UNSIGNED AUTO_INCREMENT;",
            "b) ALTER TABLE person  person_id SMALLINT UNSIGNED AUTO_INCREMENT;",
            "c) ALTER TABLE person MODIFY person_id ;",
            "d) ALTER TABLE person"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "8. Will the following SQL command produce any error?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">  <span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> person\n  <span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>lname<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’S’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’U’<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’T’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’U’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n <span class=\"coMULTI\">/* where person_id is a primary key */</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) No Error",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Person_id declared as a primary key therefore it never contain same value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "9. Will the following SQL command produce any error?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> person\n<span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>lname<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’S’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’U’<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’T’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’U’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n<span class=\"coMULTI\">/* where person_id is a primary key */</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) No Error",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "What is the default value of column?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NULL",
            "b) 0",
            "c) -1",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: When table is defined in Mysql then each column related to table will contain NULL Value as default.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to select columns and rows from the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) ALTER",
            "c) MODIFY",
            "d) FROM"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "2. In the following SQL command “person” stands for?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> Birth_date\n   <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table name",
            "b) Attribute",
            "c) Multivalued attribute",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "3. In the following SQL command “*” stands for?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Retrieve all data from the table",
            "b) Retrieve data of primary key only",
            "c) Retrieve NULL data",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "Which Clause is used to select a particular row from the set of row in an existing table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) FROM",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "5. In the following SQL command “person_id” can be ____________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>l name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> Birth_data <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n   <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only Primary Key",
            "b) Primary Key or any other Attribute",
            "c) Only Attribute but not a primary Key",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "Which Clause is used to sort the stored data in alphabetical order?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ORDER by CLAUSE",
            "b) MODIFY",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) UPDATE"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "Which Clause is used to select a particular table in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) SELECT",
            "c) FROM",
            "d) ALTER"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "Which command is used to show all tables that are stored in a database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOWS",
            "b) SHOW",
            "c) SHOWES",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct syntax for showing all tables in the database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOWS TABLES",
            "b) SHOW TABLE",
            "c) SHOW",
            "d) SHOWS TABLES;"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "10. If attribute “fruit” stores data as “apple, mango, banana” in table person then what will be the output of the following SQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fruit <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n    <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> fruit;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) apple, mango, banana",
            "b) apple, banana, mango",
            "c) mango, apple, banana",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: ORDER BY Clause always sort in alphabetical order which also known as lexicographical order.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "Which statement is used for updating existing information in the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) MODIFY",
            "d) ALTER"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to delete an existing row from the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELETE",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) MODIFY",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "3. In the following MySQL command how many rows will be updated?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">UPDATE</span> person\n   <span class=\"kw1\">SET</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’s’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   Fname <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ’p’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span>;\n   <span class=\"coMULTI\">/* person_id is a primary key */</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Single row",
            "b) Double row",
            "c) No row",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "4. In the following MySQL command how many rows will be updated?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw1\">UPDATE</span> person\n   <span class=\"kw1\">SET</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’s’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   Fname<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’p’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id&amp;lt;<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>;\n   <span class=\"coMULTI\">/* person_id is a primary key */</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0-9",
            "b) 1-6",
            "c) No row",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "5. In the following MySQL command how many rows will be deleted?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>;\n<span class=\"coMULTI\">/*person_id is a primary key */</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) No row",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "6. In the following MySQL command how many rows will be deleted?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id&amp;lt;<span class=\"nu0\">10</span>;\n<span class=\"coMULTI\">/*person_id is a primary key */</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0-9",
            "b) 1-7",
            "c) No row",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "“INSERT” is same as “UPDATE”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO",
            "b) YES",
            "c) May be",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “INSERT “is used to entering the data in the newly created table while “UPDATE” is used to modify the data which is already inserted with help of statement “INSERT”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to rename the existing table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RENAME",
            "b) MODIFY",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions are not performed by “ALTER” clause?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Change the name of the table",
            "b) Change the name of the column",
            "c) Drop a column",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "Numbers prefixed with ‘0x’ are in base __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 32",
            "d) 64"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are many numeric datatypes. They include integers and floating points. For example, 34, 12.3, -1.3E11. The numbers that are prefixed with ‘0x’ are in hexadecimal."
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "The mantissa in -1.58E5 is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1.58",
            "b) 1.58",
            "c) E",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The scientific notation for real numbers is possible in MySQL. Approximate values are represented as floating point numbers in scientific notation. It consists of a mantissa and exponent."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "The BIGINT precision is of bit _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 64",
            "c) 128",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the scientific notation for real numbers is possible. Some values are represented as floating point numbers in scientific notation consisting of a mantissa and exponent."
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "The DECIMAL used for expressions containing only exact values with fractional part is of digit precision _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 64",
            "c) 65",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the expressions containing only exact values that are all integers, the evaluation uses BIGINT (64 – bit) precision. MySQL evaluates expressions using exact/approximate math."
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "If a string is to be converted to a number, it is converted into a _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) double precision floating point",
            "b) single precision floating point",
            "c) decimal integer",
            "d) hexadecimal integer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the expressions containing only exact values and where one or more values have a fractional part, the DECIMAL arithmetic is used with digits of precision equal to 65."
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "The bit-field values are prefixed with __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0b",
            "b) 0bit",
            "c) bit-",
            "d) ‘bit’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When there is a need to convert a string to a number to evaluate an expression, it is first converted to a double precision floating point value. Then, it can be used to do arithmetic."
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "‘2341’ is a ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) floating point",
            "c) hexadecimal",
            "d) string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the bit-field values can be either written as b’value’ or 0bvalue. Here, value is a sequence of digits zero or/and one. For example, b’1010′ and 0b1010 are decimal value 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "If ANSI_QUOTES is enabled, MySQL treats the double quotes as ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) identifier-quoting character",
            "b) string-quoting character",
            "c) hexadecimal",
            "d) string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the BIT values in the result set are displayed as binary strings. In order to convert them to integers, either a zero is added or the ‘CAST()’ operator is used to cast them."
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "The escape sequence for carriage return is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ‘\\c’",
            "b) ‘\\r’",
            "c) ‘\\b’",
            "d) ‘\\z’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL recognizes many escape sequences like other programming languages. An escape sequence begin with a backslash character. The ‘\\0’ is different from NULL. It is a zero valued byte."
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "Which mode is used to turn off the special meaning of backslash and treat it as an ordinary character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO_ESCAPES_SLASH",
            "b) NO_ESCAPES_BACKSLASH",
            "c) NO_BACKSLASH_ESCAPES",
            "d) NO_BACKSLASH_ESCAPE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL provides the facility to use a wide range of escape sequences. They are special characters. They begin with the backslash character. For example, ‘\\r’ specifies carriage return."
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "x’ffff’ in decimal is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 65534",
            "b) 66535",
            "c) 65536",
            "d) 65537"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To turn off the special meaning of backslash in MySQL, and treat it as an ordinary character, the SQL mode named NO_BACKSLASH_ESCAPES is enabled. The escape sequence is treated as characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "X’61626364′ and X’61626364′ are respectively __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) abcd and 1633837924",
            "b) abcd and 4297383361",
            "c) dcba and 1633837924",
            "d) dcba and 4297383361"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, string values are specified using the standard SQL notation x’val’. Here, val is pairs of hexadecimal digits (‘0’ through ‘ 9 ’ and ‘ a ’ through ‘ f ’). x’ffff’ is 65536 in decimal."
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "The number of legal hexadecimal values among 0x0a, 0x0A, 0X0a and 0X0A is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the numeric contexts, each hexadecimal number constant is treated as a number. Without adding a zero to it, a hexadecimal literal is treated as a string. Hence it is displayed as abcd."
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "What is used to produce a new string from an old string in the desired character set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Introducers",
            "b) CONVERT()",
            "c) CONVERTER()",
            "d) CONVERTS()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the hexadecimal values are case sensitive. The leading 0x is what makes it case sensitive. Not the lowercase ‘x’ notation is used here. Numbers prefixed with ‘0X’ are illegal."
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "To measure the length of a string in bytes, the operator used is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHAR_LENGTH()",
            "b) LENGTH()",
            "c) LEN()",
            "d) SIZE()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the string values are classified into two general categories. They are the binary strings and non binary strings. A binary string is only a sequence of bytes interpreted without a character set."
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "Which character set variable indicates the character set used for storing identifiers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) character_set_system",
            "b) character_set_server",
            "c) collation_server",
            "d) character_set_database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The introducers and CONVERT() clause are not the same in MySQL. An introducer modifies the way a string is interpreted and does not modify the string. CONVERT() produces a new string from the old one."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "Character data can be stored as ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fixed length string",
            "b) Variable length string",
            "c) Either Fixed or Variable length string",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: To store character data we can use two definitions\nChar(20)  /*fixed length */\nVarchar(20) /* variable length */\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "Which declaration represents that “character data will consume the same number of bytes as declared and is right padded”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Char",
            "b) Varchar",
            "c) Both Char and Varchar",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "Which declaration doesn’t use the same number of bytes and consumption of bytes depends on the input data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Varchar",
            "b) Char",
            "c) Both Varchar and Char",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "The maximum length of the char columns is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 255 bytes",
            "b) 65, 535 bytes",
            "c) 256 bytes",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "The maximum length of the varchar columns is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Upto 65, 535 bytes",
            "b) Upto 256 bytes",
            "c) Upto 65, 567 bytes",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "In oracle database variable length column is declared by ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Varchar",
            "b) Varchar 3",
            "c) Varchar2",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "Mysql support different character sets,  which command is used to display all character sets?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW CHARACTER SET;",
            "b) SHOW;",
            "c) CHARACTER SET;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "Which one is the correct declaration for choosing the character set other than default?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Varchar(20) character set utf8;",
            "b) Varchar(20);",
            "c) Varchar(20) character set;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "Which “text type” has the maximum number of bytes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tiny text",
            "b) Text",
            "c) Medium text",
            "d) Long text"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Long text store 4, 294, 967, 295.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "Which among the following have the maximum bytes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Varchar",
            "b) Char",
            "c) Text type",
            "d) Both Varchar and Char"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "What will happen if the data being loaded into a text column exceeds the maximum size of that type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Extra memory will be allocated",
            "b) Process terminate",
            "c) Data will be truncated",
            "d) Depend on the system"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: Mysql cannot allocate dynamic memory therefore if data exceeds the memory then extra data will be truncated.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "Which data type is more suitable for storing “small notes” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Char",
            "b) Varchar",
            "c) Mediumtext",
            "d) Longtext"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "Which data type is more suitable for storing “documents” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Varchar",
            "b) Longtext",
            "c) Mediumtext",
            "d) Either Varchar or Longtext"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Longtext has largest range.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "“Numeric Data” is used to store ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Whole numbers",
            "b) Natural numbers",
            "c) Rational numbers",
            "d) Both Whole and Natural numbers"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "Which Numeric Data type has the largest range?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mediumint",
            "b) Smallint",
            "c) Int",
            "d) Tinyint"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "What will be the storage pattern for “float(4,2)” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total of four digits, two to the left of decimal and two to the right of decimal",
            "b) Total of six digits",
            "c) Total of four digits, not distributed uniformly",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: As per standards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Which among the following are the correct representation of “float(4,2)”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 24.33",
            "b) 124.4",
            "c) 12.123",
            "d) Both 24.33 and 124.4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Float(4,2) allowed at most 2 digit at right of the decimal and left of the decimal.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct representation of “float(5,0)”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12345.123",
            "b) 12345.1",
            "c) 12345",
            "d) 123.123"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: “float(5,0) says there should be total of five digit, in which no digit should be at the right of the decimal.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct representation of “float(1,1)”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total of 1 digit",
            "b) Total of 2 digit",
            "c) Total of 2 digit, one digit at right of the decimal, one digit at left of the decimal",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "Which data type is used to store data and time in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric data type",
            "b) Text data type",
            "c) Temporal data type",
            "d) Char/Varchar"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: Temporal data are used for storing Date, Time, TimeStamp or Datetime.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "What is the default format for “Date” data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) YYYY-MM-DD",
            "b) MM-YYYY-DD",
            "c) DD-MM-YYYY",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Default means values that are assumed by the server.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "What is the default format for “Datetime” data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) YYYY-MM-DD   HH:MI:SS",
            "b) MM-YYYY-DD   HH:MI:SS",
            "c) DD-YYYY-MM    MI:HH:SS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Default means values that are assumed by the server.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "What is the default format for “Timestamp” data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) YYYY-MM-DD   HH:MI:SS",
            "b) MM-YYYY-DD   HH:MI:SS",
            "c) DD-YYYY-MM    MI:HH:SS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Default means values that are assumed by the server.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "What is the default format for “Year” data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) YYYY",
            "b) YYYY-DD-MM",
            "c) MM-YYYY-DD",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Default means values that are assumed by the server.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "What is the default format for “Time” data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) HHH:MI:SS",
            "b) SS:MI:HHH",
            "c) MI:SS:HHH",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Default means values that are assumed by the server.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "Is “Datetime” and “Timestamp” are same data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “Timestamp” column will automatically be populated with current Date/time by the Mysql server, when any row modified."
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "Which value will show an error when stored in float(4,2)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12.11",
            "b) 13.1",
            "c) 1.12",
            "d) 123.44"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: “Float(4,2)” cannot store more than 4 digits.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "The datatype for single precision floating point number is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLOAT",
            "b) DOUBLE",
            "c) INT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are various numeric datatypes in MySQL. Some of them are TINYINT, SMALLINT, BIGINT, FLOAT, DOUBLE and BIT. ‘FLOAT’ is for single precision floating point numbers unlike DOUBLE."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "Which datatype is used for a fixed length binary string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) VARCHAR",
            "b) BINARY",
            "c) VARBINARY",
            "d) BLOB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL has a variety of string datatypes for use. Strings can hold arbitrary binary data. All the four options are string type names. BINARY is used for a fixed length binary string."
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "Which datatype means a variable length non binary string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) VARCHAR",
            "b) BINARY",
            "c) VARBINARY",
            "d) BLOB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are a wide variety of string datatypes for use. Strings can even hold image and sound data. All the four options are string type names. VARCHAR represents a variable length non binary string."
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "Which data and time datatype stores time value in ‘hh:mm:ss’ format?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DATE",
            "b) TIME",
            "c) DATETIME",
            "d) TIMESTAMP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL has some variety of date and time datatypes. These datatypes are crucial for representing records in a table. The ‘TIME’ type represents a time value, stored in the ‘hh:mm:ss’ format."
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "Which spatial datatype is used to store a curve?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GEOMETRY",
            "b) POINT",
            "c) LINESTRING",
            "d) POLYGON"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are many spatial datatypes available for use. Some examples are GEOMETRY, POINT, LINESTRING and POLYGON. The LINESTRING type is used to represent a curve."
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: UNSIGNED and ZEROFILL are allowable only for numeric types, and CHARACTER SET and COLLATE are allowable only for non-binary string types. These are type specific attributes."
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "The datatype INT stores ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16 bit",
            "b) 32 bit",
            "c) 48 bit",
            "d) 64 bit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For every data type except the BLOB and TEXT types, spatial types, or columns with the AUTO_INCREMENT attribute, a DEFAULT def_value clause can be specified to keep a default value for a column."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "The datatype SMALLINT stores ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16 bit",
            "b) 32 bit",
            "c) 48 bit",
            "d) 8 bit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The DEFAULT def_value clause can be specified for every data type except the BLOB and TEXT types, spatial types, or columns with the AUTO_INCREMENT attribute. The def_value holds the default."
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "The maximum non zero value for FLOAT is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.402823466E+38",
            "b) 3.402823466E+37",
            "c) 3.402823466E+39",
            "d) 3.402823466E+35"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, each datatype has its own range. Data types give an idea of the kind of values and the ranges that a variable is allowed to store. The maximum non zero value for FLOAT is 3.402823466E+38."
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "The maximum non zero values for DOUBLE is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ±1.7976931348623157E+307",
            "b) ±1.7976931348623157E+308",
            "c) ±1.7976931348623157E+306",
            "d) ±1.7976931348623157E+305"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, all the datatypes have their own ranges. Data types give an idea of the kind of values and the ranges that a variable is allowed to store. The maximum non zero value for DOUBLE is ±1.7976931348623157E+308."
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "The storage size in bytes required for the MEDIUMINT datatype is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The numeric datatypes used in MySQL vary over ranges. There are a variety of INT types in the type specification. TINYINT requires 1, SMALLINT requires 2 bytes and MEDIUMINT requires 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "The size of the BIT type is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the numeric datatypes used in MySQL vary over the fields. However the maximum size is fixed. Unlike the other numeric types the size of the BIT datatype depends on the length of the field."
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "The REAL type is synonym for ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLOAT",
            "b) INT",
            "c) DOUBLE",
            "d) BIT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The REAL datatype, by default, is for the DOUBLE type. Floating point types can be defined as UNSIGNED. This eliminates the negative end of the type ranges. MySQL has a variety of default types."
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "The maximum number of elements allowed in SET() is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16",
            "b) 32",
            "c) 64",
            "d) 128"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The SET type specification is very useful for storing a collection a ordered and distinct elements. The storage size required for this datatype is variable and dependent on the cardinality."
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, the string datatypes are broadly categorised into two, namely, binary string types and non binary string types. BINARY, VARBINARY and BLOB are the binary string datatypes."
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "The maximum size in bytes of a row in MySQL is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 65534",
            "b) 65535",
            "c) 65536",
            "d) 65537"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The allowable range of M for VARCHAR(M) syntactically is 1 to 65535, but the effective number of the maximum characters is less than 65535 since MySQL has a maximum row size of 65,535 bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "For which type are illegal values converted to the appropriate ‘zero’ value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) String",
            "c) ENUM",
            "d) TIME"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the numeric or TIME columns, the values that are outside the legal range are clipped to the nearest endpoint of the range. The resulting value is stored. This is the method to handle defaults for numerics."
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "What is the command to see the warning messages?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DISPLAY WARNINGS",
            "b) DISP WARNINGS",
            "c) DISP WARNING",
            "d) SHOW WARNINGS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are different ways to handle the illegal values for different datatypes for default. For date or time columns, illegal values are converted to the appropriate “zero” value for the type."
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "The SQL mode to check for divide by zero error is ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) STRICT_ALL_TABLES",
            "b) ERROR_FOR_DIVISION_BY_ZERO",
            "c) ERROR_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO",
            "d) ERROR_WHEN_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the default value conversions are reported as warnings for INSERT, REPLACE and UPDATE statements. The SHOW WARNINGS command is used after executing one of those statements to see the warning messages."
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "Which mode is used to turn on strict mode and all of the additional restrictions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) STRICT_ALL_TABLES",
            "b) ERROR_FOR_DIVISION_BY_ZERO",
            "c) TRADITIONAL",
            "d) ERROR_WHEN_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To enable the check for divide by zero errors int all the storage engines, the SQL mode named ‘ERROR_FOR_DIVISION_BY_ZERO’ can be enabled. This is done by using SET sql_mode = ‘mode_name’."
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "Which mode is a shorthand for ‘both strict modes plus a bunch of other restrictions’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) STRICT_ALL_TABLES",
            "b) STRICT_TRANS_TABLES",
            "c) TRADITIONAL",
            "d) ERROR_WHEN_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘TRADITIONAL’ mode is used to enable the strict mode and all of the additional restrictions. It is done by the command SET sql_mod = ‘TRADITIONAL’; The other SQL modes have other functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "Which mode prevents MySQL to perform full checking of date parts?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALLOW_DATES_INVALID",
            "b) ALLOW_INVALID_DATES",
            "c) PREVENT_DATE_CHECK",
            "d) STOP_DATES_CHECK"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘TRADITIONAL’ mode is used to enable the strict mode. It also enables all of the additional restrictions by the command ‘SET sql_mod = ‘TRADITIONAL” The other SQL modes have other functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "Which keyword suppresses errors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SUPPRESS",
            "b) STOP",
            "c) PREVENT",
            "d) IGNORE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, it is also possible to selectively weaken the strict mode at some places. If the ALLOW_INVALID_DATES SQL mode is enabled, MySQL doesn’t perform full checking of the date parts."
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "Which mode prevents entry of the ‘zero’ date value in strict mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SUPPRESS",
            "b) NO_ZERO_DATE",
            "c) PREVENT",
            "d) NO_ZERO_IN_DATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, to suppress errors, IGNORE keyword is used with INSERT or UPDATE statements. With the IGNORE clause, statements that would result in an error due to invalid values result only in a warning."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "Which column attribute provides unique numbers for identification?",
        "Options": [
            "a) AUTO_INCREMENT",
            "b) UNSIGNED",
            "c) IDENTIFY",
            "d) DESCRIBE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the mechanism for providing unique numbers is through the AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute. It enables the generation of sequential numbers automatically. This facilitates identification."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "The AUTO_INCREMENT sequences normally begin at __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there can only be one column per table with the AUTO_INCREMENT attribute. It should also have an integer data type. The AUTO_INCREMENT is also allowed for floating point types."
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "The value of recently generated sequence number can be obtained by ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) LAST_INSERT_ID()",
            "b) LATEST_INSERT_ID()",
            "c) INITIAL_INSERT_ID()",
            "d) INSERT_ID()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute provides unique numbers for column identification. AUTO_INCREMENT sequences normally begin at 1 and increase monotonically like 1, 2, 3, and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "When no AUTO_INCREMENT value has been generated during the current connection, LAST_INSERT_ID() returns ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The value of most recently generated sequence number can be obtained by calling the LAST_INSERT_ID() function. This enables to reference the AUTO_INCREMENT value in the subsequent statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "Suppose the last row has the AUTO_INCREMENT column value 32. Suppose a new row is added by setting AUTO_INCREMENT value equal to 100. The next row added will have value _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 33",
            "c) 100",
            "d) 101"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘LAST_INSERT_ID()’ function returns zero when no ‘AUTO_INCREMENT’ value has been generated during the current connection with the server. It is tied to the current connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "The number of rows in the table is 10. Suppose all rows are deleted. The new row starts with sequence number _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 100",
            "d) 101"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘LAST_INSERT_ID()’ is tied only to AUTO_INCREMENT values that are generated during the current connection to the server. It is not affected by AUTO_INCREMENT tied with the other clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "In a MyISAM table, if the maximum value of an AUTO_INCREMENT increment column is 12 and that row is deleted, the next value generated is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12",
            "b) 13",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the new value is larger than the current next sequence number, then the sequence is reset to continue with the next value after that for the following rows. In this way, “bumping up” the counter is done."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "In MyISAM tables, when a table is emptied with the TRUNCATE TABLE, the counter begins at _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) arbitrary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the row containing the largest value in an AUTO_INCREMENT column is deleted, that value is reused the next time a new value is generated. In this case the sequence number is 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "The expression 12 DIV 5 evaluates to ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.4",
            "b) 2",
            "c) error",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘DIV’ operator in MySQL is used to perform the integer divisions. The operator ‘/’ performs the quotient of the operands. If result exceeds the 64-bit range, unpredicted results are shown."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "If the PIPES_AS_CONCAT is disabled, ‘abc’ || ‘xyz’ results in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) error",
            "d) -1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the SQL mode PIPES_AS_CONCAT is disabled, the SQL standard ‘||’ operation for string concatenation is not valid in MySQL. Both operands are converted to zero. So the result is zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "‘abc’ || ‘xyz’, when PIPES_AS_CONCAT is enabled, results in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) abcxyz",
            "d) xyzabc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the SQL mode PIPES_AS_CONCAT has been enabled, the SQL standard ‘||’ operation for string concatenation becomes valid in MySQL. Both operands are concatenated to give ‘abcxyz’."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "The expression ‘2 BETWEEN 2 AND 5’ results in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘BETWEEN ……. AND’ clause is used to return a boolean value, if the given operand value lies between the values specified by the ‘AND’ clause. The range endpoints are inclusive."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "The expression ‘HI’ LIKE NULL results in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL provides pattern matching based on the ‘REGEXP’ operator and regular expressions that are similar to those used in Unix programs, namely, grep, sed and vi. REGEXP does not take collation into account."
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, any pattern matching that is performed with the ‘NULL’ operand, fails. Expressions like: ‘abcdef’ LIKE NULL, NULL LIKE ‘%’, all result into the value NULL. NULL is not used to perform comparisons."
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct order of precedence (high to low)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) !, ^, <<, XOR",
            "b) ^, !,  <<, XOR",
            "c) !,  <<, XOR, ^",
            "d) !, ^, XOR,  <<"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the LIKE operator compares its operands as binary strings if either operand is a binary string. If the operands are non binary strings, the LIKE operator compares them according to their collation. "
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "0x61 + 0 results in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) ‘a’",
            "c) 97",
            "d) arbitrary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the wildcard characters may be specified anywhere in a pattern. The ‘%’ wildcard is used to match variable number of characters. Here, the wildcard matches all the four words."
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "The AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute is best used with which type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLOAT",
            "b) INT",
            "c) CHARACTER",
            "d) DOUBLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The AUTO_INCREMENT is a column attribute and it is best used with the integer datatypes. It automatically assigns monotonically increasing values to the AUTO_INCREMENT columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "Which datatype is best suited to store currency values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INT",
            "b) FLOAT",
            "c) DOUBLE",
            "d) DECIMAL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Currency is a numeric information. For monetary calculations, FLOAT and DOUBLE are subject to rounding error and may not be suitable. A DECIMAL(M, 2) type is best suited for it."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "If a column is expected to store values up to 2 million, the best datatype for it is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SMALLINT",
            "b) TINYINT",
            "c) MEDIUMINT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, there is no data type provided which has an optional time part. The ‘DATE’ type values never have a time part. The ‘DATETIME’ type values must have a time part in them."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "Which of these types store the longest length of strings?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHAR",
            "b) VARCHAR",
            "c) TINYTEXT",
            "d) TEXT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The different numeric types used in MySQL are used to store different range of values. To store values of the order of a million, the MEDIUMINT or BIGINT datatype is sufficient."
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "Which of these values is not valid as an AUTO_INCREMENT value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: in MySQL, the different string datatypes are used to store different lenghts of the string. Here, the length would refer to the number of characters in the string. TEXT stores longer strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "If an integer column is used for the values in range 1 to 99999, the best suitable datatype is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) MEDIUMINT SIGNED",
            "b) MEDIUMINT UNSIGNED",
            "c) SMALLINT SIGNED",
            "d) SMALLINT UNSIGNED"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘AUTO_INCREMENT’ columns must be NOT NULL. If the NOT NULL is omitted, MySQL adds it automatically. AUTO_INCREMENT column values begin with 1 and increase monotonically after it."
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "INT2 maps to MySQL type _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) TINYINT",
            "b) SMALLINT",
            "c) MEDIUMINT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘AUTO_INCREMENT’ values are a sequence of unique values assigned to the columns such that they increase monotonically. They begin with the value 1 and increment by a unit."
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "INT3 maps to MySQL type _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) TINYINT",
            "b) SMALLINT",
            "c) MEDIUMINT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the range starts from the positive value 1, it is best to keep the datatype as UNSIGNED. The maximum value is of the order of 10^5, so a MEDIUMINT datatype is well suited."
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "Which of these return a result to the client?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored functions",
            "b) Stored procedures",
            "c) Triggers",
            "d) Events"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Stored functions return a result from a calculation and can be used in expressions. Stored procedures do not return a result directly but can be used to perform general computations."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "Which of these is defined to execute when the table is modified only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored functions",
            "b) Stored procedures",
            "c) Triggers",
            "d) Events"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, triggers are associated with a table. They are defined to execute when the table is modified via INSERT, DELETE or UPDATE statements. MySQL supports objects to be stored on server side."
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "What executes on a time activated basis according to a schedule?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored program",
            "b) Events",
            "c) Triggers",
            "d) Stored procedures"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the events execute on a time activated basis according to a schedule. Triggers are defined to execute when the table is modified via INSERT, DELETE or UPDATE statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "Which character does the mysql client program recognize as a statement delimiter?",
        "Options": [
            "a) :",
            "b) .",
            "c) ;",
            "d) ,"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Stored programs improve database security because controlled access can be enabled to sensitive data by appropriate selection of the privileges a program has when it executes."
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "Which command is used to redefined the mysql delimiter?",
        "Options": [
            "a) redefine_delim",
            "b) delim_redefine",
            "c) delimiter",
            "d) redefine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: By default, mysql itself recognizes the semicolon as a statement delimiter, so the delimiter must be redefined temporarily to cause mysql to pass the entire stored program definition to the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "Which of the following characters cannot be used as a delimiter?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ,",
            "b) .",
            "c) ;",
            "d) \\"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To redefine the mysql delimiter, the delimiter command is used. A delimiter is a sequence of characters. It specifies the boundary between the separate regions in data streams."
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the character backslash character is reserved for specifying escape sequences. For example, the escape sequence ‘\\t’ specifies a tab space character. It cannot be used as a delimiter."
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements does not modify the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INSERT",
            "b) UPDATE",
            "c) DELETE",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the stored routines is a limited term. It refers only to the stored functions and procedures. Both types of objects are defined using the similar syntax and are discussed together."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "To produce a stored function, which statement is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PRODUCE FUNCTION",
            "b) CREATE FUNCTION",
            "c) PRODUCE PROCEDURE",
            "d) CREATE PROCEDURE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘CREATE FUNCTION’ statement is used to create a stored function in MySQL. The ‘CREATE PROCEDURE’ statement is used to create a stored procedure instead, from which values are not returned. "
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "How many values can be returned from a given stored function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the stored function cannot return multiple values. Instead, multiple stored functions can be written and invoked from within a single statement however, they are different from stored procedures."
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "How many values can be returned from a stored procedure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, unlike the stored functions, the stored procedures cannot return values. They can be used to perform calculations or produce the result sets passed back to the clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "Suppose a stored function named PI() is written in the database ‘sampdb’. How would it be called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PI()",
            "b) sampdb.PI()",
            "c) MySQL.PI()",
            "d) db.PI()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a stored function is defined with the same name as a built in function, the function name should be qualified with the database name when it is invoked. The function ‘PI()’ is built in."
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "Which privilege must be given to the database to create a stored function or procedure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE ROUTINE",
            "b) CREATE METHOD",
            "c) CREATE FUNCTION",
            "d) CREATE PROCEDURE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘CREATE ROUTINE’ privilege must be given for the database in order to create a stored function or procedure. Stored functions and procedures always belong to a particular database."
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "Which variable is set to zero when automatic privilege granting is not needed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) automatic_sp_privileges",
            "b) automatic_ps_privileges",
            "c) automatic_pg_privileges",
            "d) automatic_gp_privileges"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The automatic_sp_privileges system variable is set to zero when the automatic privilege granting is not needed and revocation should not be allowed to occur. It is a crucial system variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "Which procedure parameter enables the caller to pass in a value and get back a value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IN",
            "b) OUT",
            "c) INOUT",
            "d) GETINOUT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In an IN parameter, the caller passes a value into the procedure. An OUT parameter is exactly the opposite. The ‘INOUT’ parameter enables the caller to pass in a value and also to get back a value."
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "For the same input parameters, if the stored function returns the same result, it is called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) deterministic",
            "b) non deterministic",
            "c) regular",
            "d) monotonous"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The IN, OUT and INOUT keywords do not apply to stored functions, triggers and events. Triggers and events do not have parameters at all. For the stored functions, all parameters are like IN parameters."
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "10. What is abc in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> abc HANDLER <span class=\"kw1\">FOR</span> def ghi;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) action",
            "b) condition value",
            "c) statement",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the same input parameters, if the stored function returns the same result, it is called a deterministic function. Otherwise, the stored function is called not deterministic."
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to create a trigger?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE TRIGGER",
            "b) CREATE TRIGGERS",
            "c) PRODUCE TRIGGER",
            "d) PRODUCE TRIGGERS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, a trigger can examine or change new data values to be inserted or used to update a row in a table. This enables the enforcement of the data integrity constraints."
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "For which of the following are triggers not supported?",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) update",
            "c) insert",
            "d) views"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to create a trigger, the CREATE TRIGGER statement is used. The definition indicates the particular type of statement for which the trigger activates and whether it activates before or after the rows are modified."
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to remove a trigger?",
        "Options": [
            "a) REMOVE",
            "b) DELETE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) CLEAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the triggers are run only after the table modifications like insert, update and delete are run. Triggers are not supported for views. In order to create a trigger, the CREATE TRIGGER statement is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "Before MySQL 5.1.6 which privilege was required to create and drop triggers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PRIVILEGE",
            "b) TRIGGER",
            "c) SUPER",
            "d) MACRO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In order to delete a trigger, the DROP TRIGGER statement is used. The DROP TRIGGER construct is used by writing the phrase ‘DROP TRIGGER’ followed by the scheme name specification."
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "7. What is abc in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TRIGGER</span> abc <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">...</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">...</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> def <span class=\"kw1\">FOR</span> EACH <span class=\"kw1\">ROW</span> ghi;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) trigger name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) trigger statement",
            "d) update statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The privilege to create and drop triggers is version specific in MySQL. Before MySQL 5.1.6, the SUPER privilege was needed. Access control is more correctly handled post this version."
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "8. What is def in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TRIGGER</span> abc <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">...</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">...</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> def <span class=\"kw1\">FOR</span> EACH <span class=\"kw1\">ROW</span> ghi;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) trigger name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) trigger statement",
            "d) update statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, because a trigger is associated with a table, the TRIGGER privilege is a must for that table to be able to create and drop triggers for it. The SUPER privilege was used pre 5.1.6."
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "9. What is ghi in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TRIGGER</span> abc <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">...</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">...</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> def <span class=\"kw1\">FOR</span> EACH <span class=\"kw1\">ROW</span> ghi;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) trigger name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) trigger statement",
            "d) update statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the trigger creation construct is the ‘CREATE TRIGGER’ construct. It specifies the trigger name, the type of statement for which it is activated, and the table name and statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "10. What is def in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DECLARE</span> abc HANDLER <span class=\"kw1\">FOR</span> def ghi;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) action",
            "b) condition value",
            "c) statement",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The trigger creation construct in MySQL is the ‘CREATE TRIGGER’ construct. It specifies components like the trigger name, the type of statement for which it is activated, and the table name and statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "Which of these is a stored program associated with a schedule?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trigger",
            "b) Event",
            "c) Stored function",
            "d) Stored procedure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL version 5.1.6 and above has an event scheduler. It enables us to perform time activated database operations. An event is a stored program that is associated with a schedule."
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "Which of the following lines is used to turn on the event scheduler?",
        "Options": [
            "a) event_scheduler = ON",
            "b) eventscheduler = ON",
            "c) event_scheduler_ON",
            "d) events_scheduler_ON"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The event scheduler does not run by default, so it must be turned on if events are to be used. An event is a stored program that is associated with a schedule to perform database operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to check the status of the event scheduler at runtime?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW STATUS OF ‘event_scheduler’",
            "b) SHOW VARIABLES OF ‘event_scheduler’",
            "c) SHOW STATUS LIKE ‘event_scheduler’",
            "d) SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘event_scheduler’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The line ‘event_scheduler = ON’ is put in the option file that the server reads. The event scheduler does not run by default. It must be turned on if events are to used in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "Which value of event_scheduler enables checking status but not changing it at runtime?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ON",
            "b) OFF",
            "c) DISABLED",
            "d) ENABLED"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, in order to check the status of the event scheduler at runtime, the statement: SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘event_scheduler’; is used. The event_scheduler is a system variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "Which log does the event scheduler log to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) record",
            "c) library",
            "d) update"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, if the event_scheduler is set to ‘DISABLED’ at startup, its status cannot be changed but can be checked at runtime. The events can be created but they will not execute."
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "Which clause specifies periodic execution at fixed intervals?",
        "Options": [
            "a) EVERY",
            "b) ALL",
            "c) AT",
            "d) ALTERNATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, if the event scheduler is stopped, no events are run. It is also possible to leave the scheduler running but disable the individual events. This can be done with ‘DISABLED’."
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "To create or drop events for a database, which privilege should be granted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) DROP",
            "c) PRIVILEGE",
            "d) EVENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the event scheduler writes to the error log of the server, which can be checked for information about what the scheduler is doing. It logs the events as it runs them."
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "The default definer of an event is the user who _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) created the database",
            "b) created the event",
            "c) created the table",
            "d) created the column"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘EVERY n interval’ clause specifies the periodic execution at fixed intervals. The interval values are like those used for the DATE_ADD() function, such as HOUR, DAY or MONTH."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "The creation of a stored program is similar to the definition of a _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trigger",
            "b) Event",
            "c) View",
            "d) Table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When a stored program is created, an object is created that is to be executed later. This also the case when a view is defined: It sets up a SELECT statement intended for later invocation."
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "When the security context enables carefully written stored programs to be set up that provide controlled access to tables for users, it is called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) good",
            "b) bad",
            "c) illegal",
            "d) fare"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The security context is good if it enables carefully written stored programs to be set up that provide controlled access to tables for users who are not able to access them directly."
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "When a user creates a stored program that accesses sensitive data but forgets that other people who can invoke the object have the same access, the security context is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) good",
            "b) bad",
            "c) illegal",
            "d) fare"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The security context is bad if a user creates a stored program that accesses sensitive data but forgets that other people who can invoke the object have the same access to that data as its definer."
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "A stored procedure is invoked using the statement __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INVOKE",
            "b) SEE",
            "c) CALL",
            "d) RETURN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The triggers and events are invoked automatically by the server, so the concept of invoking user is not applied. Thus, they have no SQL SECURITY characteristic and always execute with definer privileges."
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "What produces result sets?",
        "Options": [
            "a) View",
            "b) SELECT",
            "c) Stored function",
            "d) Trigger"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, a stored procedure is invoked using the CALL statement. A stored procedure does not have a return value but can modify its parameters. It also returns some result sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "Which privilege is enabled to create of alter a stored function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SUPER",
            "b) PRIOR",
            "c) TOP",
            "d) SUPERIOR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, views are the stored queries that when referenced produce a result set. A view acts as a virtual table. A stored procedure is also a component that can return result sets."
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to create or alter a stored function, the SUPER privilege should be given in addition to the CREATE ROUTINE privilege that is normally required. Depending on the DEFINER value in the function definition SUPER might be required."
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the stored routines cannot contain arbitrary SQL statements. For example, the locking statements LOCK TABLES and UNLOCK TABLES are not permitted in the stored routines."
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "The maximum number of indexes on MyISAM table is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) more than 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are many techniques available for optimizing queries. Indexing is the most useful. Generally the one thing that makes the most difference is the proper use of indexes."
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "The data rows of a MyISAM table are stored in __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) data file",
            "b) index file",
            "c) log file",
            "d) error file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, for a MyISAM table, there can be more than one indexes. The data rows of the MyISAM table are stored in a data file and the index values are stored in a separate index file."
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "In a single table (with 10 columns) join query the number of values needed to examine per column is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The data rows of the MyISAM table are stored in a data file and the index values are stored in a separate index file. In MySQL, for a MyISAM table, there can be more than one indexes. "
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "5. Suppose tbl_1 is a table consisting of 8 rows and tbl_2 is a table consisting of 6 rows, the number of combinations through which the search is performed is __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> tbl_1<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>i1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> tbl_2<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>i2\n\t<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> tbl_1 <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> tbl_2\n\t<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> tbl_1<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>i1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> tbl_2<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>i2;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 14",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 48"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For indexing in the context of performing joins, in a single table query, the number of values that are needed to be examined per column is the number of rows in the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, when the tables are unindexed, the searches are run through all the possible combinations. In this case, the search space is 8 x 6 = 48, the product of the number of rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "If a column contains 7 values and 6 distinct values, the cardinality is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 13",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, all the MyISAM tables shared tablespace files size if bound by the operating system file size limits. For InnoDB tables shared tablespaces, it is not bound by this factor."
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "For a table having 4 columns, the number of columns to which hash function is applied when using hash indexes is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the cardinality of a column is the number of distinct values that it contains. A column that contains the values 1, 2, 3, 4, 4, 5, 6 has a cardinality of six and not seven."
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "The slow query log is written as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) numbers",
            "b) text",
            "c) image",
            "d) graph"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the hash indexes, a hash function is applied to each of the column values. The resulting hash values are stored in the index and used to perform lookups on it."
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "To check how MySQL would execute a SELECT query, which statement is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TELL",
            "b) SHOW",
            "c) DISPLAY",
            "d) EXPLAIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, by issuing an EXPLAIN statement MySQL displays some information about how it would execute a SELECT query without actually executing it. It is prefixed with the query."
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "To perform analysis of key values by the server, the statement used is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANALYZE KEYS",
            "b) ANALYZE TABLE",
            "c) PERFORM ANALYSIS",
            "d) PERFORM TABLE ANALYSIS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the MyISAM and InnoDB tables, the server can be told to perform an analysis of key values by issuing the ANALYZE TABLE statement. It helps in knowing about query optimization."
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to verify optimizer operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANALYZE",
            "b) VERIFY",
            "c) EXPLAIN",
            "d) SHOW"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The EXPLAIN statement in MySQL can tell whether the indexes are being used or not. This information is helpful when different ways of writing a statement need to be tested."
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to force the optimizer to use tables in a particular order?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FORCE INDEX",
            "b) USE INDEX",
            "c) IGNORE INDEX",
            "d) STRAIGHT_JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: STRAIGHT_JOIN is used to force the optimizer to use tables in a particular order. The MySQL optimizer by default considers itself free to determine the order in which to scan tables most quickly."
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "Which of these comparisons is slowest?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INT/INT",
            "b) INT/BIGINT",
            "c) BIGINT/BIGINT",
            "d) All are of same speed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: On comparing indexed columns, identical data types will give better performance than dissimilar types. So an INT/INT or BIGINT/BIGINT comparison is faster than an INT/BIGINT comparison."
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "6. Which of the following WHERE clauses are faster?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">.</span> <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> col <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> &amp;lt; <span class=\"nu0\">9</span>\n    <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">.</span> <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> col &amp;lt; <span class=\"nu0\">9</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) same speed",
            "d) dependent on operating system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For the first variation, MySQL would retrieve the value of ‘col’ for each row, multiply by three, and then compare the result to nine. In this case, no index can be used and hence it is slower."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "7. What are the results of the following SQL commands if col is an integer column?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">.</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> mytbl <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> num_col <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'4'</span>;\n\t<span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">.</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> mytbl <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> num_col <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) same",
            "b) different",
            "c) 1 is an error",
            "d) 2 is an error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The first query invokes a type conversion. The conversion operation involves some performance penalty for converting the integer and string to double to perform the comparison."
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "Which system variable tells the optimizer to skip certain plans based on estimates of the number of rows accessed for each table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) optimizer_prune_level",
            "b) optimizer_search_depth",
            "c) optimizer_search",
            "d) optimizer_prune"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The optimizer_prune_level variable tells the optimizer to skip certain plans based on estimates of the number of rows accessed for each table. This option is kept on by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "Which system variable tells how far into the rest of each incomplete plan the optimizer should look to evaluate whether it should be expanded further?",
        "Options": [
            "a) optimizer_prune_level",
            "b) optimizer_search_depth",
            "c) optimizer_search",
            "d) optimizer_prune"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the optimizer_search_depth system variable tells how far into the “future” of each incomplete plan the optimizer should look to evaluate whether it should be expanded further."
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "To convert an int to string, the function is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INET_ATON()",
            "b) INET_NTOA()",
            "c) INET_ITOS()",
            "d) INET_STOI()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Numbers can be compared in a single operation while string comparisons involve several byte by byte or character by character comparisons. As the strings become longer, the performance gets poor. "
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "To convert a string to an int, the function is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INET_ATON()",
            "b) INET_NTOA()",
            "c) INET_ITOS()",
            "d) INET_STOI()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the function used to convert an integer to a string is INET_NTOA(). On the other hand, the function INET_ATON() converts a string to the corresponding integer value. "
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "To maintain performance of tables having variable length rows, which statement is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MAINTAIN TABLE",
            "b) BALANCE TABLE",
            "c) ADJUST TABLE",
            "d) OPTIMIZE TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the function used to convert a string to an integer is INET_ATON(). On the other hand, the function INET_NTOA() converts a string to the corresponding integer value. "
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Options": [
            "a) same",
            "b) variable length",
            "c) fixed length",
            "d) indeterminate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the variable length rows, there is more fragmentation of the table on which many deletes or updates are performed. OPTIMIZE TABLE is run periodically to maintain performance. "
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) variable length",
            "b) same",
            "c) fixed length",
            "d) indeterminate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The fixed length columns are faster and take more space. CHAR(n) columns take n characters per value because the values are padded with trailing spaces when stored in the table. "
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHAR",
            "b) VARCHAR",
            "c) CHAR & VARCHAR",
            "d) Either CHAR or VARCHAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, the fixed length columns are faster and take more space. CHAR(n) columns take n characters per value because the values are padded with trailing spaces when stored in the table. "
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "Which of these can be used to generate hash values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MS5()",
            "b) MA5()",
            "c) MF5()",
            "d) MD5()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, because CHAR on average takes more space than VARCHAR, VARCHAR is preferred to be used to minimize the amount of the storage and disk I/O needed to process the rows. "
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "IP numbers can be represented as _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) both integers and a string",
            "b) a string  but not integers",
            "c) integers but not a string",
            "d) neither a string nor integers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, avoiding the NULL in columns may make the queries simpler, since it is not required to check for NULL as a special case. Simpler queries generally can be processed more quickly. "
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Options": [
            "a) LOAD DATA",
            "b) INSERT",
            "c) Same",
            "d) Indeterminate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, bulk loading is more efficient than the single row loading. The key cache does not need to be flushed after each input record is loaded. It can also be flushed at the end of the batch of records."
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "Without LOCAL, LOAD DATA is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) more efficient",
            "b) less efficient",
            "c) same speed",
            "d) arbitrary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Loading is faster when a table has no indexes. If there are indexes, the contents of the row should be added to the table and each index must also be modified to notify the addition of the new row."
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "Which option turns on the –extended-insert?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –opt",
            "b) –opti",
            "c) –op",
            "d) –optimize"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘LOAD DATA’ in all forms is more efficient than the ‘INSERT’ because it loads rows in bulk. The server first parses then interprets only one statement instead of many."
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "Which table option for MyISAM tables reduces index flushing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DELAY_KEY_WRITE",
            "b) DELAY_WRITE_KEY",
            "c) KEY_WRITE_DELAY",
            "d) WRITE_KEY_DELAY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LOAD DATA is more efficient without LOCAL. Without LOCAL, the file must be located on the server. The FILE privilege must be given. The server can read the file directly from disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "Which option repairs MyISAM tables automatically after they open?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –myisam-recover=FORCE",
            "b) –myisam-recover=STOP",
            "c) –recover-myisam=FORCE",
            "d) –recover-myisam=STOP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the –opt option is enabled it turns on the –extended-insert option, which produces multiple row INSERT statements and some other options that allow the dump file to be processed more efficiently."
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "The option which delays index flushing for slave server is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –delay-write-key=ALL",
            "b) –delay-key-write=ALL",
            "c) –key-write-delay=NONE",
            "d) –key-delay-write=NONE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For MyISAM tables a strategy for reducing index flushing is to use the DELAY_KEY_WRITE table option. With this option the data rows are written to the data file immediately."
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "TO enable the compressed client/server protocol the option is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –enable",
            "b) –compress",
            "c) –reduce",
            "d) –restrict"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to make sure that the repairs happen the server is started with the –myisam-recover=FORCE option. This enables the server to check MyISAM tables when it opens them and repair them automatically."
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "To reactivate indexes the command used is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DISABLE KEYS",
            "b) DISABLE INDEXES",
            "c) ENABLE KEYS",
            "d) ENABLE INDEXES"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For the replication slave servers, the –delay-key-write=ALL option delays index flushing for all MyISAM tables, regardless of how they were created originally on the master server."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Options": [
            "a) writes",
            "b) reads",
            "c) same priority",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A client performing an operation that modifies a table is a writer and the client that performs a retrieval from the table is a reader. The writes have higher priority than reads."
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The MyISAM, MERGE and the MEMORY storage engines implement the default scheduling policy of MySQL with the help of the table locks. Whenever a client accesses a table a lock for it must be acquired first."
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "Which statement issues a lock on tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISSUE LOCK",
            "b) LOCK ISSUE",
            "c) LOCK TABLES",
            "d) ISSUE LOCKS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Locks can be acquired and released explicitly by issuing LOCK TABLES and UNLOCK TABLES statements. Normally the server’s lock manager automatically acquires locks as necessary and releases them when they no longer are needed."
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Reading does not change the table. There is no reason one reader should prevent another from accessing the table. So a read lock enables other clients to read the table at the same time."
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The LOW_PRIORITY statement modifier influences the default scheduling policy of MySQL. This keyword applies to all the four: DELETE, INSERT, LOAD DATA, REPLACE. It also applies to UPDATE."
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the LOW_PRIORITY and HIGH_PRIORITY modifiers have an effect only for those storage engines that use table locks. The storage engines MyISAM, MERGE and MEMORY use table locks."
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "Find the odd one out in terms of scheduling policies.",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) MEMORY",
            "d) MERGE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘DELAYED’ statement modifier that influences the default scheduling policies of MySQL works for the following tables: MyISAM, MEMORY, ARCHIVE and as of MySQL 5.1.19, also for BLACKHOLE tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "Which table is preferred when there are many updates?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) MEMORY",
            "d) MERGE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The InnoDB storage engine implements locking at a different level. It has differing performance characteristics in terms of contention management. It uses row-level locks."
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Options": [
            "a) memory",
            "b) disk",
            "c) same speed",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the administrators have more privileges since they have more control of the MySQL server or the machine on which it runs. Accessing data in memory is faster than from disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "Which system variable controls the size of the table cache?",
        "Options": [
            "a) table_cache",
            "b) cache_table",
            "c) open_cache",
            "d) cache_open"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, when the server opens table files it keeps them open to minimize the number of file-opening operations. It maintains information about open files in the table cache."
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "Which status indicator assesses how effective the table cache is?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Open_tables",
            "b) Opened_tables",
            "c) Close_tables",
            "d) Closed_tables"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the server accesses various tables, the table cache fills up. The server closes the tables that have not been used recently in order to make room for opening the new tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "In MySQL, the default size of the key buffer in MB is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 16",
            "d) 32"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The larger values allow MySQL to hold more index blocks in memory at once. This increases the chances of finding key values in memory without having to read a new block from disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "The system variable to maintain InnoDB log buffer size is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) innodb_log_buffer_size",
            "b) innodb_buffer_log_size",
            "c) buffer_log_innodb_size",
            "d) log_buffer_innodb_size"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The InnoDB storage engine has its own cache used for buffering the data and index values. It maintains a log buffer. The size for this is controlled by innodb_log_buffer_size."
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "To determine whether query cache is supported by the server the variable is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) have_query_cache",
            "b) have_cache_query",
            "c) query_cache_have",
            "d) cache_query_have"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A query is not cached if the query returns non deterministic results. For example, a query that uses the NOW() function returns different results over time. Therefore, it cannot be cached."
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "Which mode tells not to cache query results?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, in order to determine whether a server supports the query cache or not, the value of the ‘have_query_cache’ system variable is checked. It returns ‘YES’ if support is available."
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "Which mode tells cache queries that begin with SELECT SQL_CACHE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The have_query_cache system variable is used to check whether there is support for query cache. The mode ‘0’ tells not to cache the query results or to retrieve the cached results."
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "Which command is used to remove existing tables or database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP TABLE",
            "b) DELETE",
            "c) Either DROP TABLE or DELETE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "Which command is used to display all the existing tables in a database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW TABLES",
            "b) SHOW TABLE",
            "c) SHOW",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "Is duplicate entry of primary key is allowed in SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Primary key are used to uniquely define attributed stored in the table.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "Is duplicate entry of other attributes are allowed in SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Duplicate values are allowed but not for Primary Key attributes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "Which is the correct format to store date in the SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DEC-01-1991",
            "b) 01-1991-11",
            "c) 01-DEC-12",
            "d) 1991-11-01"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "Which of the following are the valid “database datatypes” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numerical",
            "b) Temporal",
            "c) Text",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "7. Find the error in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> person\n<span class=\"br0\">(</span> person_id <span class=\"kw1\">SMALLINT</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> name <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LAST</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span>\n  CONSTRAINTS pk_person <span class=\"kw1\">PRIMARY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">KEY</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n  <span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> person\n  <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LAST</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n  <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ’s’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ’p’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n  <span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> person\n  <span class=\"br0\">(</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LAST</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’s’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’p’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No error",
            "b) Error, Duplicate value",
            "c) Any other error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Primary can never have same value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "8. Find the error in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">  <span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> person\n  <span class=\"br0\">(</span> person_id <span class=\"kw1\">SMALLINT</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> name <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LAST</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VARCHAR</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> Bith_date <span class=\"kw1\">DATE</span>\n  CONSTRAINTS pk_person <span class=\"kw1\">PRIMARY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">KEY</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>person_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;\n  <span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> person\n  <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LAST</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> Birth_date<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n  <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’s’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’p’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">24</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1991</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) In correct data value",
            "b) No error",
            "c) Any other error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Format for DATE datatype is YYYY-MM-DD.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Which Key is used to link two tables in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Primary Key",
            "b) Foreign Key",
            "c) Both Primary and Foreign Key",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Foreign Key is only the Key which can link two tables.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "Which line of the following statements will produce error?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM person WHERE person_id=1;",
            "b) SELECT pname FROM person;",
            "c) SELECT pname, lname, person_id FROM person;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "Which compiler is used to execute the structured query language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DCL",
            "b) DDL",
            "c) DML",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: Structured query language consists of Data manipulation language as well as data definition language. Therefore DML compiler.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "Which among the following tags belong to Data definition language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) FROM",
            "c) WHERE",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Data definition language contains all tags which are used for the definition of the structures in Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "Which among the following tags belong to Data Manipulation language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UPDATE",
            "b) ALTER",
            "c) MODIFY",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Data Manipulation language contains all tags which are used for manipulating the existing structure in Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "Query Mechanism performs the following functions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax correction",
            "b) Checking permission for executing the query",
            "c) Checking permission for accessing the desired data",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "What jobs “Query Optimizer” perform in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Determine the efficient way to execute a query",
            "b) Syntax errors",
            "c) Permissions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Query optimizer is used to find the efficient way to execute a query in Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "6. What is the meaning of “EMPTY SET” in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> person_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’s’;\n<span class=\"coMULTI\">/* after Execution*/</span> Mysql tool <span class=\"kw1\">RETURN</span> EMPTY <span class=\"kw1\">SET</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span>:00sec</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No values",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Access denied",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “EMPTY SET” means there were no values stored in the structure that belongs to lname.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "Which are the two languages used in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DML/DDL",
            "b) DDL/DCL",
            "c) DML/DDM",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: DDL (Data Definition Language)\n                        DML (Data Manipulation Language).\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "The users responsible for  query processing in database system are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Native users",
            "b) Application programmers",
            "c) Sophisticated users",
            "d) Specialized users"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: Sophisticated users interact with the system without writing any application programs; they form the request in a database query language.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "Select the sequence for how the query mechanism works?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Authentication-> DDL->DML->query optimizer->output",
            "b) DDL->DML->query optimizer-> Authentication->output",
            "c) DML->query optimizer-> Authentication-> DDL-> output",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answers: a\nExplanation: When we execute any query, the first step is authentication (password). Second step for data definition mechanism, the third step is for Data Manipulation and the last is optimizer for efficient execution.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to determine “which column to include in the query sets”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) FROM",
            "c) WHERE",
            "d) ORDER BY"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to “Identifies table from which to draw table and how the table should be joined”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FROM",
            "b) SELECT",
            "c) ORDER By",
            "d) WHERE"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to “Filters out unwanted data”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FROM",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) ORDER BY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to “group rows together by common columns values”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) GROUP BY",
            "c) FROM",
            "d) WHERE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to “filter out unwanted Groups”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) HAVING",
            "b) FROM",
            "c) WHERE",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to “sort the rows of the final result set by one or more columns”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) HAVING",
            "b) ORDER BY",
            "c) WHERE",
            "d) FROM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to “Modify the existing field of the table”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER",
            "b) FROM",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) MODIFY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a “query clause”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) MODIFY",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) FROM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Modify is not a clause, it just used with clause Alter.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "“MODIFY” is used with which “Query clause”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER",
            "b) FROM",
            "c) WHERE",
            "d) ORDER BY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Modify is not a clause, it just used with clause Alter.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "What exports table definitions and contents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqladmin",
            "c) mysqlimport",
            "d) mysqlexport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, some distributions include a set of some client programs. ‘mysqldump’ exports the table definitions and the contents. ‘mysqladmin’ performs adminisitrative tasks."
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "What loads data files into tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqladmin",
            "c) mysqlimport",
            "d) mysqlexport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘mysqlimport’ loads the data files into the tables. In MySQL, some distributions include a set of some client programs. ‘mysqldump’ exports the table definitions and the contents."
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "What performs administrative operations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqladmin",
            "c) mysqlimport",
            "d) mysqlexport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, some distributions include a set of some client programs. ‘mysqladmin’ performs the administrative operations. ‘mysqlimport’ loads the data files into the tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "Which option executes all SQL statements in a SQL script irrespective of the number of errors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –ensure",
            "b) –violent",
            "c) –force",
            "d) –run"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: With mysql, raw SQL statements can be entered. With MySQL programs input methods can be provided for the user that are more intuitive and easier to be used. So input handling is customized."
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "Which of these is used during MySQL setup?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqld_multi",
            "b) mysql.server",
            "c) mysqld_safe",
            "d) comp_err"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Input provided by the user can be validated. For instance, dates can be checked to make sure they conform to the format that MySQL expects, or certain fields can be filled in to check."
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "Which of these is not used to connect to the MySQL server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql",
            "b) mysqladmin",
            "c) mysqlcheck",
            "d) mysql_upgrade"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If SQL queries in a file are run using mysql in batch mode, mysql either quits after the first error. If the –force option is specified all the queries are executed indiscriminately."
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "Which program emulates the client load for a MySQL server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqlslap",
            "b) mysqldump",
            "c) mysqladmin",
            "d) mysqlimport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The program ‘comp_err’ is used during the MySQL build or the MySQL installation process. This program compiles the error message files from the error source files. The others are not run during startup."
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "Which program reads the statement from a binary log?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_config",
            "b) mysqlbinlog",
            "c) mysqldump",
            "d) mysqlimport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: mysql_upgrade is used after a MySQL upgrade operation. It checks tables for incompatibilities and repairs them if necessary. It updates the grant tables with any changes that have been made in newer versions of MySQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The client library provides the means through which the MySQL bindings for other languages can be built on top of the C API. This type of interface exists for Perl, PHP, Python and others."
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "Which language is the core for APIs and communication in MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) C++",
            "c) Python",
            "d) Ruby"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to provide application development, MySQL provides a client library written in the C programming language. It enables the access of MySQL databases from a C program."
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are interfaces for languages like Java, PHP and Python that implement the native client-server protocol directly instead of using the C library to handle communications."
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "The primary programming interface to MySQL is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) C API",
            "b) C++ API",
            "c) Java API",
            "d) Python API"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Each language binding defines its own interface that dictates all the rules for accessing MySQL. Popular and useful programming languages like C++, Java, Python, PHP and others."
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "The DBI API for Perl is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) database interface",
            "b) database id",
            "c) database identity",
            "d) database integrity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The primary programming interface to MySQL is the C API. It is used to implement some of the standard clients in the MySQL distribution including mysql, mysqladmin and mysqldump."
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "For which language is the engine specific interface PDO defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Python",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) PHP",
            "d) C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, DBI is implemented as a Perl module. It interfaces with other modules at the DBD (Database Driver) level. Each of it provides access to a specific database engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "For which language is the PEAR module used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Python",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) PHP",
            "d) C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Like DBI, PHP includes support for accessing several database engines in addition to MySQL. It has engine specific interfaces, and interfaces that are more engine independent."
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "The JDBI interface is available for _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) C++",
            "c) Python",
            "d) Java"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The PEAR database module is specified for the language PHP. PHP is a server side scripting language and it provides an appropriate method of embedding programs in the web pages."
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "Which of these is the most general purpose language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) Python",
            "d) PHP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: C is a general purpose language, so in principle it can be used for anything. C tends to be used more often for standalone programs rather than for Web programming in practice."
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "Among the following, for which language is image processing least simple?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PHP",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) Python",
            "d) C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It is not as easy to perform text processing and memory management in C than it is in languages like Perl and PHP. These capabilities tend to be heavily used in the web applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "The CGI.pm module for website development is a part of _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Perl",
            "b) Java",
            "c) Python",
            "d) C++"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Like C, Perl is also suitable for writing standalone programs. However, Perl is quite useful for Web site development. The CGI.pm module of Perl can be extensively used for it."
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "For a heavily used program, which of these languages should be preferred?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) PHP",
            "d) Python"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For interpreted languages used in web development, the performance is better when the interpreter is invoked as a module which is a part of the Web server itself. Compiler is faster generally."
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "The protocol CGI is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) computer graphics interface",
            "b) common graphics interface",
            "c) computer gateway interface",
            "d) common gateway interface"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: C is compiled while Perl and PHP are interpreted. So C programs generally will run faster than Perl or PHP scripts. Therefore C should be the best choice for a heavily used program."
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Options": [
            "a) Perl",
            "b) PHP",
            "c) same",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The web server ‘Apache’ uses the interpreters as some CGI programs. This means that it communicates with these programs using the popular ‘Common Gateway Interface (CGI)’ protocol."
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "Which is the correct decreasing order for highly developed text manipulation capabilities?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Perl, PHP, C",
            "b) Perl, C, PHP",
            "c) PHP, Perl, C",
            "d) C, PHP, Perl"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The startup penalty for a standalone interpreter makes it give at least an order of magnitude poorer performance than the module interpreter. Interpreters also have a setup cost."
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "Which API provides the lowest level interface to the server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C API",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) PHP",
            "d) Python"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A clearly significant difference between Perl and PHP is that Perl has a bigger memory footprint than PHP. Apache processes are larger with ‘mod_perl’ linked in than with ‘mod_php’."
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "Which option is necessary to compile a C program havin math functions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -lm",
            "b) -ln",
            "c) -lp",
            "d) -lq"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To compile a program written in the C language, it is compiled by issuing the option ‘-lm’. The examples of some math functions found in ‘math.h’ are floor(), sqrt(), pow(), log()."
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": "The option for specifying the executable name while compiling with gcc is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -e",
            "b) -o",
            "c) -a",
            "d) -b"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a C program is compiled with gcc, the option -o is issued in order to specify the name of the executable that is created after compilation. The default name given is ‘a.out’."
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "Which file can be used to execute multiple compile statements?",
        "Options": [
            "a) makefile",
            "b) dofile",
            "c) putfile",
            "d) pushfile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Makefile is used to write multiple commands in there. The file is executed by prefixing the command ‘make’ with the command to run the file script containing the statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "Which flag is used to compile client programs that use MySQL header files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -O",
            "b) -I",
            "c) -U",
            "d) -A"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘-I’ option is specified when the client programs are compiled that use the MySQL header files. The compiler can easily find these header files when the ‘-I’ option is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "The MySQL clients are linked with _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -lmysqlclient",
            "b) -cmysqlclient",
            "c) -dmysqlclient",
            "d) -vmysqlclient"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL clients should be linked using the ‘-lmysqlclient’ option in the link command. A ‘-L’ option also needs to be specified to tell the linker where to find the library for it."
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "What can be used as an alternative to mysqlconfig?",
        "Options": [
            "a) pkg-config",
            "b) dkg-config",
            "c) rkg-config",
            "d) qkg-config"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: On Unix, the linking process uses the dynamic libraries by default. In order to link to the static client library instead, its path name should be added to the link command to do the job."
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Options": [
            "a) Perl",
            "b) PHP",
            "c) Same",
            "d) Machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘pkg-config’ statement can be used as an alternative to the ‘mysql_config’ statement for obtaining information like compiler flags or to link libraries required to compile some MySQL applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "The static C library client in Windows is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqlclient.lib",
            "b) mysqlclient.lb",
            "c) mysqlclient.lm",
            "d) myclient.lib"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A clearly significant difference between Perl and PHP is that Perl has a bigger memory footprint than PHP. Apache processes are larger with ‘mod_perl’ linked in than with ‘mod_php’."
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used on Solaris?",
        "Options": [
            "a) gcc",
            "b) clang",
            "c) Sun Studio",
            "d) FreeBSD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The code can be linked with either the dynamic or static C client library. On Windows, the static library is named ‘mysqlclient.lib’ and the dynamic library is named ‘libmysql.dll’. "
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "Which library file contains various portability macros and definitions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘my_sys.h’ header file contains a variety of portability macros and definitions required for structures and functions. These structures and functions are used by the client library."
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "Which header should be included first?",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The file ‘my_global.h’ takes care of including several other header files that are likely to be generally useful, like ‘stdio.h’. It also includes Windows compatibility information."
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "mysql_init() returns a _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) structure",
            "d) pointer to a structure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When NULL is passed to mysql_init() it automatically allocates a MYSQL structure, initializes it, and returns a pointer to it. The MYSQL data type is a structure containing information about a connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "Which of these can be used in place of MYSQL_SERVER_VERSION?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIBMYSQL_VERSION",
            "b) LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "c) MYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "d) MYSQL_ID"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Generally, when linking to a static MySQL C client library, the client library and the client application must use the same compiler option when it is required to link the C runtime."
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used interchangeably with MYSQL_VERSION_ID?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIBMYSQL_VERSION",
            "b) LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "c) MYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "d) MYSQL_ID"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macros ‘LIBMYSQL_VERSION’ and ‘LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID’ have the same values as ‘MYSQL_SERVER_VERSION’ and ‘MYSQL_VERSION_ID’ and the two sets of macros can be used in place of each other."
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "Which option is supplied to ensure TCP/IP connection to local server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –localhost",
            "b) –host",
            "c) –hostlocal",
            "d) –connectlocal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘LIBMYSQL_VERSION’ and ‘LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID’ macros have the same values as ‘MYSQL_SERVER_VERSION’ and ‘MYSQL_VERSION_ID’ and the two sets of macros can be used interchangeably."
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "The –protocol value ‘TCP’ runs on which operating systems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) all",
            "b) unix only",
            "c) windows only",
            "d) none"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In order to ensure that the client makes a TCP/IP connection to the local server, the ‘–host’ or ‘-h’ option is used to specify a host name value of 127.0.0.1 or the IP address of the local server."
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "The ‘SOCKET’ protocol is permitted on which operating systems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) all",
            "b) unix only",
            "c) windows only",
            "d) none"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The connections to remote servers always use TCP/IP. To connect to the server running on remote.example.com using the default port number (3306) this command is used: mysql –host=remote.example.com."
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "1. How many of the following use NULL to indicate failure?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_init<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_connect<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Both of the client library routines named ‘mysql_init()’ and ‘mysql_real_connect()’ return a pointer to the connection handler in order to indicate success and NULL to indicate failure."
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "2. How many of the following does not return a value?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\tmysql_close<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_init<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_connect</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is not necessary that every Application Programming Interface call would return a value. For example, the client routine named ‘mysql_close()’ returns void, that is, it does not return a value."
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "Which of these returns a string containing an error message?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_error()",
            "b) mysql_errno()",
            "c) mysql_sqlstate()",
            "d) mysql_close()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The API call named ‘mysql_error()’ returns a string containing an error message. ‘mysql_close()’ does not return any value at all. ‘mysql_errno()’ returns a MySQL-specific numeric code."
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns a MySQL-specific numeric code?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_error()",
            "b) mysql_errno()",
            "c) mysql_sqlstate()",
            "d) mysql_close()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The API call named ‘mysql_errorno()’ returns a MySQL-specific numeric error code. ‘mysql_error()’ returns a string containing an error message. ‘mysql_close()’ does not return any value at all."
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns an SQLSTATE code?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_error()",
            "b) mysql_errno()",
            "c) mysql_sqlstate()",
            "d) mysql_close()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The MySQL API call named ‘mysql_sqlstate()’ returns an SQLSTATE code. This SQLSTATE value is more ‘vendor neutral’ because it is based on the ‘ANSI SQL’ and ‘ODBC’ standards."
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "The argument to the function mysql_error() is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) structure",
            "d) pointer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The argument to the API functions ‘mysql_error()’, ‘mysql_errno()’ and ‘mysql_sqlstate()’ is a pointer to the connection handler. These should be called after an error occurs."
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "What does mysql_real_connect() return if it fails?",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) structure",
            "d) NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The function ‘mysql_real_connect()’ must complete successfully before any other API functions that require a valid MYSQL connection handler structure can be executed. It returns NULL on failure."
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "The –protocol value ‘TCP’ runs on which operating systems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) unix only",
            "b) windows only",
            "c) all",
            "d) none"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function named ‘load_defaults()’ reads the option files. It takes four arguments. It does not pick up values from the environment settings. All connection parameters can be brought to the argument vector."
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "The general statement-issuing routine is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_real_query()",
            "b) mysql_query_real()",
            "c) mysql_image_query()",
            "d) mysql_query_image()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The general statement-issuing routine is mysql_real_query(). The statement is provided as a counted string (a string plus a length). The length of the statement string must be kept track of."
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "2. Which of these is more restrictive?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_query<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_query<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_query()",
            "b) mysql_real_query()",
            "c) same",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement-issuing function other than ‘mysql_real_query()’ is ‘mysql_query()’. It is more restrictive in what it allows in the statement string although it is often easier to use."
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "For failure, mysql_query() returns _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) a non-zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both of the functions named ‘mysql_query()’ and ‘mysql_real_query()’ return zero for statements that succeed. They return non zero for failure. A statement is successfully executed if the server accepts it."
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, it is important to note that ‘SELECT’ is not the only statement that returns some rows. Statements like ‘SHOW’, ‘DESCRIBE’, ‘EXPLAIN’ and ‘CHECK TABLE’ do so as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "mysql_fetch_row() returns _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) structure",
            "d) pointer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘mysql_fetch_row()’ returns a MYSQL_ROW value, a pointer to an array of values. If the return value is assigned to a variable named row each value within the row is accessed as row[i]."
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "8. How many of the following take a connection handler as an argument?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_store_result<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_use_result<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The columns containing binary value including null bytes do not print properly using the %s printf() format specifier. printf() expects a null terminated string. It prints the column value only up to the first null byte."
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "9. Which of these has a lower memory requirements?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_use_result<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_store_result<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_use_result()",
            "b) mysql_store_result()",
            "c) same",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The functions ‘mysql_store_result()’ and ‘mysql_use_result()’ are similar because both of them take a connection handler argument and then return a result set after carrying out processes."
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The functions ‘mysql_store_result()’ and ‘mysql_use_result()’ are similar because both of them take a connection handler argument and then return a result set after carrying out the processes."
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "What enables encrypted connections to be established?",
        "Options": [
            "a) exec_stmt_ssl",
            "b) exec_ssl_stmt",
            "c) exec_stmnt_ssl",
            "d) exec_ssl_stmnt"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the ‘exec_stmt_ssl’ to work properly, MySQL must have been built with SSL support, and the server must be started with the proper options that identify its certificate and key files."
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "The exec_stmt_ssl is written in _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) C++",
            "b) C",
            "c) Python",
            "d) Perl"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘sampdb’ distribution contains a source file named ‘exec_stmt_ssl.c’ from which the client program ‘exec_stmt_ssl’ can be built. There is a procedure to build this file."
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": "On failure, ‘mysql_query()’ returns _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) a non-zero value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both of the functions named ‘mysql_query()’ and ‘mysql_real_query()’ return zero for statements that succeed. They return non zero for failure. A statement is successfully executed if the server accepts it."
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "Which mode prevents MySQL to perform full checking of date parts?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PREVENT_DATE_CHECK",
            "b) STOP_DATES_CHECK",
            "c) ALLOW_DATES_INVALID",
            "d) ALLOW_INVALID_DATES"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: With mysql, raw SQL statements can be entered. With MySQL programs input methods can be provided for the user that are more intuitive and easier to be used. So input handling is customized."
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to determine the storage engine for individual tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW TABLE STATUS",
            "b) SHOW DEFAULT STATUS",
            "c) SHOW STATUS OF TABLE",
            "d) SHOW STATUS TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For the numeric or TIME columns, the values that are outside the legal range are clipped to the nearest endpoint of the range. The resulting value is stored. This is the method to handle defaults for numerics."
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "Which table in the ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ stores information about storage engines and server plugins?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ENGINES, PLUGINS",
            "b) FILES, PLUGINS",
            "c) PLUGINS, STATISTICS",
            "d) ENGINES, FILES"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, it is also possible to selectively weaken the strict mode in some places. If the ALLOW_INVALID_DATES SQL mode is enabled, MySQL doesn’t perform full checking of the date parts."
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL provides a method to determine the storage engine for each table with the ‘SHOW TABLE STATUS’ statement. The output of this statement is the name of the storage engine indicator."
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "The embedded server library containing the MySQL server linkable into applications is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) libmysqla",
            "b) libmysqlb",
            "c) libmysqlc",
            "d) libmysqld"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MySQL includes an embedded server library, libmysqld, containing the MySQL server in a way that can be linked into applications. This enables the production of MySQL-based standalone applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "When building from source, the embedded server library is enabled by _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –with-embedded-server",
            "b) –with-server-embedded",
            "c) –with-embedded-library",
            "d) –with-library-embedded"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: While building from the source, the embedded server library is enabled by using the option ‘–with-embedded-server’ while running ‘configure’. This applies equally to MySQL 5.0 and 5.1."
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "Which clause is used to display information that matches a given pattern?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) IS",
            "c) SAME",
            "d) LIKE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, an embedded application includes both a client side and a server side, in order that it can process one group of options for the client and another group for the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "Comparing a known value with NULL results into _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) null",
            "b) zero",
            "c) a positive value",
            "d) a negative value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Writing an application that uses the embedded server is different from writing one that operates in a client/server context. A program that is written as a client/server application can easily be converted to use the embedded server."
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "Which is the command to move the cursor to the beginning of line in mysql input editor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ctrl-E",
            "b) Ctrl-D",
            "c) Esc-a",
            "d) Ctrl-A"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘LIKE’ clause filters information that match a given pattern. ‘WHERE’ clause selects information that is specified by a condition. ‘IS’ is used to match the exact condition specified. "
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "The name of the option file in Unix is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) .my.cnf",
            "b) .my.ini",
            "c) .my.opt",
            "d) .my.opc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, NULL is not comparable to other known values. It will result in a NULL when compared to any value. The following statement would result in four NULLs: ‘SELECT NULL = 0, NULL < 0, NULL <> 0, NULL > 0′."
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "System variable in MySQL server that enables to configure the SQL mode is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) sql_mode",
            "b) sql_config",
            "c) sql_server",
            "d) sql_enable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Control-A moves the cursor to the beginning of the line. Ctrl-E moves the cursor to the end of the line. Control-D deletes the character under the cursor whereas Esc-a is not valid."
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "Which option enables multiple-statement execution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS",
            "b) CLIENT_STATEMENTS_MULTI",
            "c) MULTI_STATEMENTS_CLIENT",
            "d) MULTI_CLIENTS_STATEMENTS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘multiple-statement’ execution is not enabled by default, so the server must be told that it is intended to be used. There are two ways to tell the server to enable the execution."
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "3. Which of these is preferred when stored procedures are not being used?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\tCLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_set_server_option<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS",
            "b) mysql_set_server_option()",
            "c) any of the two",
            "d) neither of the two"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two ways to enable the multiple-statement execution. The first is to add the ‘CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS’ option in the flags argument to ‘mysql_real_connect()’ at connect time."
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "Which option executes all SQL statements in a SQL script irrespective of the number of errors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –ensure",
            "b) –force",
            "c) –violent",
            "d) –run"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the program does not use stored procedures anyone is suitable. If the program uses stored procedures and invokes a ‘CALL’ statement that returns a result set, the first method is better."
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "6. The number of attributes in the following SQL table is ______________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\t<span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> employee <span class=\"br0\">(</span>\n\t\temp_name <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\temp_id <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span>\n\t<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 30"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function ‘mysql_next_result()’ returns a status and initiates retrieval of the next set if more results are available. The status is zero if more results are available and -1 if not."
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "To see the table structure which command is issued?",
        "Options": [
            "a) VIEW tbl_name;",
            "b) SELECT TABLE tbl_name;",
            "c) SELECT tbl_name;",
            "d) DESCRIBE tbl_name;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If SQL queries in a file are run using mysql in batch mode, mysql either quits after the first error. If the –force option is specified all the queries are executed indiscriminately."
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "Which character is illegal in naming an unquoted identifier in SQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .",
            "b) _",
            "c) $",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The name of the table created is ’employee’. It has two attributes, namely, ’emp_name’ and ’emp_id’. The attributes are the columns in a table. emp_name is of type string and emp_id is of type integer."
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "Which statement is valid if ‘`sampledb`’ is a database and ‘`tbl`’ is a table in it?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT * FROM `sampledb.member`",
            "b) SELECT * FROM `sampledb`.`member`",
            "c) SELECT * FROM `member`.`sampledb`",
            "d) SELECT * FROM `member.sampledb`"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘DESCRIBE’ command is issued to see the structure of the table ‘tbl_name’. It shows the structure in the format: Field-Type-Null-Key-Default-Extra. The ‘VIEW’ and ‘SELECT’ commands are used to see the contents of the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "The default case sensitivity of the database and table names depends on ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Server SQL mode",
            "b) Operating system of machine",
            "c) Does not depend on anything",
            "d) SQL server"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An identifier is used to refer to a database or its elements. These elements can be entire tables or attributes. The names of these identifiers follow some set of rules, so they have a set of legal characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All statements cannot be prepared. The prepared-statement API applies to the statements: CREATE TABLE, DELETE, DO, INSERT, REPLACE, SELECT, SET, UPDATE and most variations of SHOW."
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "The maximum collations a character set can have is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) more than 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The binary protocol is more difficult to use because more setup is necessary for transmitting and receiving data values. The binary protocol does not support all statements, for example, ‘USE’."
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "A synonym for CHARACTER SET is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CSET",
            "b) CHSET",
            "c) CHARSET",
            "d) CHCSET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The binary protocol is more difficult to use because more setup is necessary for transmitting and receiving data values. The binary protocol does not support all statements like ‘USE’."
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "The statement used to select a default database is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) USE",
            "b) CREATE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) SCHEMA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The MySQL server allows simultaneous use of multiple character sets. A given character set is allowed to have one or more collations. It can be chosen according to the need of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "The statement that makes changes to the global attributes of the database is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHANGE",
            "b) ALTER",
            "c) ALTERNATE",
            "d) UPDATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘CHARACTER SET’ can be abbreviated into ‘CHARSET’ and can be used in the same contexts and statements where ‘CHARACTER SET’ is used. ‘charset’ is the server-supported character set."
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "The statement used to remove indexes on tables is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP INDEX",
            "b) DELETE INDEX",
            "c) REMOVE INDEX",
            "d) FLUSH INDEX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL has the facility to use various statements specifically at the database level. For selecting a default database, the keyword or clause used is the ‘USE’ statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "The statement used to change the table name is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) RENAME",
            "b) CHANGE",
            "c) CHANGENAME",
            "d) CHANGENM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘ALTER TABLE’ statement is used to make changes to global attributes of the database. This statement is followed by the name of the database, character set and collation."
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "What is the general term for information about databases and the objects in MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) datum",
            "b) info",
            "c) record",
            "d) metadata"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL provides statements to change the structure of tables. To add or remove the indexes on the existing database tables, the ‘CREATE INDEX’ and ‘DROP INDEX’ tables are used."
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "The shebang line is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) #!",
            "b) !#",
            "c) #$",
            "d) $#"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Perl scripts are text files, which can be ceated using any text editor. All Perl scripts generally begin with a #! (shebang) line. A script is a file containing a sequence of commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "The Perl DBI is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) database inheritance",
            "b) database integrity",
            "c) database interface",
            "d) database isolation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Perl scripts are text files, which can be ceated using any text editor. All Perl scripts generally begin with a #! (shebang) line. A script is a file containing a sequence of commands."
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "The default path to perl in Unix is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) /usr/bin/perl",
            "b) /usr/bin",
            "c) /usr/perl",
            "d) /usr/perl/bin"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Perl DBI is the Perl Database Interface. The work of the interface is to form a link between the application programming interface in C with all the other programming languages."
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "5. Which of these is not optional?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> select_list <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> table_list <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> row_constraint <span class=\"kw1\">GROUP</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> grouping_columns;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) select_list",
            "b) table_list",
            "c) row_constraint",
            "d) grouping_columns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All Perl scripts generally begin with a #! (shebang) line. A script is a file containing a sequence of commands. The Perl scripts are text files, which can be ceated using any text editor."
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "Which is the join in which all the rows from the right table appear in the output irrespective of the content of the other table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CARTESIAN JOIN",
            "b) CROSS JOIN",
            "c) INNER JOIN",
            "d) RIGHT JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Given above was a basic syntax of the SELECT statement. Everything in the syntax is optional except the ‘select_list’ option. All the others are free to be omitted, and will work fine."
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "What is the facility that allows nesting one select statement into another?",
        "Options": [
            "a) nesting",
            "b) binding",
            "c) subquerying",
            "d) encapsulating"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In a ‘RIGHT JOIN’, the output is produced for every row of the right table, even if it does not exist in the other table. This is the reason why it is called a ‘RIGHT JOIN’. ‘RIGHT JOIN’ and ‘LEFT JOIN’ are a kind of OUTER JOIN."
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "Which of these operators does not perform relative value comparisons?",
        "Options": [
            "a) =",
            "b) ==",
            "c) <=",
            "d) >="
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘subquerying’ support provided by MySQL is a capability that allows writing one ‘SELECT’ statement within parentheses and nesting within another. This allows logically selecting content from tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "To combine multiple retrievals, which keyword is used to write several SELECT statements between them?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COMBINE",
            "b) CONCAT",
            "c) JOIN",
            "d) UNION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operators =, <>, >, >=, <, and >= perform relative value comparisons in MySQL. ‘==’ is not a valid comparison operator in MySQL. Such operators are useful in filtering information from a table."
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "Issuing ‘SELECT’ on a MERGE table is like _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) UNION",
            "b) UNION ALL",
            "c) UNION DISTINCT",
            "d) JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘UNION’ operator is used for combining the results of various ‘SELECT’ queries into one. For example, ‘SELECT a FROM table1 UNION SELECT a FROM table2;’ produces the results from tables table1 concatenated with that of table2."
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "In Perl DBI, functions are called ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) functions",
            "b) procedures",
            "c) methods",
            "d) programs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the DBI API, functions are called and pointers to structures are used. The functions are called ‘methods’, pointers are called ‘references’, pointer variables are called ‘handles’."
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "Which variable is used as a handle to an open file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The variable named ‘$fh’ is a handle to an open file. ‘$h’ is a generic handle and the meaning depends on context. ‘$dbh’ is a handle to a database object. ‘$sth’ is a handle to a query object."
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "The variable that is a handle to a database object is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The variable named ‘$dbh’ is a handle to an open file. ‘$h’ is a generic handle and the meaning depends on context. ‘$dbh’ is a handle to a database object. ‘$sth’ is a handle to a query object."
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "Which variable returns code from operations that return true or false?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rc",
            "b) $rv",
            "c) $rows",
            "d) $ary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Perl Non-handle variable ‘$rc’ returns code from operations that return true or false. ‘$rv’ returns value from operations that return an integer. ‘$rows’ returns value from operations that return a row count."
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "The statement to remove indexes on tables is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DROP INDEX",
            "b) DELETE INDEX",
            "c) REMOVE INDEX",
            "d) FLUSH INDEX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL provides statements to change the structure of tables. To add or remove the indexes on the existing database tables, the ‘CREATE INDEX’ and ‘DROP INDEX’ tables are used."
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "What allows nesting one select statement into another?",
        "Options": [
            "a) nesting",
            "b) binding",
            "c) subquerying",
            "d) encapsulating"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘subquerying’ support provided by MySQL is a capability that allows writing one ‘SELECT’ statement within parentheses and nesting within another. This allows logically selecting content from tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "The operator that does not perform relative-value comparisons is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) =",
            "b) ==",
            "c) <=",
            "d) >="
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operators =, <>, >, >=, <, and <= perform relative value comparisons in MySQL. ‘==’ is not a valid comparison operator in MySQL. Such operators are useful in filtering information from a table."
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "The key declares that an index in one table is related to that in another is called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) primary",
            "b) secondary",
            "c) foreign",
            "d) cross"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, a foreign key is the one that facilitates index relations across tables. It declares that an index in one table is related to that in another and place constraints."
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "The generic handle whose meaning depends on context is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The variable named ‘$fh’ is a handle to an open file. ‘$h’ is a generic handle and the meaning depends on context. ‘$dbh’ is a handle to a database object. ‘$sth’ is a handle to a query object."
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "The non handle array representing a row of values is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rc",
            "b) $rv",
            "c) $rows",
            "d) $ary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Perl Non-handle variable ‘$ary’ is an array or list representing a row of values returned by a query. ‘$rc’ returns code from operations that return true or false. ‘$rv’ returns value from operations that return an integer. ‘$rows’ returns value from operations that return a row count."
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "The return value from operations returning a row count is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rc",
            "b) $rv",
            "c) $rows",
            "d) $ary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Perl Non-handle variable ‘$ary’ is an array or list representing a row of values returned by a query. ‘$rc’ returns code from operations that return true or false. ‘$rv’ returns value from operations that return an integer. ‘$rows’ returns value from operations that return a row count."
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "Which mode of search is the search string parsed into words and the search looks for rows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Boolean mode",
            "b) Natural language",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: While using the DBI API functions are called and pointers to structures are used. The functions are called “methods,” pointers are called “references,” pointer variables are called “handles”."
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "The indicator of presence/absence of a word in search is used in the mode ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural language",
            "b) Boolean mode",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a full text search capability is provided, which enables to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations. There are three kinds of full text searches."
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "The numbers that are prefixed with ‘0x’ are in base __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 32",
            "d) 64"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A full text search capability is provided in MySQL. It facilitates to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations. Boolean search is one of the three modes."
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "What is the escape sequence for carriage return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ‘\\c’",
            "b) ‘\\r’",
            "c) ‘\\b’",
            "d) ‘\\z’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are many numeric datatypes. They include integers and floating points. For example, 34, 12.3, -1.3E11. The numbers that are prefixed with ‘0x’ are in hexadecimal."
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": "What is the datatype for single precision floating point number?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLOAT",
            "b) DOUBLE",
            "c) INT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The scientific notation for real numbers is possible in MySQL. Approximate values are represented as floating point numbers in scientific notation. It consists of a mantissa and exponent."
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "RTF refers to ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rich Text Format",
            "b) Right Text Format",
            "c) Rich Text Function",
            "d) Right Text Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RTF (Rich Text Format) is a format developed by Microsoft that is understood by many word processors. MS-Word is one such program. Many others such as ‘OpenOffice’ understand it too."
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "The function returning an array of row values is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_array()’ returns an array of row values. ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "The function returning reference to hash of row values is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "fetchrow_hashref() returns reference to hash of row values keyed by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) table name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values, keyed by the column name. The function ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values."
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "The function returning reference to array of row values is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "What is the maximum non zero value for FLOAT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.402823466E+38",
            "b) 3.402823466E+37",
            "c) 3.402823466E+39",
            "d) 3.402823466E+35"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, each datatype has its own range. Data types give an idea of the kind of values and the ranges that a variable is allowed to store. The maximum non zero value for FLOAT is 3.402823466E+38."
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "What is the maximum non zero values for DOUBLE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ±1.7976931348623157E+307",
            "b) ±1.7976931348623157E+308",
            "c) ±1.7976931348623157E+306",
            "d) ±1.7976931348623157E+305"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, all the datatypes have their own ranges. Data types give an idea of the kind of values and the ranges that a variable is allowed to store. The maximum non zero value for DOUBLE is ±1.7976931348623157E+308."
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "Illegal values converted to the appropriate ‘zero’ value for ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric",
            "b) String",
            "c) ENUM",
            "d) TIME"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are different ways to handle the illegal values for different datatypes for default. For date or time columns, illegal values are converted to the appropriate “zero” value for the type."
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "The column attribute provides unique numbers for identification is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) AUTO_INCREMENT",
            "b) UNSIGNED",
            "c) IDENTIFY",
            "d) DESCRIBE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the mechanism for providing unique numbers is through the AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute. It enables the generation of sequential numbers automatically. This facilitates identification."
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "The module that links DBI to the web is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CGI.pn",
            "b) CGI.pem",
            "c) CGI.pm",
            "d) CGI.po"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The CGI.pm module is used to write scripts that use the ‘Common Gateway Interface’ protocol. It defines how a web server communicates with other programs. It provides an easy link."
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "CGI stands for ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Computer Gateway Interface",
            "b) Common Gateway Interface",
            "c) Computer Generated Interface",
            "d) Common Generated Interface"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘CGI.pm’ module is so called because it helps write scripts that use the ‘Common Gateway Interface’ protocol which defines how a web server communicates with other programs."
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "Which line is written at the top of the script to write a Perl script using CGI.pm?",
        "Options": [
            "a) use this CGI",
            "b) put CGI",
            "c) use CGI",
            "d) include CGI"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In order to write a Perl script that uses the ‘CGI.pm’ module, a ‘use CGI’ statement is included near the beginning of the script that imports the function names of the module."
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "By default, the AUTO_INCREMENT sequences begin at __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘CGI.pm’ supports an object oriented style of use which allows to invoke its functions without importing the names. To do this, a use statement is included and a CGI object is created."
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "What does the expression ’12 DIV 5′ evaluate to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.4",
            "b) 2",
            "c) error",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, there can only be one column per table with the AUTO_INCREMENT attribute. It should also have an integer data type. The AUTO_INCREMENT is also allowed for floating point types."
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "What does ‘abc’ || ‘xyz’ result in if the PIPES_AS_CONCAT is disabled?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) error",
            "d) -1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute provides unique numbers for column identification. AUTO_INCREMENT sequences normally begin at 1 and increase monotonically like 1, 2, 3, and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "The AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute is best used with ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLOAT",
            "b) INT",
            "c) CHARACTER",
            "d) DOUBLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘DIV’ operator in MySQL is used to perform the integer divisions. The operator ‘/’ performs the quotient of the operands. If result exceeds the 64-bit range, unpredicted results are shown."
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "The datatype best suited to store currency values is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INT",
            "b) FLOAT",
            "c) DOUBLE",
            "d) DECIMAL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When the SQL mode PIPES_AS_CONCAT is disabled, the SQL standard ‘||’ operation for string concatenation is not valid in MySQL. Both operands are converted to zero. So the result is zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "The output from PHP is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) statically generated",
            "b) dynamically generated",
            "c) not generated",
            "d) no output"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The elementary operation of PHP is interpreting a script in order to produce a web page. This is sent to a client. A PHP script generally contains a mix of HTML and executable code."
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "PHP variables are preceded by __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) _",
            "b) @",
            "c) $",
            "d) &"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As soon as the PHP interpreter comes across a special opening tag it switches from ‘text copy’ mode to ‘PHP code’ mode. It starts interpreting the file as PHP code to be executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "The datatype best suited to store currency values is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INT",
            "b) FLOAT",
            "c) DOUBLE",
            "d) DECIMAL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The interpreter switches between code mode back and text mode when it sees another special tag which signals the end of the code. This enables the mix of static text with dynamically generated results."
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "What returns a result to the client?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored functions",
            "b) Stored procedures",
            "c) Triggers",
            "d) Events"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: All the PHP scripts that use variables have variable names preceded by the dollar sign (‘$’). The variables are signified by this identifier, irrespective of the value it stores."
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "What is defined to execute when the table is modified only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored functions",
            "b) Stored procedures",
            "c) Triggers",
            "d) Events"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Currency is a numeric information. For monetary calculations, FLOAT and DOUBLE are subject to rounding error and may not be suitable. A DECIMAL(M, 2) type is best suited for it."
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to produce a stored function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PRODUCE FUNCTION",
            "b) CREATE FUNCTION",
            "c) PRODUCE PROCEDURE",
            "d) CREATE PROCEDURE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Stored functions return a result from a calculation and can be used in expressions. Stored procedures do not return a result directly but can be used to perform general computations."
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "The number of values that can be returned from a given stored function is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, triggers are associated with a table. They are defined to execute when the table is modified via INSERT, DELETE or UPDATE statements. MySQL supports objects to be stored on server side."
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "The statement used to create a trigger is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE TRIGGER",
            "b) CREATE TRIGGERS",
            "c) PRODUCE TRIGGER",
            "d) PRODUCE TRIGGERS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘CREATE FUNCTION’ statement is used to create a stored function in MySQL. The ‘CREATE PROCEDURE’ statement is used to create a stored procedure instead, from which values are not returned. "
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "In PHP, if $a represents an array with numeric indices, how is the first element accessed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $a[1] ",
            "b) $a[0] ",
            "c) $a.1",
            "d) $a.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If $a represents an array with numeric indices, its elements are accessed as $x[0], $x[1], and so on. In general terms, each element at the position i is accessed and used as $a[i – 1]."
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "In PHP, which operator is used to access property of an object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .",
            "b) *",
            "c) ->",
            "d) @"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The PHP arrays can even have both numeric and associative elements. For example, $x[1] and $x[“large”] can both be the elements of the same array. $x can be an object, whose elements are accessed by the arrow ‘->’ operated."
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "DBI scripts are located in the directory ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) cgi-inc",
            "b) cgi-bin",
            "c) cgi-usr",
            "d) cgi-perl"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If $a represents an object, the properties it has can be accessed as $a->property-name. For instance, $a->white, $a->black, $a->blue, $a->red can be the properties of $a and accessed in this way."
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "A stored program associated with a schedule is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trigger",
            "b) Event",
            "c) Stored function",
            "d) Stored procedure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The PHP scripts are different from DBI scripts since PHP scripts are located within the web server document tree while DBI scripts are located in a cgi-bin directory located outside of document tree."
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "The line used to turn on the event scheduler is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) event_scheduler = ON",
            "b) eventscheduler = ON",
            "c) event_scheduler_ON",
            "d) events_scheduler_ON"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DBI scripts are located in a cgi-bin directory located outside of document tree. The PHP scripts are different from DBI scripts since PHP scripts are located within the web server document tree."
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "What is the creation of a stored program similar to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trigger",
            "b) Event",
            "c) View",
            "d) Table"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL version 5.1.6 and above has an event scheduler. It enables to perform time activated database operations. An event is a stored program that is associated with a schedule."
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "When the security context enables carefully written stored programs to be set up that provide controlled access to tables for users, it is called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) bad",
            "b) good",
            "c) illegal",
            "d) fare"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The line ‘event_scheduler = ON’ is put in the option file that the server reads. The event scheduler does not run by default. It must be turned on if events are to used in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "What is the maximum number of indexes on MyISAM table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) more than 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When a stored program is created, an object is created that is to be executed later. This also the case when a view is defined: It sets up a SELECT statement intended for later invocation."
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "The hub of a MySQL installation is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqla",
            "b) mysqlb",
            "c) mysqlc",
            "d) mysqld"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The server, mysqld, is the hub of a MySQL installation; it performs all manipulation of databases and tables. On Unix, several related scripts are available to assist in server startup."
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘mysqlcheck’ and ‘mysqlisamchk’ are the programs that perform table checking, analysis, optimization and repairs when tables become damaged. ‘mysqlcheck’ works with MyISAM tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "The tool for copying databases is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql",
            "b) mysqlcheck",
            "c) mysqlhotcopy",
            "d) mysqlisamchk"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The MySQL data directory is the place where the server stores its databases and status files. It is crucial to understand that all the structures and contents of the data directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "Which statement is used to check how MySQL would execute a SELECT query?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TELL",
            "b) SHOW",
            "c) DISPLAY",
            "d) EXPLAIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘mysqldump’ and ‘mysqlhotcopy’ are the tools or programs that are used for performing the backing up of the databases and copying databases from one server to the other server(s)."
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "What is used to perform an analysis of key values by the server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANALYZE KEYS",
            "b) ANALYZE TABLE",
            "c) PERFORM ANALYSIS",
            "d) PERFORM TABLE ANALYSIS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, by issuing an EXPLAIN statement MySQL displays some information about how it would execute a SELECT query without actually executing it. It is prefixed with the query."
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "The function used to convert an int to string is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INET_ATON()",
            "b) INET_NTOA()",
            "c) INET_ITOS()",
            "d) INET_STOI()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the MyISAM and InnoDB tables, the server can be told to perform an analysis of key values by issuing the ANALYZE TABLE statement. It helps in knowing about query optimization."
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "The function used to convert a string to an int is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INET_ATON()",
            "b) INET_NTOA()",
            "c) INET_ITOS()",
            "d) INET_STOI()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the function used to convert an integer to a string is INET_NTOA(). On the other hand, the function INET_ATON() converts a string to the corresponding integer value."
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) LOAD DATA",
            "b) INSERT",
            "c) Same",
            "d) Indeterminate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the function used to convert a string to an integer is INET_ATON(). On the other hand, the function INET_NTOA() converts a string to the corresponding integer value."
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "Without LOCAL, LOAD DATA is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) less efficient",
            "b) more efficient",
            "c) same speed",
            "d) arbitrary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘LOAD DATA’ in all forms is more efficient than the ‘INSERT’ because it loads rows in bulk. The server first parses then interprets only one statement instead of many."
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "The log in which data changes received from a replication master server are written are ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) general query log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) relay log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The MySQL server is highly configurable. Some of the operational characteristics that you can control include which storage engines the server supports, the default character set, and its default time zone."
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "Which of these is the metadata log?",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) ddl log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) relay log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is useful to run multiple servers on the same machine under certain circumstances. A new MySQL release can also be tested while leaving the current production server in place."
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "The max_binlog_cache_size system variable has default size ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 GB",
            "b) 2 GB",
            "c) 4 GB",
            "d) 8 GB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Relay Log has the data changes received from a replication master server written in it. The problems encountered during the starting, running or stopping of ‘mysqld’ are written in error log."
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Options": [
            "a) writes",
            "b) reads",
            "c) same priority",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The DDL log is also known as the metadata log. The metadata operations performed by the DDL statements. The Relay Log has the data changes received from a replication master server written in it."
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The max_binlog_cache_size system variable can be used to restrict the total size used to cache a multiple-statement transaction. If transaction is larger than this it fails and rolls back."
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) memory",
            "b) disk",
            "c) same speed",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A client performing an operation that modifies a table is a writer and the client that performs a retrieval from the table is a reader. The writes have higher priority than reads."
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "The system variable controls the size of the table cache _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) table_cache",
            "b) cache_table",
            "c) open_cache",
            "d) cache_open"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The MyISAM, MERGE and the MEMORY storage engines implement the default scheduling policy of MySQL with the help of the table locks. Whenever a client accesses a table a lock for it must be acquired first."
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "Which of these exports table definitions and contents?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqladmin",
            "c) mysqlimport",
            "d) mysqlexport"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the administrators have more privileges since they have more control of the MySQL server or the machine on which it runs. Accessing data in memory is faster than from disk."
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "MySQL uses security based on ACL which stands for ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Access Control Language",
            "b) Access Control Lists",
            "c) Automatic Control Lists",
            "d) Automatic Control Language"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL uses security based on Access Control Lists (ACLs) for all connections, queries and other operations that users can attempt to perform. There is support for SSL encrypted connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "The context in which the privilege ‘CREATE TABLESPACE’ applies is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Server administration",
            "b) Tables",
            "c) Stored routines",
            "d) Views"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: On Unix the mysql client writes a record of the executed statements to a history file. By default this file is named as ‘.mysql_history’. It is created in the home directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the MySQL privilege system, a password applies globally to an account. A password cannot be explicitly associated with a specific object such as a database, table, or routine."
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "The language that is the core for APIs and communication in MySQL is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) C++",
            "c) Python",
            "d) Ruby"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The column name associated with the privilege ‘CREATE TABLESPACE’ is ‘Create_tablespace_priv’. The context in which this privilege is being used is the server administration."
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "The most general purpose language is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) C",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) Python",
            "d) PHP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The client library provides the means through which the MySQL bindings for other languages can be built on top of the C API. This type of interface exists for Perl, PHP, Python and others."
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "The language in which image processing is least simple is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) PHP",
            "b) Perl",
            "c) Python",
            "d) C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to provide application development, MySQL provides a client library written in the C programming language. It enables access to MySQL databases from a C program."
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "The option necessary to compile a C program havin math functions is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -lm",
            "b) -ln",
            "c) -lp",
            "d) -lq"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: C is a general purpose language, so in principle, it can be used for anything. C tends to be used more often for standalone programs rather than for Web programming in practice."
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "What is the option for specifying the executable name while compiling with gcc?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -e",
            "b) -o",
            "c) -a",
            "d) -b"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It is not as easy to perform text processing and memory management in C than it is in languages like Perl and PHP. These capabilities tend to be heavily used in web applications."
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "For InnoDB tables in mysqldump an online backup that takes no locks on tables can be performed by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –multiple-transaction",
            "b) –single-transaction",
            "c) –double-transaction",
            "d) –no-transaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For InnoDB tables it is possible to perform an online backup that takes no locks on tables using the option ‘–single-transaction’ to ‘mysqldump’. The ‘mysqldump’ can make backups."
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "To reload a delimited text data file use ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqld",
            "c) mysqlimport",
            "d) mysqlnaive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A way to create text data files along with files containing ‘CREATE TABLE’ statements for the backed up tables is to use ‘mysqldump’ with –tab. To reload a delimited text data file ‘mysqlimport’ is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "SBR replication is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Statement based",
            "b) Row based",
            "c) Column based",
            "d) Table based"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Replication enables data from one MySQL database server (the master) to be copied to one or more MySQL database servers (the slaves). Replication is asynchronous by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "The library file that contains various portability macros and definitions is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two main kinds of replication format: Statement Based Replication (SBR) replicates entire SQL statements and Row Based Replication (RBR) replicates only the changed rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "The header that should be included first is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘my_sys.h’ header file contains a variety of portability macros and definitions required for structures and functions. These structures and functions are used by the client library."
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following use ‘NULL’ to indicate failure?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_init<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_connect<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The file ‘my_global.h’ takes care of including several other header files that are likely to be generally useful, like ‘stdio.h’. It also includes Windows compatibility information."
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "8. Which of the following does not return a value?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_close<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_init<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_connect</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Both of the client library routines named ‘mysql_init()’ and ‘mysql_real_connect()’ return a pointer to the connection handler in order to indicate success and NULL to indicate failure."
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "What is the general statement-issuing routine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_real_query()",
            "b) mysql_query_real()",
            "c) mysql_image_query()",
            "d) mysql_query_image()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is not necessary that every Application Programming Interface call would return a value. For example, the client routine named ‘mysql_close()’ returns void, that is, it does not return a value."
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "10. The most restrictive among the following is ______________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_query<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_query<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_query()",
            "b) mysql_real_query()",
            "c) same",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The general statement-issuing routine is mysql_real_query(). The statement is provided as a counted string (a string plus a length). The length of the statement string must be kept track of."
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "The option that specifies the data directory location at server startup is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –data",
            "b) –data_dir",
            "c) –data-dir",
            "d) –datadir"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: At the server startup the data directory location is specified by using a ‘–datadir=dir_name’ option. It is helpful for naming a location other than the compiled in default. "
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "The datadir variable value can be seen using ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW VARIABLES",
            "b) DISP VARIABLES",
            "c) CONNECT VARIABLES",
            "d) SHOW VARIABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The data directory location is checked by the ‘datadir’ variable. It can be obtained using a ‘SHOW VARIABLES’ statement or a ‘mysqladmin’ variables command, like: SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘datadir’. "
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "Which data directory subdirectory provides the information used to inspect the internal execution of the server at runtime.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql",
            "b) performance_schema",
            "c) sys",
            "d) nbdinfo"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘performance_schema’ directory corresponds to the Performance Schema. It provides information used to inspect the internal execution of the server at runtime. The ‘sys’ directory maps to ‘nbdinfo’. "
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "Which data directory subdirectory corresponds to the nbdinfo database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql",
            "b) performance_schema",
            "c) sys",
            "d) nbdinfo"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The sys directory corresponds to the sys schema. It provides a set of objects to interpreting Performance Schema information. The ‘performance_schema’ directory corresponds to the Performance Schema. "
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "Encrypted connections can be established using ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) exec_stmt_ssl",
            "b) exec_ssl_stmt",
            "c) exec_stmnt_ssl",
            "d) exec_ssl_stmnt"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the ‘exec_stmt_ssl’ to work properly, MySQL must have been built with SSL support, and the server must be started with the proper options that identify its certificate and key files. "
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "What is exec_stmt_ssl written in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C++",
            "b) C",
            "c) Python",
            "d) Perl"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘sampdb’ distribution contains a source file named ‘exec_stmt_ssl.c’ from which the client program ‘exec_stmt_ssl’ can be built. There is a procedure to build this file. "
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "What is the embedded server library containing the MySQL server linkable into applications?",
        "Options": [
            "a) libmysqla",
            "b) libmysqlb",
            "c) libmysqlc",
            "d) libmysqld"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MySQL includes an embedded server library, libmysqld, containing the MySQL server in a way that can be linked into applications. This enables the production of MySQL-based standalone applications. "
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "What is the embedded server library when building from source enabled by?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –with-embedded-server",
            "b) –with-server-embedded",
            "c) –with-embedded-library",
            "d) –with-library-embedded"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: While building from the source, the embedded server library is enabled by using the option ‘–with-embedded-server’ while running ‘configure’. This applies equally to MySQL 5.0 and 5.1. "
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "In the database directory of the database each view and trigger object is associated with how many files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, each database has a database directory that is located under the data directory. The tables, views and triggers within a database correspond to files in the database directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "What is the maximum number of characters allowed for a database name to have?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16",
            "b) 32",
            "c) 64",
            "d) 128"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Each view and trigger object is associated with one file in the database directory of the database containing that object. A view consists of a .frm file that contains the view definition."
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "The data directory subdirectory that corresponds to the nbdinfo database is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql",
            "b) performance_schema",
            "c) sys",
            "d) nbdinfo"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MySQL allows the database names and the table names to be a maximum of 64 characters long. The length of these names is also bound by the length allowed by the operating system on the machine."
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "5. Which of these is preferred when stored procedures are not being used?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_set_server_option<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS",
            "b) mysql_set_server_option()",
            "c) any of the two",
            "d) neither of the two"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The sys directory corresponds to the sys schema. It provides a set of objects to interpret Performance Schema information. The ‘performance_schema’ directory corresponds to the Performance Schema."
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "The option that executes all SQL statements in a SQL script irrespective of the number of errors is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –ensure",
            "b) –force",
            "c) –violent",
            "d) –run"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the program does not use stored procedures anyone is suitable. If the program uses stored procedures and invokes a ‘CALL’ statement that returns a result set, the first method is better."
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "What is the synonym for CHARACTER SET?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CSET",
            "b) CHSET",
            "c) CHARSET",
            "d) CHCSET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function ‘mysql_next_result()’ returns a status and initiates retrieval of the next set if more results are available. The status is zero if more results are available and -1 if not."
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "What is the statement used to select a default database?",
        "Options": [
            "a) USE",
            "b) CREATE",
            "c) DROP",
            "d) SCHEMA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If SQL queries in a file are run using mysql in batch mode, mysql either quits after the first error. If the –force option is specified all the queries are executed indiscriminately."
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "Symlink is an applicable relocation method for ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) entire data directory",
            "b) individual database tables",
            "c) server PID file",
            "d) log files"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Symlink is an applicable relocation method for the individual database tables. However, the startup option is better suited relocation method for server PID file and the log files."
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "For which of these is the startup option best suited?",
        "Options": [
            "a) entire data directory",
            "b) individual database tables",
            "c) server PID file",
            "d) individual database directories"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The startup option is better suited relocation method for server PID file and the log files, while symlink is an applicable relocation method for the individual database tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "When relocating an individual table, the table to be relocated should be ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) TRANSACTION",
            "d) ENGINE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The server always looks for the database directories in the data directory. The only way to relocate a database is by the symlink method. The server should be stopped if running."
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "What is the special database that always exists after setting up MySQL on a computer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sampdb",
            "b) mysql",
            "c) information_schema",
            "d) readme_db"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The relocation of an individual table is supported only under certain limited circumstances. When relocating an individual table, the table to be relocated should be a MyISAM table."
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "6. What is InnoDB in the following MySQL code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> student <span class=\"br0\">(</span>\n\t\tname <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\tstudent_id <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\t<span class=\"kw1\">PRIMARY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">KEY</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>student_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n\t<span class=\"br0\">)</span> ENGINE <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> InnoDB;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) database name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) reference engine",
            "d) storage engine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: After installation of MySQL, ‘information_schema’ is the special database that always exists. ‘mysql’ can be seen depending on access rights. It holds the grant tables. ‘sampdb’ and ‘readme_db’ do not exist by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "7. What is the table name in the following SQL code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">INSERT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">INTO</span> student <span class=\"kw1\">VALUES</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'Kyle'</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">'M'</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) student",
            "b) VALUES",
            "c) Kyle",
            "d) M"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘InnoDB’ is the name of the ‘storage engine’ for the above table. The ‘ENGINE’ clause is used to specify the name of the storage engine that MySQL should use to handle the table being created. MySQL has several storage engines with its own properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "In which file are the statements entered in ‘mysql’ saved?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .mysql_queries",
            "b) .queries",
            "c) .mysql_history",
            "d) .history"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘INSERT INTO’ clause here inserts a row in the table named ‘student’. The table has three fields. The first field or attribute value in the row/tuple is ‘Kyle’. The second attribute value is ‘M’ and the last attribute is set to NULL."
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "Which command is used to make a script file ‘run_me.sh’ executable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) chmod +e run_me.sh",
            "b) chmod +a run_me.sh",
            "c) chmod +y run_me.sh",
            "d) chmod +x run_me.sh"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Statements entered in ‘mysql’ are stored in the file named ‘.mysql_history’. This file is located in the home directory itself. The SQL statements can be directly pasted into this file."
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "The superuser account of the grant tables in the mysql database is called ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) super",
            "b) prime",
            "c) root",
            "d) leaf"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The root accounts are superuser accounts intended for administrative purposes. The root accounts have the privileges and to delete all the databases and shutting down the server."
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "Which script initializes the data directory during installation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_install_db",
            "b) mysql_install_dbm",
            "c) mysql_init_db",
            "d) mysql_init_dbm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The data directory is initialized during the installation by ‘mysql_install_db’. If MySQL is installed on Linux from RPM packages then ‘mysql_install_db’ is run automatically."
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": "Anonymous accounts have user name ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) root",
            "b) blank",
            "c) super",
            "d) prime"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Anonymous accounts have user name left blank. The main benefit of removing the anonymous user accounts is it significantly simplifies the task of setting up non-anonymous accounts."
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "What does the default case sensitivity of database and table names depend on?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SQL server",
            "b) Server SQL mode",
            "c) Operating system of machine",
            "d) Does not depend on anything"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the ‘REVOKE’ and ‘DROP USER’ statements, the server automatically re-reads the grant tables and no FLUSH PRIVILEGES statements are needed. Hence the grant tables are re-read."
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "The case sensitive among these is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored function name",
            "b) Stored procedure name",
            "c) Trigger name",
            "d) Event name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The default case sensitivity imposes a dependency on the operating system of the machine on which the MySQL server is running. Windows does not treat database and table names as case sensitive unlike Unix."
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "The variable used to set table alias names as non case sensitive is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) lower_case_table_names",
            "b) lower_case_all",
            "c) lower_case_alias",
            "d) lower_case_aliases"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The stored functions and stored procedure names in MySQL are not case sensitive. Event names are also not case sensitive. Unlike the standard SQL, the trigger names in MySQL is case sensitive."
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "The clause that can be used to sort string values according to a specific collation is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SORT",
            "b) GROUP",
            "c) FILTER",
            "d) COLLATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, by default the alias names are case sensitive. An alias can hence be specified in any letter case, upper, lower or mixed. If the variable ‘lower_case_table_names’ is non zero, the alias names of tables are not case sensitive. "
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "The statement used to find out which character sets are available is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW CHARACTER SET",
            "b) SHOW COLLATION",
            "c) SHOW CHARACTER SETS",
            "d) SHOW COLLATIONS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘COLLATE’ operator can be used to sort the string values according to a specific collation. For example, ‘SELECT col FROM tbl ORDER BY col COLLATE latin1_swedish_ci’ sorts by Swedish collation. "
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "10. The collations this statement lists are ______________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SHOW</span> COLLATION <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> <span class=\"st0\">'utf8%'</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) names beginning with utf8",
            "b) names ending with utf8",
            "c) names containing utf8% anywhere",
            "d) names ending in utf8%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is simple to determine the character sets and collations that are available in MySQL. ‘SHOW CHARACTER SET’ shows the character sets while ‘SHOW COLLATION’ shows the collations."
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "The error log file has a suffix ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) .err",
            "b) .er",
            "c) .error",
            "d) .log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Windows, by default, the error log is located in the ‘C:\\Program Files\\MySQL\\MySQL Server 5.7\\data’ directory. It is the file with a suffix of .err, or may be specified by passing in the ‘–log-error’ option."
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "The option which finds the startup options supported by the server through mysqld is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –verbose",
            "b) –vertex",
            "c) –startup",
            "d) –shutdown"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement ‘mysqld –verbose –help’ is used for finding out all the startup options that are supported by the server. It is possible to run the server manually or automatically."
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "Server startup can also be done by the ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) option file",
            "b) log file",
            "c) error file",
            "d) system file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The options are listed in an option file. Options specified in this way are given one per line. Only the long option form can be used and it is written without the leading dashes."
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "The keyword used to create a database is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) SET",
            "c) SETUP",
            "d) LINK"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to select a database as the default database for the MySQL server using the ‘USE’ statement, some access privilege for the database needs to be granted or attained."
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "Which file is created by the server to store the database attributes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) db.otp",
            "b) dp.zip",
            "c) db.opt",
            "d) db.cls"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement ‘CREATE DATABASE database_name;’ is used to create a database with the name ‘database_name’. A database qualifier should be used to specify the full name of the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "What is the default storage engine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) EXAMPLE",
            "b) ARCHIVE",
            "c) MyISAM",
            "d) NDB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Whenever a database is created in MySQL, the MySQL server creates a directory with the same name as the database. It creates the file db.opt to store the attributes."
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "The name of the format file for a table named my_tbl is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_tbl.fmt",
            "b) my_tbl.frm",
            "c) my_tbl.fmr",
            "d) my_tbl.ftm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MySQL comes with multiple storage engines. The default storage engine used is ‘MyISAM’. ‘EXAMPLE’ is the stub storage engine, NDB is the storage engine for MySQL Cluster."
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "The server listens on a network port for TCP/IP connections unless started with the option ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –networking",
            "b) –skip-networking",
            "c) –skip-networks",
            "d) –quit-networking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: On all the platforms the server listens on a network port for the TCP/IP connections, unless and until it is started with the –skip-networking option. The default port number is 3306."
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "Which option is used to specify to the server the IP number of the server host on which the server should listen?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –verbose",
            "b) –bind-address",
            "c) –startup",
            "d) –shutdown"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If the server host has more than one IP number, the server can be specified the one that it should use when listening for connections by starting it with a ‘–bind-address’ option."
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "The option used to specify the socket file pathname is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –socket",
            "b) –pathtosocket",
            "c) –path_socket",
            "d) –socket_pathfile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The default socket file usually is ‘/tmp/mysql.sock’. Operating system distributions that include MySQL often use a different location. The –socket option is used to specify explicitly."
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "The disk data that the FILES table in INFORMATION_SCHEMA stores is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) NDB",
            "b) NBD",
            "c) NBK",
            "d) NCD"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL supports shared memory connections on Windows. This capability is disabled by default. In order to enable it, the server is started with the ‘–shared-memory’ option."
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "In which table of INFORMATION_SCHEMA is the information about table index characteristics stored?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FILES",
            "b) STATISTICS",
            "c) SCHEMATA",
            "d) VIEWS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is another way to access information about the databases and their objects (metadata). It is based on the ‘SQL standard’, although some content is MySQL-specific."
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "What is the join where all possible row combinations are produced?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INNER JOIN",
            "b) OUTER",
            "c) NATURAL",
            "d) CARTESIAN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is a method to access information about the databases and its objects known as metadata. It has various tables that can be viewed with ‘SHOW’ statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "What is the clause that filters JOIN results called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) SORT",
            "c) GROUP",
            "d) GROUP BY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘STATISTICS’ table in the ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ stores information about the table index characteristics. ‘INFORMATION_SCHEMA’ is responsible for storing database metadata."
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "What are CROSS JOIN and JOIN are similar to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INNER JOIN",
            "b) NATURAL JOIN",
            "c) OUTER JOIN",
            "d) CARTESIAN JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In ‘cartesian product’, each row of each table is combined with each row in every other table to produce all possible combinations. This produces a very large number of rows since the number is the product of rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "The grant table that stores users who can connect to the server and their global privileges are ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) user",
            "b) db",
            "c) tables_priv",
            "d) procs_priv"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The grant table ‘user’ stores the users who can connect to the server and their global privileges. ‘db’ has the database privileges records. ‘tables_priv’ has table privileges."
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "The stored-routine privileges are contained in ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) user",
            "b) db",
            "c) tables_priv",
            "d) procs_priv"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘procs_priv’ stores stored-routine privileges. The grant table ‘user’ stores the users who can connect to the server and their global privileges. ‘db’ has the database privileges records."
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "The statement used to obtain access privileges to an account is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) OBTAIN",
            "b) GET",
            "c) GRANT",
            "d) NEED"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the named account exists, ‘GRANT’ modifies its privileges. If the account does not exist, ‘GRANT’ creates it with the given privileges. It is used to obtain access privileges."
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "The operators used when a subquery returns multiple rows to be evaluated in comparison to the outer query are _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) IN and NOT IN",
            "b) EXISTS and NOT EXISTS",
            "c) OUTER JOIN and INNER JOIN",
            "d) LEFT JOIN and RIGHT JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL supports shared memory connections on Windows. This capability is disabled by default. In order to enable it, the server is started with the ‘–shared-memory’ option."
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "The ALL subquery performs the operation _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) row",
            "b) column",
            "c) table",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The usage of aggregates inside ‘WHERE’ clauses is not allowed. For example, the following statement will not work: ‘SELECT * FROM my_table WHERE attribute_name = MAX(attribute_name)’, because the MAX value is not known yet. "
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "The keyword used with UNION that does not retain duplicate rows is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALL",
            "b) NARROW",
            "c) STRICT",
            "d) DISTINCT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When there is a need to evaluate multiple rows in comparison to the outer query, the ‘IN’ and ‘NOT IN’ operators are used. They are used for testing whether a comparison value is present in a set of values."
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "The keyword used with UNION that retains duplicate rows is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALL",
            "b) NARROW",
            "c) STRICT",
            "d) DISTINCT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operators ‘ALL’ and ‘ANY’ are used to perform operations on columns. They are used in conjunction with a comparison operator in order to test the result of a column subquery."
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "The log that contains a record of server startups and shutdowns and the messages about exceptional conditions is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) general query",
            "c) slow query log",
            "d) binary log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The error log contains a record of server startups and shutdowns and the messages about problems or exceptional conditions. If the server fails to start this log provides the help."
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "The log that identifies statements that may be in need of being rewritten for better performance is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) general query",
            "c) slow query log",
            "d) binary log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The purpose of the slow-query log is to help the identification of statements that may be in need of being rewritten for better performance. This helps in query optimizations."
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "The default value in seconds in the system variable ‘long_query_time’ is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 20",
            "d) 60"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The server maintains a ‘long_query_time’ system variable that defines slow queries (10 seconds by default). If a query takes more than these seconds of real time it is considered slow."
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "The logging option to enable binary log index file is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –log-bin-index",
            "b) –bin-log-index",
            "c) –index-log-bin",
            "d) –index-bin-log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘–log-bin-index’ is the logging option that enables the binary log index file. ‘–log-error’ enables the error log file. Similarly, –log enables the general log file."
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "The operators that are used when a subquery returns multiple rows to be evaluated in comparison to the outer query are _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) IN and NOT IN",
            "b) EXISTS and NOT EXISTS",
            "c) OUTER JOIN and INNER JOIN",
            "d) LEFT JOIN and RIGHT JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The usage of aggregates inside ‘WHERE’ clauses is not allowed. For example, the following statement will not work: ‘SELECT * FROM my_table WHERE attribute_name = MAX(attribute_name)’, because the MAX value is not known yet. "
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "The ALL subquery performs operations on _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) row",
            "b) column",
            "c) table",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When there is a need to evaluate multiple rows in comparison to the outer query, the ‘IN’ and ‘NOT IN’ operators are used. They are used for testing whether a comparison value is present in a set of values."
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "What is the kind of delete when deletion of an employee from the table also deletes that employee from another table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) transparent",
            "b) concrete",
            "c) elaborate",
            "d) cascaded"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operators ‘ALL’ and ‘ANY’ are used to perform operations on columns. They are used in conjunction with a comparison operator in order to test the result of a column subquery."
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "The storage engine in MySQL that provides foreign key support is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRANSACTION",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) MyISAM",
            "d) MEMORY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, a cascaded delete and update are possible where records can be deleted from multiple tables. These tables are related with the help of foreign keys. Foreign keys make table updates flexible."
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "What is the property of InnoDB that enforces foreign key relationships stay intact?",
        "Options": [
            "a) atomicity",
            "b) durability",
            "c) consistency",
            "d) referential integrity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, there are a list of storage engines to choose from. Each storage engine provides its own set of facilities. The foreign key facilities are provided by the InnoDB storage engine."
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "Which mode exists at both global level and session-specific level?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sql_mode",
            "b) key_buffer_size",
            "c) server_mode",
            "d) query_mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The system variable ‘sql_mode’ that indicates the default SQL mode is an example of a variable that exists at both the global and session levels. This mode affects several aspects of SQL statement processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "Which system variable determines the number of rows from INSERT DELAYED statements that can be queued per table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fast_queue_size",
            "b) general_queue_size",
            "c) slow_queue_size",
            "d) delayed_queue_size"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The system variable ‘delayed_queue_size’ determines the number of rows from INSERT DELAYED statements that can be queued per table (for the storage engines that support DELAYED inserts)."
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "The largest value to which the variable ‘max_allowed_packet’ can be set is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1GB",
            "b) 2GB",
            "c) 4GB",
            "d) 8GB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘max_allowed_packet’ stores the maximum size to which the buffer used for client communications can grow. The largest value to which ‘max_allowed_packet’ variable can be set is 1GB."
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "Increasing the value of which system variable enables mysqld to keep more tables open simultaneously?",
        "Options": [
            "a) table_cache",
            "b) max_connect",
            "c) delayed_queue_size",
            "d) max_allowed_packet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘table_cache’ stores the size of the table cache. Increasing the value enables ‘mysqld’ to keep more tables open simultaneously by reducing the number of files open and close operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Question": "The keyword used with UNION that retains duplicate rows is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALL",
            "b) NARROW",
            "c) STRICT",
            "d) DISTINCT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The keyword ‘ALL’ used along with ‘UNION’ is not synonymous with just the ‘UNION’ statement. It produces the duplicate rows, if they exist, from the combination of the two tables in the SELECT query."
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "The search mode that uses natural language search as a subroutine is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural language",
            "b) Boolean mode",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The query expansion search occurs in two phases. The natural language search is applied in the first phase. Query expansion search is one of the three modes of fulltext searching."
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "For what can the FULLTEXT indexes be created for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) MEMORY",
            "d) TRANSITION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Full-text searches are based on the FULLTEXT indexes. They can be created for MyISAM tables only. In MySQL, a full text search enables to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "For which of these storage engines are configuration options always built?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Falcon",
            "b) FEDERATED",
            "c) InnoDB",
            "d) MyISAM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The configuration options for the storage engine ‘MyISAM’ are always built. The runtime options for MyISAM are also always enabled. For the others, runtime options are explicitly enabled."
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "The storage engine for which the runtime options are always enabled is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Falcon",
            "b) FEDERATED",
            "c) InnoDB",
            "d) MEMORY"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The configuration options for the storage engine ‘MEMORY’ are always built. The runtime options for ‘MEMORY’ are also always enabled. For the others, runtime options are explicitly enabled byt specifications."
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "The most important configurable resource for MyISAM is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) key cache",
            "b) memory cache",
            "c) time cache",
            "d) speed cache"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the index processing, ‘MyISAM’ manages its own key cache, which is the most important configurable resource for the MyISAM storage engine. It is used for index based retrievals and sorts."
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "Which system variable enables mysqld to keep more tables open simultaneously?",
        "Options": [
            "a) table_cache",
            "b) max_connect",
            "c) delayed_queue_size",
            "d) max_allowed_packet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘table_cache’ stores the size of the table cache. Increasing the value enables ‘mysqld’ to keep more tables open simultaneously by reducing the number of files open and close operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "5. xyz in the following MySQL statement is __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VIEW</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> t;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) table",
            "b) column",
            "c) view",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A ‘View’ is created in MySQL by writing the clause ‘CREATE VIEW’ followed by the view name. Then follows the list of column names of the table that are to be presented as the view."
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "6. abc in the following MySQL statement is ____________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VIEW</span> xyz <span class=\"br0\">(</span>abc<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> a <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> t;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) view",
            "d) database"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Column names for a view can be explicitly provided in the ‘CREATE VIEW’ clause itself. It presents the table view with the aliased column names instead of the original column names."
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "How can a view refer to multiple tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) UNION",
            "b) JOIN",
            "c) GROUP",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a ‘View’ can refer to multiple tables. This makes it a lot simpler to execute the queries involving joins. When a selection is made from the view, the join is executed producing the results."
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "What is the mantissa in -1.58E5?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1.58",
            "b) 1.58",
            "c) E",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the scientific notation for real numbers is possible. Some values are represented as floating point numbers in scientific notation consisting of a mantissa and exponent."
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "What is the precision of BIGINT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 64",
            "c) 128",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the expressions containing only exact values that are all integers, the evaluation uses BIGINT (64 – bit) precision. MySQL evaluates expressions using exact/approximate math."
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "How many digits is the DECIMAL used for expressions containing only exact values with fractional part?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 64",
            "c) 65",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In MySQL, for the expressions containing only exact values and where one or more values have a fractional part, the DECIMAL arithmetic is used with digits of precision equal to 65."
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "The LOCAL capability for client library is enabled by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –enabled-local-file",
            "b) –enable-local-infile",
            "c) –enable-global-file",
            "d) –enable-local-file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘LOCAL’ capability for the ‘LOAD DATA’ statement does not need to be enabled explicitly. It can be controlled at build time and at runtime. This can be achieved in two ways."
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "What is the most important configurable resource for MyISAM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) key cache",
            "b) memory cache",
            "c) time cache",
            "d) speed cache"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: At build time LOCAL capability for the client library can be enabled or disabled by default. The ‘–enable-local-infile’ or ‘–disable-local-infile’ option is used when running configure."
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "How many options can be used to control LOCAL capability at runtime?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the index processing, ‘MyISAM’ manages its own key cache, which is the most important configurable resource for the MyISAM storage engine. It is used for index based retrievals and sorts."
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "6. abc in the following MySQL statement is ___________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> xyz <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> abc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) row name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: At runtime, the server can be started with the ‘–local-infile’ or ‘–skip-local-infile’ options to enable or disable ‘LOCAL’ capability on the server side. It can be enabled at build time too."
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "7. ‘x’ in the following MySQL statement is ____________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">DELETE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> x <span class=\"kw1\">USING</span> x <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> y <span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>col <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>col;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) column name",
            "b) table name",
            "c) server name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a multiple table ‘DELETE’ operation can be performed on the tables combined using any kind of ‘JOIN’ operation. The syntax also allows for deleting rows from multiple tables at once."
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "The mode used to turn off the special meaning of backslash and treat it as an ordinary character is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO_ESCAPES_SLASH",
            "b) NO_ESCAPES_BACKSLASH",
            "c) NO_BACKSLASH_ESCAPES",
            "d) NO_BACKSLASH_ESCAPE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Here, the operation that is being performed in the statement is the ‘DELETE’ operation. The table name is ‘xyz’ and column name is ‘abc’. The rows having abc value equal to 5 get deleted."
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "What is x’ffff’ in decimal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 65534",
            "b) 66535",
            "c) 65536",
            "d) 65537"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘DELETE’ operation is being performed in the statement. The table names are ‘x’ and ‘y’. The column name is ‘col’. The rows from left join of x and y get deleted according to the condition given."
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "What are X’61626364′ and X’61626364′?",
        "Options": [
            "a) abcd and 1633837924",
            "b) abcd and 4297383361",
            "c) dcba and 1633837924",
            "d) dcba and 4297383361"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To turn off the special meaning of backslash in MySQL, and treat it as an ordinary character, the SQL mode named NO_BACKSLASH_ESCAPES is enabled. The escape sequence is treated as characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "The variable which represents the default time zone of the MySQL server is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) time_zone",
            "b) system_time_zone",
            "c) date_and_time",
            "d) system_time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the server sets its default time zone by examining its environment. This is the local time zone of the server host. The time zone can be specified explicitly at the server startup."
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "The number of options that can be used to control LOCAL capability at runtime is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘system_time_zone’ represents the time zone that the server determines to be the server host time zone at startup time. It exists only as a global system variable and cannot be reset at runtime."
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "If an error occurs during the transaction the troubleshoot is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) rollback",
            "c) commit",
            "d) update"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The system variable ‘time_zone’ represents the default time zone of the MySQL server. By default, this variable is set to ‘SYSTEM’ which means to use the system_time_zone setting."
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "The ‘A’ in the ACID property of transactions is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Availability",
            "b) Accuracy",
            "c) Adjustability",
            "d) Atomicity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: At runtime, the server can be started with the ‘–local-infile’ or ‘–skip-local-infile’ options to enable or disable ‘LOCAL’ capability on the server side. It can be enabled at build time too."
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "The ‘C’ in the ACID property of transactions is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compound",
            "b) Concrete",
            "c) Collision",
            "d) Consistency"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Whenever an error occurs during a transaction, it is generally taken to the state prior to the beginning of transaction execution. This is known as rollback. It is a set of undo operations."
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "The datatype that means a variable length non binary string is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) VARCHAR",
            "b) BINARY",
            "c) VARBINARY",
            "d) BLOB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the transaction systems have an important set of characteristics in common. This is known as the ‘ACID’ property of the transaction. It refers to the four elementary characteristics of a transaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "The date and time datatype that stores time value in ‘hh:mm:ss’ format is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DATE",
            "b) TIME",
            "c) DATETIME",
            "d) TIMESTAMP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The elementary characteristics of a transaction are known as the ‘ACID’ properties. ‘ACID’ is the acronym for the four basic characteristics that a transaction must have for smooth processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "The spatial datatype used to store a curve is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) GEOMETRY",
            "b) POINT",
            "c) LINESTRING",
            "d) POLYGON"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there is a wide variety of string datatypes for use. Strings can even hold image and sound data. All four options are string type names. VARCHAR represents a variable length non binary string."
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "The option that supplies the pathname to root directory of MySQL installation is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –basedir",
            "b) –datadir",
            "c) –port",
            "d) –socket"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: OS imposes per process limits on the number of open file descriptors. If the system makes it difficult to raise the limit, running multiple instances of the server binary is done."
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "The log enabled by –relay-log-index is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) relay log index",
            "b) relay log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) error log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The option ‘–basedir’ has the purpose to specify the pathname to the root directory of the MySQL installation. The pathname to the data directory is specified by the option ‘–datadir’."
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "What is the storage size in bytes required for the MEDIUMINT datatype?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The system variable ‘time_zone’ represents the default time zone of the MySQL server. By default, this variable is set to ‘SYSTEM’ which means to use the system_time_zone setting."
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "What is the size of the BIT type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The numeric datatypes used in MySQL vary over ranges. There are a variety of INT types in the type specification. TINYINT requires 1, SMALLINT requires 2 bytes and MEDIUMINT requires 3."
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "What is the synonym for REAL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLOAT",
            "b) INT",
            "c) DOUBLE",
            "d) BIT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the numeric datatypes used in MySQL vary over the fields. However, the maximum size is fixed. Unlike the other numeric types, the size of the BIT datatype depends on the length of the field."
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "Execution on a time activated basis according to a schedule is done by _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stored program",
            "b) Events",
            "c) Triggers",
            "d) Stored procedures"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The REAL datatype, by default, is for the DOUBLE type. Floating point types can be defined as UNSIGNED. This eliminates the negative end of the type ranges. MySQL has a variety of default types."
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": "The character that the MySQL client program recognizes as a statement delimiter is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) :",
            "b) .",
            "c) ;",
            "d) ,"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the events execute on a time activated basis according to a schedule. Triggers are defined to execute when the table is modified via INSERT, DELETE or UPDATE statements."
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "Which upgrade involves exporting existing data using mysqldump?",
        "Options": [
            "a) inplace",
            "b) logical",
            "c) illogical",
            "d) system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The in-place upgrade involves shutting down the old MySQL version, replacing the old MySQL binaries or packages with the new ones, restarting MySQL on the existing data directory, and running mysql_upgrade."
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "Which upgrade involves shutting down the old MySQL version and replacing the old binaries?",
        "Options": [
            "a) inplace",
            "b) logical",
            "c) illogical",
            "d) system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The logical upgrade involves exporting existing data from the old MySQL version using mysqldump, installing the new MySQL version, loading the dump file into the new MySQL version."
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": "Slow shutdown can be performed by setting innodb_fast_shutdown to _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) -1",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: With a slow shutdown InnoDB performs a full purge and change buffer merge before shutting down. This ensures that data files are fully prepared in case of file format differences."
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "The command to see the warning messages is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DISPLAY WARNINGS",
            "b) DISP WARNINGS",
            "c) DISP WARNING",
            "d) SHOW WARNINGS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A procedure that involves REPAIR TABLE with the USE_FRM option must be done before upgrading. Use of this statement with a version of MySQL different from the one used to create the table can damage the table."
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "What is the SQL mode to check for divide by zero error?",
        "Options": [
            "a) STRICT_ALL_TABLES",
            "b) ERROR_FOR_DIVISION_BY_ZERO",
            "c) ERROR_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO",
            "d) ERROR_WHEN_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the default value conversions are reported as warnings for INSERT, REPLACE and UPDATE statements. The SHOW WARNINGS command is used after executing one of those statements to see the warning messages."
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "The mode used to turn on strict mode and all of the additional restrictions is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) STRICT_ALL_TABLES",
            "b) ERROR_FOR_DIVISION_BY_ZERO",
            "c) TRADITIONAL",
            "d) ERROR_WHEN_DIVIDE_BY_ZERO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To enable the check for divide by zero errors int all the storage engines, the SQL mode named ‘ERROR_FOR_DIVISION_BY_ZERO’ can be enabled. This is done by using SET sql_mode = ‘mode_name’."
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "The number of values returned from a stored procedure can be _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘TRADITIONAL’ mode is used to enable the strict mode and all of the additional restrictions. It is done by the command SET sql_mod = ‘TRADITIONAL’; The other SQL modes have other functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "How would a stored function named PI() written in the database ‘sampdb’ be called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PI()",
            "b) sampdb.PI()",
            "c) MySQL.PI()",
            "d) db.PI()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, unlike the stored functions, the stored procedures cannot return values. They can be used to perform calculations or produce the result sets passed back to the clients."
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "The privilege that must be given to the database to create a stored function or procedure is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE ROUTINE",
            "b) CREATE METHOD",
            "c) CREATE FUNCTION",
            "d) CREATE PROCEDURE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a stored function is defined with the same name as a built in function, the function name should be qualified with the database name when it is invoked. The function ‘PI()’ is built in."
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "To check if the data directory contains insecure files or directories, the command executed is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ls -l",
            "b) ls -a",
            "c) ls -la",
            "d) ls -lu"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It can be determined whether the data directory contains insecure files or directories by executing ‘ls -la’. Then the lookup for files or directories that have the “group” or “other” permissions turned on."
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "What enables the read and execute access to all users outside of mysql group.",
        "Options": [
            "a) drwxrwxr-x",
            "b) drwxrwxr-y",
            "c) drwyrwyr-x",
            "d) drwyrwyr-y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Some database directories have the proper permissions like ‘drwx——‘ enables read, write, and execute access to the owner, but no access to anyone else. Other directories have an overly permissive access mode like ‘drwxrwxr-x’."
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "Which program is used as a utility for MyISAM table maintenance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) innochecksum",
            "b) myisam_ftdump",
            "c) myisamchk",
            "d) myisamlog"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The server uses a Unix domain socket file for connections by clients to localhost. The socket file normally is publicly accessible so that client programs can use it again properly."
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "What does the AUTO_INCREMENT sequences normally begin at?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The program ‘myisamchk’ is a utility for the table maintenance. ‘innochecksum’ is used for offline InnoDB file checksum utility. To display full text index information ‘myisam_ftdump’ is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "How can the value of recently generated sequence number be obtained?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LAST_INSERT_ID()",
            "b) LATEST_INSERT_ID()",
            "c) INITIAL_INSERT_ID()",
            "d) INSERT_ID()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute provides unique numbers for column identification. AUTO_INCREMENT sequences normally begin at 1 and increase monotonically like 1, 2, 3, and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "What does LAST_INSERT_ID() return when no AUTO_INCREMENT value has been generated during the current connection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The value of most recently generated sequence number can be obtained by calling the LAST_INSERT_ID() function. This enables to reference the AUTO_INCREMENT value in the subsequent statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "Triggers are not supported for _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) delete",
            "b) update",
            "c) insert",
            "d) views"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘LAST_INSERT_ID()’ function returns zero when no ‘AUTO_INCREMENT’ value has been generated during the current connection with the server. It is tied to the current connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "How is a stored procedure invoked?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INVOKE",
            "b) SEE",
            "c) CALL",
            "d) RETURN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the triggers are run only after the table modifications like insert, update and delete are run. Triggers are not supported for views. In order to create a trigger, the CREATE TRIGGER statement is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "Which table lists the accounts and the databases for which the privileges are provided?",
        "Options": [
            "a) user",
            "b) db",
            "c) tables_priv",
            "d) procs_priv"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘db’ table lists which accounts have privileges for which databases. If a privilege is granted here, it applies to all objects in a database (tables, stored routines and so on)."
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "The table that lists the column level privileges is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) columns_priv",
            "b) db",
            "c) tables_priv",
            "d) procs_priv"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘columns_priv’ table lists the column-level privileges. A privilege that is supplied here applies to a particular column. The ‘db’ table lists which accounts have privileges for which databases."
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "Which of these grant table scope columns is case insensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Host",
            "b) User",
            "c) Password",
            "d) Db"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Db’ and ‘Table_name’ values are always treated as case sensitive even though the treatment of database and table names in SQL statements depends on the filesystem case sensitivity of the host."
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "What causes a replication master server to delete all the binary log files even if they are still in use?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RESET MASTER LOGS",
            "b) FLUSH TABLES",
            "c) RELOAD",
            "d) FLUSH LOGS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘RESET MASTER LOGS’ causes a replication master server to delete all binary log files even if they are in use which removes the information necessary to maintain the replication integrity."
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "What does ‘abc’ || ‘xyz’, when PIPES_AS_CONCAT is enabled, result in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) abcxyz",
            "d) xyzabc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the SQL mode PIPES_AS_CONCAT has been enabled, the SQL standard ‘||’ operation for string concatenation becomes valid in MySQL. Both operands are concatenated to give ‘abcxyz’."
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "What does the expression ‘2 BETWEEN 2 AND 5’ result in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘BETWEEN ……. AND’ clause is used to return a boolean value, if the given operand value lies between the values specified by the ‘AND’ clause. The range endpoints are inclusive."
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "The line that is not used to turn on the event scheduler is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) event_scheduler = ON",
            "b) eventscheduler = ON",
            "c) event_scheduler_ON",
            "d) events_scheduler_ON"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL provides pattern matching based on the ‘REGEXP’ operator and regular expressions that are similar to those used in Unix programs, namely, grep, sed and vi. REGEXP does not take collation into account."
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "The statement that is used to check the status of the event scheduler at runtime is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW STATUS OF ‘event_scheduler’",
            "b) SHOW VARIABLES OF ‘event_scheduler’",
            "c) SHOW STATUS LIKE ‘event_scheduler’",
            "d) SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘event_scheduler’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The line ‘event_scheduler = ON’ is put in the option file that the server reads. The event scheduler does not run by default. It must be turned on if events are to used in the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "The value of event_scheduler that enables checking status but not changing it at runtime is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ON",
            "b) OFF",
            "c) DISABLED",
            "d) ENABLED"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, in order to check the status of the event scheduler at runtime, the statement: SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘event_scheduler’; is used. The event_scheduler is a system variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "How many files does each end of a client/server connection including SSL support use to set up secure communications?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: With a MySQL installation that includes SSL support the server and its clients can communicate securely. Each end of a connection uses three files to set up secure communications."
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "The TLS protocol is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) transparent layer security",
            "b) transport layer security",
            "c) transparent level security",
            "d) transport level security"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL supports encrypted connections between clients and the server using the TLS protocol. It is also referred to as SSL but MySQL does not actually use the SSL protocol for encrypted connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "The grant table scope columns that is case insensitive is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Host",
            "b) User",
            "c) Password",
            "d) Db"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Db’ and ‘Table_name’ values are always treated as case sensitive even though treatment of database and table names in SQL statements depends on the filesystem case sensitivity of the host."
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "Which variable checks for the availability of SSL support?",
        "Options": [
            "a) have_ssl",
            "b) has_ssl",
            "c) avail_ssl",
            "d) ssl_avail"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: After the SSL-capable server is started, to verify that it supports SSL, connection is established with ‘mysql’ and the following query is issued: SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘have_ssl’."
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "What is the best datatype for a column that is expected to store values up to 2 million?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SMALLINT",
            "b) TINYINT",
            "c) MEDIUMINT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there is no data type provided which has an optional time part. The ‘DATE’ type values never have a time part. The ‘DATETIME’ type values must have a time part in them."
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "The datatype that stores the longest length of strings is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHAR",
            "b) VARCHAR",
            "c) TINYTEXT",
            "d) TEXT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The different numeric types used in MySQL are used to store a different range of values. To store values of the order of a million, the MEDIUMINT or BIGINT datatype is sufficient."
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "The security context when a user creates a stored program that accesses sensitive data but forgets that other people who can invoke the object have the same access is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) good",
            "b) bad",
            "c) illegal",
            "d) fare"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In MySQL, the different string datatypes are used to store different lenghts of the string. Here, the length would refer to the number of characters in the string. TEXT stores longer strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "The recovery of data changes made since a given point in time is called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) decremental",
            "b) incremental",
            "c) close",
            "d) clear"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Incremental recovery refers to the recovery of data changes made since a given point in time. It is performed after restoring a full backup that brings the server to its state as of the time the backup was made."
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "What performs a key distribution analysis and stores the distribution for the named table or tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ANALYZE TABLE",
            "b) CHECK TABLE",
            "c) CHECKSUM TABLE",
            "d) OPTIMIZE TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘ANALYZE TABLE’ performs a key distribution analysis and stores the distribution for the named table or tables. For the MyISAM tables, this statement is equivalent to using ‘myisamchk –analyze’."
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "Which of the following columns is not returned by ‘OPTIMIZE TABLE’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Op",
            "c) Msg_type",
            "d) Msg_txt"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘OPTIMIZE TABLE’ table catches and throws any errors that occur while copying table statistics from the old file to the newly created file. It returns a result set of columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "REPAIR TABLE does not work for _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) ARCHIVE",
            "c) InnoDB",
            "d) CSV"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘REPAIR TABLE’ works for MyISAM, ARCHIVE, and CSV tables. For MyISAM tables, it has the same effect as ‘myisamchk –recover’ tbl_name by default. This statement does not work with views."
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "What is a synonym for CHARACTER SET?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CSET",
            "b) CHSET",
            "c) CHARSET",
            "d) CHCSET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The binary protocol is more difficult to use because more setup is necessary for transmitting and receiving data values. The binary protocol does not support all statements like ‘USE’. "
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "The line which is written at the top of the script to write a Perl script using CGI.pm is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) use this CGI",
            "b) put CGI",
            "c) use CGI",
            "d) include CGI"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘CHARACTER SET’ can be abbreviated into ‘CHARSET’ and can be used in the same contexts and statements where ‘CHARACTER SET’ is used. ‘charset’ is the server-supported character set."
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "To perform consistency checks on a MyISAM table the statement is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHECK TABLE",
            "b) REPAIR TABLE",
            "c) ANALYZE TABLE",
            "d) OPTIMIZE TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to perform consistency checks or table repairs on a MyISAM table a ‘CHECK TABLE’ or ‘REPAIR TABLE’ statement is issued. The ‘mysqlcheck’ program can also be invoked."
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "The statement that performs key distribution analysis and stores the distribution for the named tables is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHECK TABLE",
            "b) ANALYZE TABLE",
            "c) CHECKSUM TABLE",
            "d) OPTIMIZE TABLE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘ANALYZE TABLE’ performs a key distribution analysis and stores the distribution for the named table or tables. For the MyISAM tables, this statement is equivalent to using ‘myisamchk –analyze’."
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "The column not returned by ‘OPTIMIZE TABLE’ is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Table",
            "b) Msg_txt",
            "c) Op",
            "d) Msg_type"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘OPTIMIZE TABLE’ table catches and throws any errors that occur while copying table statistics from the old file to the newly created file. It returns a result set of columns."
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "For which table does ‘REPAIR TABLE’ not work?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) ARCHIVE",
            "c) CSV",
            "d) InnoDB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘REPAIR TABLE’ works for MyISAM, ARCHIVE, and CSV tables. For MyISAM tables, it has the same effect as ‘myisamchk –recover’ tbl_name by default. This statement does not work with views."
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "What is the Perl DBI?",
        "Options": [
            "a) database inheritance",
            "b) database integrity",
            "c) database interface",
            "d) database isolation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Perl DBI is the Perl Database Interface. The work of the interface is to form a link between the application programming interface in C with all the other programming languages."
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "What is the default path to Perl in Unix?",
        "Options": [
            "a) /usr/bin/perl",
            "b) /usr/bin",
            "c) /usr/perl",
            "d) /usr/perl/bin"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: All Perl scripts generally begin with a #! (shebang) line. A script is a file containing a sequence of commands. The Perl scripts are text files, which can be created using any text editor."
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "How is the output from PHP generated?",
        "Options": [
            "a) statically generated",
            "b) dynamically generated",
            "c) not generated",
            "d) no output"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The interpreter switches between code mode back and text mode when it sees another special tag that signals the end of the code. This enables the mix of static text with dynamically generated results."
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "What attempts auto recovery based on the contents of its serial log?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MyISAM",
            "b) InnoDB",
            "c) Falcon",
            "d) TRANSACTION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When the Falcon storage engine is enabled, it attempts the auto recovery based on the contents of its serial log. If the InnoDB storage engine is enabled, it checks for a variety of problems automatically."
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To enable MyISAM table recovery, the server is started with the ‘–myisam-recover = level’ option. The value of level is a comma-separated list of the following: BACKUP, FORCE, QUICK or DEFAULT."
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "Under which option are index changes not flushed until tables close?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –delay-write-key",
            "b) –delay-key-write",
            "c) –write-key-delay",
            "d) –key-write-delay"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the MyISAM recovery is important if the server is run with the ‘–delay-key-write’ option. Under this condition, the index changes are not flushed until the tables close."
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "Which option suppresses output unless there are errors in the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –silent",
            "b) –wild",
            "c) –suppress",
            "d) –noout"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘–silent’ option suppresses the output unless there are errors in the tables. The ‘cron’ jobs typically generate a mail message if a job produces any output at all."
    },
    {
        "id": 747,
        "Question": "What is the variable that is a handle to a database object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The variable named ‘$dbh’ is a handle to an open file. ‘$h’ is a generic handle and the meaning depends on context. ‘$dbh’ is a handle to a database object. ‘$sth’ is a handle to a query object."
    },
    {
        "id": 748,
        "Question": "The variable that returns code from operations that return true or false is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rc",
            "b) $rv",
            "c) $rows",
            "d) $ary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Perl Non-handle variable ‘$rc’ returns code from operations that return true or false. ‘$rv’ returns value from operations that return an integer. ‘$rows’ returns value from operations that return a row count."
    },
    {
        "id": 749,
        "Question": "In PHP, how is the first element accessed if $a represents an array with numeric indices?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $a[1] ",
            "b) $a[0] ",
            "c) $a.1",
            "d) $a.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If $a represents an array with numeric indices, its elements are accessed as $x[0], $x[1], and so on. In general terms, each element at the position i is accessed and used as $a[i – 1]."
    },
    {
        "id": 750,
        "Question": "Which operator is used to access property of an object in PHP?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .",
            "b) *",
            "c) ->",
            "d) @"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The PHP arrays can even have both numeric and associative elements. For example, $x[1] and $x[“large”] can both be the elements of the same array. $x can be an object, whose elements are accessed by the arrow ‘->’ operated."
    },
    {
        "id": 751,
        "Question": "How is the binary log rotated?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLUSH LOGS",
            "b) ROTATE LOGS",
            "c) FLUSH BINLOG",
            "d) ROTATE BINLOG"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL supports incremental backups. The server should be started with the ‘–log-bin’ option to enable binary logging. The binary log files provide information to replicate changes to the database."
    },
    {
        "id": 752,
        "Question": "How is a delimited-text data file reloaded?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqlexport",
            "b) mysqlimport",
            "c) mysqlexpand",
            "d) mysqltransfer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In order to reload a delimited-text data file, use ‘LOAD DATA INFILE’ or ‘mysqlimport’. MySQL supports the incremental backups when the server is started with the ‘–log-bin’ option."
    },
    {
        "id": 753,
        "Question": "Which program performs logical backups?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqlimport",
            "b) mysqldump",
            "c) myslqpit",
            "d) mysqllogic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘mysqldump’ performs logical backups. It produces a set of SQL statements that are executed to reproduce the original database object definitions. It dumps one or more MySQL databases for backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 754,
        "Question": "The option that suppresses output unless there are errors in the table is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –silent",
            "b) –wild",
            "c) –suppress",
            "d) –noout"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘–silent’ option suppresses the output unless there are errors in the tables. The ‘cron’ jobs typically generate a mail message if a job produces any output at all."
    },
    {
        "id": 755,
        "Question": "What is the return value from operations returning a row count?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rc",
            "b) $rv",
            "c) $rows",
            "d) $ary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Perl Non-handle variable ‘$ary’ is an array or list representing a row of values returned by a query. ‘$rc’ returns code from operations that return true or false. ‘$rv’ returns value from operations that return an integer. ‘$rows’ returns value from operations that return a row count."
    },
    {
        "id": 756,
        "Question": "The mode of search in which the search string is parsed into words and the search looks for rows is ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Boolean mode",
            "b) Natural language",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: While using the DBI API functions are called and pointers to structures are used. The functions are called “methods,” pointers are called “references,” pointer variables are called “handles”."
    },
    {
        "id": 757,
        "Question": "What is the hub of a MySQL installation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqla",
            "b) mysqlb",
            "c) mysqlc",
            "d) mysqld"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, a full text search capability is provided, which enables to look for words or phrases without using pattern-matching operations. There are three kinds of full text searches."
    },
    {
        "id": 758,
        "Question": "Which program copies the databases from one server to another?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldbcopy",
            "b) mysqlcopydb",
            "c) mysqlflushdb",
            "d) mysqldbflush"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The utility program ‘mysqldbcopy’ is capable of copying databases from one server to another server. It can also prepare copies to make transfers on the same servers. This can be done simply by running the program."
    },
    {
        "id": 759,
        "Question": "To use ‘mysqldbcopy’ which privileges are required on the source server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) INSERT",
            "c) UPDATE",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To use the utility program ‘mysqldbcopy’, the user must have SELECT privileges for the database(s) on the source server and have CREATE, INSERT, UPDATE on the destination server."
    },
    {
        "id": 760,
        "Question": "The program that performs logical backups is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqlimport",
            "b) mysqldump",
            "c) myslqpit",
            "d) mysqllogic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘mysqldump’ performs logical backups. It produces a set of SQL statements that are executed to reproduce the original database object definitions. It dumps one or more MySQL databases for backup."
    },
    {
        "id": 761,
        "Question": "In ‘mysqldump’ which option is used to make all tables in the destination databases to use a different storage engine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –next-storage-engine",
            "b) –new-storage-engine",
            "c) –clear-storage-engine",
            "d) –get-storage-engine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: While using the program ‘mysqldump’ in MySQL to copy databases from server to server, all tables in the destination databases can be directed to use a different storage engine with the –new-storage-engine option."
    },
    {
        "id": 762,
        "Question": "Which function returns reference to hash of row values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 763,
        "Question": "The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values keyed by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) table name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values, keyed by the column name. The function ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values."
    },
    {
        "id": 764,
        "Question": "Which function returns reference to array of row values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 765,
        "Question": "Which is the log in which data changes received from a replication master server are written?",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) general query log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) relay log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL server is highly configurable. Some of the operational characteristics that you can control include which storage engines the server supports, the default character set, and its default time zone."
    },
    {
        "id": 766,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘CHECK TABLE’ statement provides an interface to the table checking capabilities of the server. It works for MyISAM and InnoDB tables as well as for ARCHIVE and CSV tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 767,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘REPAIR TABLE’ statement provides an interface to the table repair capabilities of the server. It works with MyISAM and ARCHIVE tables. It also works with CSV tables as of MySQL 5.1.19."
    },
    {
        "id": 768,
        "Question": "Which myisamchk variable represents the size of buffer used to hold index blocks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) key_buffer_size",
            "b) read_buffer_size",
            "c) sort_buffer_size",
            "d) write_buffer_size"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The myisamchk variable ‘key_buffer_size’ stores the size of buffer that is used to hold index blocks. ‘read_buffer_size’ stores the size of buffer used for read operations, ‘sort_buffer_size’ is used for sorting."
    },
    {
        "id": 769,
        "Question": "Which option is used in ‘mysqldump’ to make all tables in the destination databases to use a different storage engine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –next-storage-engine",
            "b) –new-storage-engine",
            "c) –clear-storage-engine",
            "d) –get-storage-engine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: While using the program ‘mysqldump’ in MySQL to copy databases from server to server, all tables in the destination databases can be directed to use a different storage engine with the –new-storage-engine option."
    },
    {
        "id": 770,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘mysqlcheck’ and ‘mysqlisamchk’ are the programs that perform table checking, analysis, optimization and repairs when tables become damaged. ‘mysqlcheck’ works with MyISAM tables."
    },
    {
        "id": 771,
        "Question": "What is the output from PHP?",
        "Options": [
            "a) statically generated",
            "b) dynamically generated",
            "c) not generated",
            "d) no output"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL data directory is the place where the server stores its databases and status files. It is crucial to understand all structures and contents of the data directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 772,
        "Question": "What are PHP variables preceded by?",
        "Options": [
            "a) _",
            "b) @",
            "c) $",
            "d) &"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The interpreter switches between code mode back and text mode when it sees another special tag that signals the end of the code. This enables the mix of static text with dynamically generated results."
    },
    {
        "id": 773,
        "Question": "Which data type is best suited to store currency values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INT",
            "b) FLOAT",
            "c) DOUBLE",
            "d) DECIMAL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: All the PHP scripts that use variables have variable names preceded by the dollar sign (‘$’). The variables are signified by this identifier, irrespective of the value it stores."
    },
    {
        "id": 774,
        "Question": "Which program converts binary log files to statements in text form?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqllog",
            "c) mysqlbin",
            "d) mysqlbinlog"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘mysqlbinlog’ program is used to convert the binary log files to statements in text form. This makes it easy to execute. The output from ‘mysqlbinlog’ is used as input to mysql."
    },
    {
        "id": 775,
        "Question": "The ‘mysqlbackup’ command to perform a restore operation is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) copy-back-and-apply-log",
            "b) apply-log-and-copy-back",
            "c) copy-log-and-apply-back",
            "d) apply-back-and-copy-log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘mysqlbackup’ commands to perform a restore operation are ‘copy-back-and-apply-log’ and ‘copy-back’ (for directory backup only). The restoration process requires the database server to be already shut down."
    },
    {
        "id": 776,
        "Question": "The myisamchk variable that represents the size of buffer used to hold index blocks is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) key_buffer_size",
            "b) read_buffer_size",
            "c) sort_buffer_size",
            "d) write_buffer_size"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The myisamchk variable ‘key_buffer_size’ stores the size of buffer that is used to hold index blocks. ‘read_buffer_size’ stores size of buffer used for read operations, ‘sort_buffer_size’ is used for sorting."
    },
    {
        "id": 777,
        "Question": "Where does MySQL Enterprise Backup record details of each backup?",
        "Options": [
            "a) history_backup",
            "b) backup_history",
            "c) backlog_history",
            "d) history_backlog"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The restored data includes the ‘backup_history’ table, where ‘MySQL Enterprise Backup’ records details of each backup. The table allows to perform future incremental backups using ‘–incremental-base=history:last_backup’."
    },
    {
        "id": 778,
        "Question": "What is the log in which data changes received from a replication master server are written?",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) general query log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) relay log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL server is highly configurable. Some of the operational characteristics that you can control include which storage engines the server supports, the default character set, and its default time zone."
    },
    {
        "id": 779,
        "Question": "The metadata log is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) ddl log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) relay log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is useful to run multiple servers on the same machine under certain circumstances. A new MySQL release can also be tested while leaving the current production server in place."
    },
    {
        "id": 780,
        "Question": "What is the default size of ‘max_binlog_cache_size’ system variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 GB",
            "b) 2 GB",
            "c) 4 GB",
            "d) 8 GB"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Relay Log has the data changes received from a replication master server written in it. The problems encountered during the starting, running or stopping of ‘mysqld’ is written in error log."
    },
    {
        "id": 781,
        "Options": [
            "a) writes",
            "b) reads",
            "c) same priority",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The DDL log is also known as the metadata log. The metadata operations performed by the DDL statements. The Relay Log has the data changes received from a replication master server written in it."
    },
    {
        "id": 782,
        "Question": "The slave stores the CHANGE MASTER parameters in the file _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) slave.info",
            "b) slave.inf",
            "c) master.info",
            "d) master.inf"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘slave’ stores the ‘CHANGE MASTER’ parameters in a file named ‘master.info’ in its data directory in order to record the initial replication status. It updates the file as replication proceeds."
    },
    {
        "id": 783,
        "Question": "Which statement on the master expires binary log files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW SLAVE STATUS",
            "b) PURGE MASTER",
            "c) PURGE SLAVE",
            "d) SHOW MASTER STATUS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘PURGE MASTER’ statement on the master expires binary log files. This can be used after issuing a ‘SHOW SLAVE STATUS’ statement on each of the slaves to determine which log files are no longer needed."
    },
    {
        "id": 784,
        "Question": "Which statement suspends the replication related activity of the slave server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) RESUME SLAVE",
            "b) START SLAVE",
            "c) STOP SLAVE",
            "d) GET SLAVE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘STOP SLAVE’ and ‘START SLAVE’ statements suspend and resume the replication-related activity of a slave server. These statements are useful for telling the slave to be quiescent."
    },
    {
        "id": 785,
        "Question": "MySQL Enterprise Backup records details of each backup in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) history_backup",
            "b) backup_history",
            "c) backlog_history",
            "d) history_backlog"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The restored data includes the ‘backup_history’ table, where ‘MySQL Enterprise Backup’ records details of each backup. The table allows to perform future incremental backups using ‘–incremental-base=history:last_backup’."
    },
    {
        "id": 786,
        "Question": "In which context is the privilege ‘CREATE TABLESPACE’ applied?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Server administration",
            "b) Tables",
            "c) Stored routines",
            "d) Views"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The column name associated with the privilege ‘CREATE TABLESPACE’ is ‘Create_tablespace_priv’. The context in which this privilege is being used is the server administration."
    },
    {
        "id": 787,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The client library provides the means through which the MySQL bindings for other languages can be built on top of the C API. This type of interface exists for Perl, PHP, Python and others."
    },
    {
        "id": 788,
        "Question": "In which directory are the DBI scripts located?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cgi-inc",
            "b) cgi-bin",
            "c) cgi-usr",
            "d) cgi-perl"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The PHP scripts are different from DBI scripts since PHP scripts are located within the web server document tree while DBI scripts are located in a cgi-bin directory located outside of document tree."
    },
    {
        "id": 789,
        "Question": "Which is the stored program associated with a schedule?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trigger",
            "b) Event",
            "c) Stored function",
            "d) Stored procedure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DBI scripts are located in a cgi-bin directory located outside of document tree. The PHP scripts are different from DBI scripts since PHP scripts are located within the web server document tree."
    },
    {
        "id": 790,
        "Question": "Which of these is not an exact numeric type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SMALLINT",
            "b) DECIMAL",
            "c) NUMERIC",
            "d) REAL"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: MySQL supports all the standard SQL numeric data types. These are the exact numeric data types like INTEGER, SMALLINT, DECIMAL and NUMERIC and the approximate numeric data types like FLOAT, REAL and DOUBLE PRECISION."
    },
    {
        "id": 791,
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The BIT data type stores the bit values. It is supported for the MyISAM, MEMORY, InnoDB and NDB tables. MySQL supports all the standard SQL numeric data types, both the exact and approximate."
    },
    {
        "id": 792,
        "Question": "The statement that suspends the replication related activity of the slave server is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) RESUME SLAVE",
            "b) START SLAVE",
            "c) STOP SLAVE",
            "d) GET SLAVE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ‘STOP SLAVE’ and ‘START SLAVE’ statements suspend and resume the replication-related activity of a slave server. These statements are useful for telling the slave to be quiescent."
    },
    {
        "id": 793,
        "Question": "The minimum value stored by signed TINYINT is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -256",
            "b) -128",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 128"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL supports the SQL standard integer types INTEGER, or INT, and SMALLINT. As an extension to this standard, MySQL also supports the integer types TINYINT, MEDIUMINT and BIGINT."
    },
    {
        "id": 794,
        "Question": "MySQL uses security based on ACL. What does it stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Access Control Language",
            "b) Access Control Lists",
            "c) Automatic Control Lists",
            "d) Automatic Control Language"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL uses security based on Access Control Lists (ACLs) for all connections, queries and other operations that users can attempt to perform. There is support for SSL encrypted connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 795,
        "Question": "If $a represents an array with numeric indices in PHP, the first element accessed by ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $a[1] ",
            "b) $a[0] ",
            "c) $a.1",
            "d) $a.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: On Unix the mysql client writes a record of the executed statements to a history file. By default, this file is named as ‘.mysql_history’. It is created in the home directory."
    },
    {
        "id": 796,
        "Question": "The operator used in PHP to access property of an object is ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) .",
            "b) *",
            "c) ->",
            "d) @"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the MySQL privilege system, a password applies globally to an account. A password cannot be explicitly associated with a specific object such as a database, table, or routine."
    },
    {
        "id": 797,
        "Question": "The maximum value that can be specified to the size of VARCHAR is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 127",
            "c) 1023",
            "d) 65535"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The values in ‘VARCHAR’ columns are variable length strings. The length can be a value from 0 to 65,535. The effective maximum length of a VARCHAR is subject to the maximum row size."
    },
    {
        "id": 798,
        "Question": "The storage in bytes required for VARCHAR(4) type ‘abcd’ is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘VARCHAR’ values are not padded when they are stored. The trailing spaces are retained when values are stored and retrieved in conformance with standard SQL. The given size is 5 bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 799,
        "Question": "Which mode does not remove trailing spaces when CHAR values are retrieved?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PAD_CHAR_TO_FULL_LENGTH",
            "b) TO_FULL_LENGTH_CHAR_PAD",
            "c) CHAR_PAD_TO_FULL_LENGTH",
            "d) PAD_CHAR_TO_LENGTH"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When the CHAR values are stored, they are right-padded with spaces to the specified length. When CHAR values are retrieved, trailing spaces are removed unless the SQL mode ‘PAD_CHAR_TO_FULL_LENGTH’ is enabled."
    },
    {
        "id": 800,
        "Question": "What is the minimum value stored by signed TINYINT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -256",
            "b) -128",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 128"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL supports the SQL standard integer types INTEGER, or INT, and SMALLINT. As an extension to this standard, MySQL also supports the integer types TINYINT, MEDIUMINT and BIGINT."
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "Question": "For InnoDB tables in mysqldump an online backup that takes no locks on tables can be performed by which option?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –multiple-transaction",
            "b) –single-transaction",
            "c) –double-transaction",
            "d) –no-transaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For InnoDB tables it is possible to perform an online backup that takes no locks on tables using the option ‘–single-transaction’ to ‘mysqldump’. The ‘mysqldump’ can make backups."
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "Question": "What is used to reload a delimited text data file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldump",
            "b) mysqld",
            "c) mysqlimport",
            "d) mysqlnaive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A way to create text data files along with files containing ‘CREATE TABLE’ statements for the backed up tables is to use ‘mysqldump’ with –tab. To reload a delimited text data file ‘mysqlimport’ is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "Question": "What is SBR replication?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Statement based",
            "b) Row based",
            "c) Column based",
            "d) Table based"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Replication enables data from one MySQL database server (the master) to be copied to one or more MySQL database servers (the slaves). Replication is asynchronous by default."
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "Question": "Which is the library file that contains various portability macros and definitions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two main kinds of replication format: Statement Based Replication (SBR) replicates entire SQL statements and Row Based Replication (RBR) replicates only the changed rows."
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "Question": "Which is the header that should be included first?",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘my_sys.h’ header file contains a variety of portability macros and definitions required for structures and functions. These structures and functions are used by the client library."
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "Question": "Which of these has special automatic update behavior?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DATE",
            "b) TIME",
            "c) TIMESTAMP",
            "d) YEAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The date and time types for representing temporal values are ‘DATE’, ‘TIME’, ‘DATETIME’, ‘TIMESTAMP’ and ‘YEAR’. Each temporal type has a range of valid values and a ‘zero’ value."
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "Question": "To disallow zero month or day parts in dates, the option used is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO_ZERO_IN_DATE",
            "b) NO_DATE_WITH_ZERO",
            "c) ZERO_IN_DATE",
            "d) DATE_WITH_ZERO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL permits to store the dates where the day or month and day are zero in a DATE or DATETIME column. This is helpful for applications that need to store birthdates for which the exact date is unknown."
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "Question": "The mode that does not remove trailing spaces when CHAR values are retrieved is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) PAD_CHAR_TO_FULL_LENGTH",
            "b) TO_FULL_LENGTH_CHAR_PAD",
            "c) CHAR_PAD_TO_FULL_LENGTH",
            "d) PAD_CHAR_TO_LENGTH"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When the CHAR values are stored, they are right-padded with spaces to the specified length. When CHAR values are retrieved, trailing spaces are removed unless the SQL mode ‘PAD_CHAR_TO_FULL_LENGTH’ is enabled."
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "Question": "The functions in Perl DBI called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) functions",
            "b) procedures",
            "c) methods",
            "d) programs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MySQL automatically converts a date or time value into a number if the value is used in a numeric context and vice versa. A ‘zero’ value can also be represented in MySQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "Question": "The variable used as a handle to an open file is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the DBI API, functions are called and pointers to structures are used. The functions are called ‘methods’, pointers are called ‘references’, pointer variables are called ‘handles’."
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "Question": "Which variable is a handle to a database object?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The variable named ‘$fh’ is a handle to an open file. ‘$h’ is a generic handle and the meaning depends on context. ‘$dbh’ is a handle to a database object. ‘$sth’ is a handle to a query object."
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "Question": "Which classes does spatial data types in MySQL correspond to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) OpenGSS",
            "b) OpenGIS",
            "c) ClosedGSS",
            "d) ClosedGIS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL has spatial data types that correspond to OpenGIS classes. Some of them that hold single geometry values are ‘GEOMETRY’, ‘POINT’, ‘LINESTRING’ and ‘POLYGON’. Some can hold a collection of values."
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "Question": "Which type can store a collection of objects of any type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GEOMETRYCOLLECTION",
            "b) MULTIPOINT",
            "c) MULTILINESTRING",
            "d) MULTIPOLYGON"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘GEOMETRYCOLLECTION’ can store a collection of objects of any type. The other collection types like ‘MULTIPOINT’, ‘MULTILINESTRING’, ‘MULTIPOLYGON’ and ‘GEOMETRYCOLLECTION’ restrict collection members to those having a particular geometry type."
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "Question": "What is the generic handle whose meaning depends on context?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $dbh",
            "b) $sth",
            "c) $fh",
            "d) $h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘SPATIAL’ indexes can be created on ‘NOT NULL’ spatial columns. Therefore, if it is planned to index the column, it would need to be declared as NOT NULL. This type can be used in many ways."
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "Question": "What is the non handle array representing a row of values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) $rc",
            "b) $rv",
            "c) $rows",
            "d) $ary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL automatically converts a date or time value into a number if the value is used in a numeric context and vice versa. A ‘zero’ value can also be represented in MySQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "Question": "The mode of search is the search string parsed into words and the search looks for rows is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Boolean mode",
            "b) Natural language",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The variable named ‘$fh’ is a handle to an open file. ‘$h’ is a generic handle and the meaning depends on context. ‘$dbh’ is a handle to a database object. ‘$sth’ is a handle to a query object."
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "Question": "In which mode is the indicator of the presence/absence of a word in search used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural language",
            "b) Boolean mode",
            "c) Query expansion",
            "d) Cross mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Perl Non-handle variable ‘$ary’ is an array or list representing a row of values returned by a query. ‘$rc’ returns code from operations that return true or false. ‘$rv’ returns value from operations that return an integer. ‘$rows’ returns value from operations that return a row count."
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "Question": "Which operator is used to return value from JSON columns after evaluating the path and unquoting the result?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ->",
            "b) ->>",
            "c) <<",
            "d) >>"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operator ‘–>>’ is used to return values from JSON columns after evaluating the path and unquoting the result. It is equivalent to the function ‘JSON_UNQUOTE(JSON_EXTRACT())’."
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "Question": "The right shift operator is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) >>",
            "b) <<",
            "c) <",
            "d) >"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The right shift operator is ‘>>’. It is used to shift the bits of a number towards the right. The left shift operator is ‘<<‘. It is used to shift the bits of a number to the left."
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "Question": "Which operator compares sounds?",
        "Options": [
            "a) MATCH SOUNDS",
            "b) CHECK SOUNDS",
            "c) SOUNDS LIKE",
            "d) SOUNDS SIMILAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The operator ‘SOUNDS LIKE’ is used to compare the sound. The ‘RLIKE’ is a synonym for ‘REGEXP’, which is a pattern matching using regular expressions. There are a lot of other operators for use. "
    },
    {
        "id": 821,
        "Question": "What does RTF refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rich Text Format",
            "b) Right Text Format",
            "c) Rich Text Function",
            "d) Right Text Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RTF (Rich Text Format) is a format developed by Microsoft that is understood by many word processors. MS-Word is one such program. Many others such as ‘OpenOffice’ understand it too."
    },
    {
        "id": 822,
        "Question": "Which function returns an array of row values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_array()’ returns an array of row values. ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 823,
        "Question": "Which function returns a reference to hash of row values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 824,
        "Question": "‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns a reference to the hash of row values keyed by what?",
        "Options": [
            "a) row name",
            "b) column name",
            "c) table name",
            "d) database name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns a reference to the hash of row values, keyed by the column name. The function ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values."
    },
    {
        "id": 825,
        "Question": "The maximum non zero value for FLOAT is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.402823466E+38",
            "b) 3.402823466E+37",
            "c) 3.402823466E+39",
            "d) 3.402823466E+35"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, each datatype has its own range. Data types give an idea of the kind of values and the ranges that a variable is allowed to store. The maximum non zero value for FLOAT is 3.402823466E+38."
    },
    {
        "id": 826,
        "Question": "The server is told to accept spaces after function names by _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –sql-mode=SKIP_SPACE",
            "b) –sql-mode=IGNORE_SPACE",
            "c) –sql-mode=SPACE_IGNORE",
            "d) –sql-mode=SPACE_SKIP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL server is told to accept spaces after function names by starting it with the ‘–sql-mode=IGNORE_SPACE’ option. Individual client programs can request this behavior by using the ‘CLIENT_IGNORE_SPACE’ option for ‘mysql_real_connect()’."
    },
    {
        "id": 827,
        "Question": "Which function returns NULL if expr1 = expr2?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CASE",
            "b) IF()",
            "c) IFNULL()",
            "d) NULLIF()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘CASE’ is used for the case operator. The function ‘IF()’ is used for the if/else construct. The function ‘IFNULL()’ is the Null if/else construct. ‘NULLIF()’ returns NULL if expr1 = expr2."
    },
    {
        "id": 828,
        "Question": "The operator that compares sounds is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) MATCH SOUNDS",
            "b) CHECK SOUNDS",
            "c) SOUNDS LIKE",
            "d) SOUNDS SIMILAR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The operator ‘SOUNDS LIKE’ is used to compare sound. The ‘RLIKE’ is a synonym for ‘REGEXP’, which is a pattern matching using regular expressions. There are a lot of other operators for use. "
    },
    {
        "id": 829,
        "Question": "The string function that returns the index of the first occurrence of substring is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) INSERT()",
            "b) INSTR()",
            "c) INSTRING()",
            "d) INFSTR()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The string function ‘INSTR()’ is used to return the index of the first occurrence of the substring. The function ‘INSERT()’ is used to insert a substring at the specified position up to the specified number of characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 830,
        "Question": "What does the AUTO_INCREMENT sequences begin at by default?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘CGI.pm’ supports an object oriented style of use which allows to invoke its functions without importing the names. To do this, a use statement is included and a CGI object is created."
    },
    {
        "id": 831,
        "Question": "8. The one that is not optional is _____________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> select_list <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> table_list <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> row_constraint <span class=\"kw1\">GROUP</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> grouping_columns;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) select_list",
            "b) table_list",
            "c) row_constraint",
            "d) grouping_columns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there can only be one column per table with the AUTO_INCREMENT attribute. It should also have an integer data type. The AUTO_INCREMENT is also allowed for floating point types."
    },
    {
        "id": 832,
        "Question": "The join in which all the rows from the right table appear in the output irrespective of the content of the other table is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CARTESIAN JOIN",
            "b) CROSS JOIN",
            "c) INNER JOIN",
            "d) RIGHT JOIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The AUTO_INCREMENT column attribute provides unique numbers for column identification. AUTO_INCREMENT sequences normally begin at 1 and increase monotonically like 1, 2, 3, and so on."
    },
    {
        "id": 833,
        "Question": "The facility that allows nesting one select statement into another is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) nesting",
            "b) binding",
            "c) subquerying",
            "d) encapsulating"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Given above was a basic syntax of the SELECT statement. Everything in the syntax is optional except the ‘select_list’ option. All the others are free to be omitted, and will work fine."
    },
    {
        "id": 834,
        "Question": "Which system variable when set to 1, makes all temporary tables to get stored on disk rather than in memory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) basedir",
            "b) back_log",
            "c) big_tables",
            "d) bind_address"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The variable ‘big_tables’ if set to 1, all temporary tables are stored on disk rather than in memory. This is a little slower but the error ‘The table tbl_name is full’ does not occur for SELECT operations that require a large temporary table."
    },
    {
        "id": 835,
        "Question": "The permitted value type for the variable ‘character_set_client’ is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) double",
            "d) string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘character_set_client’ is the character set for statements that arrive from the client. The session value of this variable is set using the character set requested by the client when client connects to server."
    },
    {
        "id": 836,
        "Question": "Which string function returns the index of the first occurrence of substring?",
        "Options": [
            "a) INSERT()",
            "b) INSTR()",
            "c) INSTRING()",
            "d) INFSTR()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘character_set_database’ is the character set used by the default database. The server sets the variable whenever the default database changes. If there is no default database the variable has the same value as ‘character_set_server’."
    },
    {
        "id": 837,
        "Question": "Which module links DBI to the web?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CGI.pn",
            "b) CGI.pem",
            "c) CGI.pm",
            "d) CGI.po"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The string funtion ‘INSTR()’ is used to return the index of the first occurrence of the substring. The function ‘INSERT()’ is used to insert a substring at the specified position up to the specified number of characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 838,
        "Question": "What does CGI stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Computer Gateway Interface",
            "b) Common Gateway Interface",
            "c) Computer Generated Interface",
            "d) Common Generated Interface"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The CGI.pm module is used to write scripts that use the ‘Common Gateway Interface’ protocol. It defines how a web server communicates with other programs. It provides an easy link."
    },
    {
        "id": 839,
        "Question": "The line that is written at the top of the script to write a Perl script using CGI.pm is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) use this CGI",
            "b) put CGI",
            "c) use CGI",
            "d) include CGI"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘CGI.pm’ module is so called because it helps write scripts that use the ‘Common Gateway Interface’ protocol which defines how a web server communicates with other programs."
    },
    {
        "id": 840,
        "Question": "What is the shebang line?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #!",
            "b) !#",
            "c) #$",
            "d) $#"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In order to write a Perl script that uses the ‘CGI.pm’ module, a ‘use CGI’ statement is included near the beginning of the script that imports the function names of the module."
    },
    {
        "id": 841,
        "Question": "Which of these is a read only variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) error_count",
            "b) big_tables",
            "c) autocommit",
            "d) foreign_key_checks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The session only system variable ‘error_count’ is a read only variable that indicates the number of errors generated by the last statement that can generate errors. The others are writable."
    },
    {
        "id": 842,
        "Question": "Which variable when set to 1 would enable foreign key checking for InnoDB tables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) error_count",
            "b) identity",
            "c) foreign_key_checks",
            "d) autocommit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Setting the variable ‘foreign_key_checks’ to 0 or 1 disables or enables the foreign key checking for InnoDB tables. The default is to perform checking. Disabling key checks can also be helpful."
    },
    {
        "id": 843,
        "Question": "The synonym for last_insert_id session variable is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) insert_id",
            "b) identity",
            "c) sql_auto_is_null",
            "d) sql_big_selects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The session only system variable ‘identity’ is a synonym for the ‘last_insert_id’ session variable. Setting ‘last_insert_id’ specifies the value to be returned by the function ‘LAST_INSERT_ID()’."
    },
    {
        "id": 844,
        "Question": "When building from source, the embedded server library is enabled by what?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –with-embedded-server",
            "b) –with-server-embedded",
            "c) –with-embedded-library",
            "d) –with-library-embedded"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: While building from the source, the embedded server library is enabled by using the option ‘–with-embedded-server’ while running ‘configure’. This applies equally to MySQL 5.0 and 5.1."
    },
    {
        "id": 845,
        "Question": "5. How many among the following use NULL to indicate failure?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_init<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_connect<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Both of the client library routines named ‘mysql_init()’ and ‘mysql_real_connect()’ return a pointer to the connection handler in order to indicate success and NULL to indicate failure."
    },
    {
        "id": 846,
        "Question": "6. How many among the following does not return a value?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">mysql_close<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_init<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_connect</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is not necessary that every Application Programming Interface call would return a value. For example, the client routine named ‘mysql_close()’ returns void, that is, it does not return a value."
    },
    {
        "id": 847,
        "Question": "What returns a string containing an error message?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_error()",
            "b) mysql_errno()",
            "c) mysql_sqlstate()",
            "d) mysql_close()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The API call named ‘mysql_error()’ returns a string containing an error message. ‘mysql_close()’ does not return any value at all. ‘mysql_errno()’ returns a MySQL-specific numeric code."
    },
    {
        "id": 848,
        "Question": "The statement that views status variables by aggregating the values over all connections is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHOW SESSION STATUS",
            "b) SHOW LOCAL STATUS",
            "c) SHOW GLOBAL STATUS",
            "d) SHOW STATUS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The MySQL server maintains various status variables that provide information about its operations. These variables and their values can be viewed by using the SHOW [GLOBAL | SESSION] STATUS statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 849,
        "Question": "Which keyword inserted in the SHOW STATUS statement shows the values for the current connection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GLOBAL",
            "b) SESSION",
            "c) LOCAL",
            "d) DEFAULT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The optional ‘GLOBAL’ keyword in the statement SHOW [GLOBAL | SESSION] STATUS statement aggregates the values over all connections and ‘SESSION’ shows the values for the current connection."
    },
    {
        "id": 850,
        "Question": "What is the synonym for last_insert_id session variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) insert_id",
            "b) identity",
            "c) sql_auto_is_null",
            "d) sql_big_selects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The session only system variable ‘identity’ is a synonym for the ‘last_insert_id’ session variable. Setting ‘last_insert_id’ specifies the value to be returned by the function ‘LAST_INSERT_ID()’."
    },
    {
        "id": 851,
        "Question": "The Audit_log_events system variable is of type _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) string",
            "b) integer",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The system variable ‘Audit_log_events’ is of type integer. The variable scope if GLOBAL, that is, it can be viewed by issuing the statement ‘SHOW GLOBAL STATUS’, instead of ‘SESSION’."
    },
    {
        "id": 852,
        "Question": "The option that executes all SQL statements in a SQL script irrespective of the number of errors is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –ensure",
            "b) –force",
            "c) –violent",
            "d) –run"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function ‘mysql_next_result()’ returns a status and initiates retrieval of the next set if more results are available. The status is zero if more results are available and -1 if not."
    },
    {
        "id": 853,
        "Question": "7. What is the number of attributes in the following SQL table?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">TABLE</span> employee <span class=\"br0\">(</span>\n\t\temp_name <span class=\"kw1\">CHAR</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n\t\temp_id <span class=\"kw1\">INT</span>\n\t<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 30"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If SQL queries in a file are run using mysql in batch mode, mysql either quits after the first error. If the –force option is specified all the queries are executed indiscriminately."
    },
    {
        "id": 854,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The name of the table created is ’employee’. It has two attributes, namely, ’emp_name’ and ’emp_id’. The attributes are the columns in a table. emp_name is of type string and emp_id is of type integer."
    },
    {
        "id": 855,
        "Question": "What does mysql_fetch_row() return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) structure",
            "d) pointer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, it is important to note that ‘SELECT’ is not the only statement that returns some rows. Statements like ‘SHOW’, ‘DESCRIBE’, ‘EXPLAIN’ and ‘CHECK TABLE’ do so as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 856,
        "Question": "Hexadecimal values assigned to user variables are treated as _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) strings",
            "b) non binary strings",
            "c) binary strings",
            "d) integers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The user defined variables are session specific. A user variable defined by one client cannot be seen or used by other clients. A user with access to the Performance Schema user_variables_by_thread table can see all user variables for all sessions is an exception."
    },
    {
        "id": 857,
        "Question": "What is the type of Audit_log_events system variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) string",
            "b) integer",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The hexadcimal or bit values assigned to user variables are treated as binary strings. In order to assign a hexadecimal or bit value as a number to a user variable, it is used in a numeric context."
    },
    {
        "id": 858,
        "Question": "The option that enables multiple-statement execution is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS",
            "b) CLIENT_STATEMENTS_MULTI",
            "c) MULTI_STATEMENTS_CLIENT",
            "d) MULTI_CLIENTS_STATEMENTS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The system variable ‘Audit_log_events’ is of type integer. The variable scope if GLOBAL, that is, it can be viewed by issuing the statement ‘SHOW GLOBAL STATUS’, instead of ‘SESSION’."
    },
    {
        "id": 859,
        "Question": "6. What is preferred when stored procedures are not being used?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\tCLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_set_server_option<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS",
            "b) mysql_set_server_option()",
            "c) any of the two",
            "d) neither of the two"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘multiple-statement’ execution is not enabled by default, so the server must be told that it is intended to be used. There are two ways to tell the server to enable the execution."
    },
    {
        "id": 860,
        "Question": "7. The one that is more restrictive is __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\">\tmysql_query<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mysql_real_query<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysql_query()",
            "b) mysql_real_query()",
            "c) same",
            "d) machine dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two ways to enable the multiple-statement execution. The first is to add the ‘CLIENT_MULTI_STATEMENTS’ option in the flags argument to ‘mysql_real_connect()’ at connect time."
    },
    {
        "id": 861,
        "Question": "What does mysql_query() return on failure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) a non-zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the program does not use stored procedures anyone is suitable. If the program uses stored procedures and invokes a ‘CALL’ statement that returns a result set, the first method is better."
    },
    {
        "id": 862,
        "Question": "Which statement upgrades the database directory name encoding?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER DATABASE",
            "b) ALTER SERVER",
            "c) ALTER EVENT",
            "d) ALTER FUNCTION"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement ‘ALTER DATABASE’ changes database attributes or upgrades the database directory name encoding. It requires the ‘ALTER’ privilege for the database to be given."
    },
    {
        "id": 863,
        "Question": "The statement that alters an existing event to have the given definition is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ALTER EVENT",
            "b) ALTER DATABASE",
            "c) ALTER FUNCTION",
            "d) ALTER DATABASE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement ‘ALTER EVENT’ alters an existing event to have the given definition. The ‘RENAME TO’ clause renames the event. The other clauses are described in the entry for ‘CREATE EVENT’."
    },
    {
        "id": 864,
        "Question": "What sets up an association between one or more MyISAM tables and the named key cache?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN",
            "b) CACHE INDEX",
            "c) ALTER DATABASE",
            "d) ALTER EVENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘CACHE INDEX’ sets up an association between one or more MyISAM tables and the named key cache which must already exist. The INDEX privilege is needed for each table named in the statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 865,
        "Question": "Which statement can produce the same output as ‘SHOW COLUMNS’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESCRIBE",
            "b) DISPLAY",
            "c) SEE",
            "d) GET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘DESCRIBE’ statement with a table name or view name produces the same kind of output as the ‘SHOW COLUMNS’ statement. The ‘SHOW’ entry can be referred to for further information."
    },
    {
        "id": 866,
        "Question": "The option that executes all SQL statements in a SQL script irrespective of the number of errors is _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –run",
            "b) –ensure",
            "c) –force",
            "d) –violent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Writing an application that uses the embedded server is different from writing one that operates in a client/server context. A program that is written as a client/server application can easily be converted to use the embedded server."
    },
    {
        "id": 867,
        "Question": "The clause that is used to display information that matches a given pattern is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) WHERE",
            "b) IS",
            "c) SAME",
            "d) LIKE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If SQL queries in a file are run using mysql in batch mode, mysql either quits after the first error. If the –force option is specified all the queries are executed indiscriminately."
    },
    {
        "id": 868,
        "Question": "The header that should be included first is ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) my_global.h",
            "b) my_sys.h",
            "c) mysql.h",
            "d) my_local.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘LIKE’ clause filters information that matches a given pattern. ‘WHERE’ clause selects information that is specified by a condition. ‘IS’ is used to match the exact condition specified. "
    },
    {
        "id": 869,
        "Question": "What does mysql_init() return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) structure",
            "d) pointer to a structure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The file ‘my_global.h’ takes care of including several other header files that are likely to be generally useful, like ‘stdio.h’. It also includes Windows compatibility information."
    },
    {
        "id": 870,
        "Question": "The statement that constructs a branching flow-control construct is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN…END",
            "b) CASE",
            "c) ITERATE",
            "d) LEAVE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘CASE’ statement provides a branching flow-control construct. When the initial expression, ‘expr’, is present, CASE compares it to the expression following each ‘WHEN’."
    },
    {
        "id": 871,
        "Question": "Which statement terminates the execution of a function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN…END",
            "b) RETURN",
            "c) ITERATE",
            "d) LOOP"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘RETURN’ statement is used only within stored functions, not stored procedures, triggers, or events. When this statement is executed it terminates execution of the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 872,
        "Question": "Association between one or more MyISAM tables and the named key cache is set by _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN",
            "b) CACHE INDEX",
            "c) ALTER DATABASE",
            "d) ALTER EVENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘CACHE INDEX’ sets up an association between one or more MyISAM tables and the named key cache which must already exist. The INDEX privilege is needed for each table named in the statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 873,
        "Question": "Which statement exits a labeled flow-control construct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESCRIBE",
            "b) LEAVE",
            "c) LOOP",
            "d) RETURN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘LEAVE’ statement is used to exit a labeled flow-control construct. This statement must appear within the construct that has the given label. The syntax of the statement is ‘LEAVE label’."
    },
    {
        "id": 874,
        "Question": "What is the exec_stmt_ssl written in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) C++",
            "b) C",
            "c) Python",
            "d) Perl"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In MySQL, the ‘sampdb’ distribution contains a source file named ‘exec_stmt_ssl.c’ from which the client program ‘exec_stmt_ssl’ can be built. There is a procedure to build this file."
    },
    {
        "id": 875,
        "Question": "What does ‘mysql_query()’ return on failure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) a non-zero value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both of the functions named ‘mysql_query()’ and ‘mysql_real_query()’ return zero for statements that succeed. They return non zero for failure. A statement is successfully executed if the server accepts it."
    },
    {
        "id": 876,
        "Question": "What can be used in place of MYSQL_SERVER_VERSION?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIBMYSQL_VERSION",
            "b) LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "c) MYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "d) MYSQL_ID"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Generally, when linking to a static MySQL C client library, the client library and the client application must use the same compiler option when it is required to link the C runtime."
    },
    {
        "id": 877,
        "Question": "What can be used interchangeably with MYSQL_VERSION_ID?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LIBMYSQL_VERSION",
            "b) LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "c) MYSQL_VERSION_ID",
            "d) MYSQL_ID"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macros ‘LIBMYSQL_VERSION’ and ‘LIBMYSQL_VERSION_ID’ have the same values as ‘MYSQL_SERVER_VERSION’ and ‘MYSQL_VERSION_ID’ and the two sets of macros can be used in place of each other."
    },
    {
        "id": 878,
        "Question": "Which of these is not a comment specifying construct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #",
            "b) /* */",
            "c) —",
            "d) !#"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The MySQL server understands three types of comments. The single line ‘#’ construct, the multiline /*…*/ construct and the — comment construct. MySQL conforms to the comment standards of SQL."
    },
    {
        "id": 879,
        "Question": "What sets the association between one or more MyISAM tables and the named key cache?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BEGIN",
            "b) CACHE INDEX",
            "c) ALTER DATABASE",
            "d) ALTER EVENT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The MySQL double-dash (–) comment style is different from the comment style of standard SQL, which begins with just two dashes. It does not require the space before any following text."
    },
    {
        "id": 880,
        "Question": "The statement that exits a labeled flow-control construct is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESCRIBE",
            "b) LEAVE",
            "c) LOOP",
            "d) RETURN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘CACHE INDEX’ sets up an association between one or more MyISAM tables and the named key cache which must already exist. The INDEX privilege is needed for each table named in the statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 881,
        "Question": "The option that executes all SQL statements in a SQL script irrespective of the number of errors is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –force",
            "b) –run",
            "c) –ensure",
            "d) –violent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ‘LEAVE’ statement is used to exit a labeled flow-control construct. This statement must appear within the construct that has the given label. The syntax of the statement is ‘LEAVE label’."
    },
    {
        "id": 882,
        "Question": "The option that is necessary to compile a C program having math functions is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -lm",
            "b) -ln",
            "c) -lp",
            "d) -lq"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: With mysql, raw SQL statements can be entered. With MySQL programs input methods can be provided for the user that is more intuitive and easier to be used. So input handling is customized."
    },
    {
        "id": 883,
        "Question": "Which option is used for specifying the executable name while compiling with gcc?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -e",
            "b) -o",
            "c) -a",
            "d) -b"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If SQL queries in a file are run using mysql in batch mode, mysql either quits after the first error. If the –force option is specified all the queries are executed indiscriminately."
    },
    {
        "id": 884,
        "Question": "The file that can be used to execute multiple compile statements is _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) makefile",
            "b) dofile",
            "c) putfile",
            "d) pushfile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To compile a program written in the C language, it is compiled by issuing the option ‘-lm’. The examples of some math functions found in ‘math.h’ are floor(), sqrt(), pow(), log()."
    },
    {
        "id": 885,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “SELECT” clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Show me all Columns and rows",
            "b) Show me all columns",
            "c) Show me all rows",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 886,
        "Question": "Which of the following clause is evaluated in the last by database server?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) FROM",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “SELECT” clause is used to show all rows or columns therefore it evaluated at last.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 887,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Show all rows and columns of table “person”",
            "b) Show all rows of table “person”",
            "c) Show all columns of table “person”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer:a\nExplanation: “SELECT” clause is used to show all rows or columns.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 888,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of of the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> Fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Show only columns (person_id, Fname, lname) and rows related to these columns",
            "b) Show only columns (person_id, Fname, lname)",
            "c) Show all rows",
            "d) Show all columns except (person_id, Fname, lname)"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “SELECT” clause is used to show all rows and columns that are mention with the   query.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 889,
        "Question": "Can “SELECT” clause be used without the clause “FROM”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) YES",
            "b) NO",
            "c) DEPENDS",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “SELECT” clause is used to show rows and columns of a particular table and clause “from” is used to denote a  table name.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 890,
        "Question": "6. Find the error in the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No Error",
            "b) No table mentioned",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “SELECT” clause cannot be used without clause “FROM”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 891,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span>  <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Show all columns but only those rows which belongs to person_id=1",
            "b) Show all columns and rows",
            "c) Shows only columns person_id",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Clause “WHERE” is also used, which tells the compiler to show only that rows which belong to person_id=1.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 892,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> person_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Show only columns(person_id, fname, lname) but only those rows which belongs to person_id=1",
            "b) Show all columns and rows",
            "c) Shows only columns person_id",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation:  Clause “WHERE” is also used, which tells the compiler to show only that rows which are belong to person_id=1.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 893,
        "Question": "Which clause is mandatory with clause “SELECT” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FROM",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) Both FROM and WHERE",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “SELECT” clause cannot be used without clause “FROM”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 894,
        "Question": "Which among the following can also be included with “SELECT” clause while writing query in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Literals",
            "b) Expressions",
            "c) User defined functions",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation:  “SELECT clause” can also include Literals like ‘ACTIVE’, Expressions like emp_id*314, Built_in functions like UPPER ().\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 895,
        "Question": "2. Is there any error in executing the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ‘ACTIVE’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n       emp_id <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3.145</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n       <span class=\"kw1\">UPPER</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>lname<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n       <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> Employee;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) NO",
            "c) Depends on condition",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation:  “SELECT clause” includes the following:  Literals like ‘ACTIVE’, Expressions like emp_id*314, Built_in functions like UPPER ().\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 896,
        "Question": "3. Is there any error in executing the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">USER</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\nVERSION <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">DATABASE</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes, “FROM” is not used",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation:  Clause “FROM” is not necessary when we used “Built in” function with “SELECT” clause.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 897,
        "Question": "What is the need of “column Aliases” in “SELECT” clause?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To assign a new label to the column in result set",
            "b) To overwrite the existing column name in result set",
            "c) To modify the column name while using literals, Expression, built_in functions with “SELECT clause",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation:  “Column Aliases” are used to assign a new label to the columns in the result set without actually changing the column name.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 898,
        "Question": "5. What will be the result of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n‘ACTIVE’ <span class=\"kw1\">STATUS</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\nemp_id <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3.14</span> emp_pi<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">UPPER</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>lname<span class=\"br0\">)</span> last_name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) emp_id, ACTIVE, emp_id * 314, UPPER(lname)",
            "b) emp_id, Status, emp_pi, last_name",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Status, emp_pi, last_name are “column aliases”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 899,
        "Question": "6.  What will be the result of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n‘ACTIVE’ <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">STATUS</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\nemp_id <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3.14</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> emp_pi<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">UPPER</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>lname<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> last_name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) emp_id, ACTIVE, emp_id * 314, UPPER(lname)",
            "b) emp_id, Status, emp_pi, last_name",
            "c) Error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Status, emp_pi, last_name are “column aliases” and Keyword “AS” is optional.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 900,
        "Question": "Which Keyword is used to remove duplicate rows in the result set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DISTINCTS",
            "b) MODIFY",
            "c) DISTINCT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 901,
        "Question": "8. If in Table “account”, a column “cust_id” consists of {1,2,2,3,3,5,6,7,8,8} then what will be the output on executing the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> DISTINICT cust_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> account;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {1, 2, 2, 3, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 8}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8}",
            "c) { }",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: DISTINICT keyword will remove the duplicate entries in the result set.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 902,
        "Question": "9. If in Table “employee”, a column “emp_id” consists of {1,2,2,3,3,5,6,7,8,8} then what will be the output on executing the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> DISTINICT emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {1,2,2,3,3,5,6,7,8,8}",
            "b) {1,2,3,5,6,7,8}",
            "c) { }",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: DISTINICT keyword will remove the duplicate entries in the result set.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 903,
        "Question": "Which among the following is an optional Keyword?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DISTINICTS",
            "b) ALL",
            "c) AS",
            "d) Both AS and ALL"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: “AS” and “ALL” are optional.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 904,
        "Question": "How can we define the clause “FROM” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It defines the tables used by a query",
            "b) It defines the linking of tables in Mysql",
            "c) It defines the tables used by a query & linking of tables in Mysql",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 905,
        "Question": "Which of the following table exist in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Permanent Tables",
            "b) Virtual tables",
            "c) Temporary tables",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Depends on the query.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 906,
        "Question": "“CREATE TABLE …” command is used to create which type of table in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Permanent Tables",
            "b) Virtual tables",
            "c) Temporary tables",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: CREATE table is used to create permanent tables in database.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 907,
        "Question": "“CREATE VIEW …” command is used to create which type of table in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Permanent Tables",
            "b) Virtual tables",
            "c) Temporary tables",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: CREATE VIEW is used to create virtual tables.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 908,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “Temporary Tables” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rows returned by sub query",
            "b) Permanent tables",
            "c) Virtual tables",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “Temporary Tables” are output format of any query on Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 909,
        "Question": "“SELECT” clause cannot be used without which clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FROM",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) ORDER BY",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “FROM” clause is necessary to point out tables in the database.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 910,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct with respect to “VIEW”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) “VIEW”  is a query that stored in the data dictionary",
            "b) There is no data associated with “VIEW”",
            "c) “VIEW” creates virtual tables in Database",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 911,
        "Question": "8. Find the missing clause from the following SQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VIEW</span> person_1 <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> person_id\n_________person;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) FROM",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “CREATE VIEW” cannot be used without “FROM” clause.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 912,
        "Question": "9. In the following MySQL query, “person_1” belongs to which category of table in MySQL?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">CREATE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">VIEW</span> person_1 <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> person_id <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Permanent Tables",
            "b) Virtual tables",
            "c) Temporary tables",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “CREATE VIEW” creates “Virtual tables” only.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 913,
        "Question": "Which command is used to create “Temporary tables” in MySQL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE TABLE;",
            "b) CREATE VIEW",
            "c) Both CREATE TABLE; and CREATE VIEW",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: “Temporary Tables” are output format of any query.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 914,
        "Question": "What is the use of “VIEW” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To hide columns from the users",
            "b) To hide the complexity of the database",
            "c) To simplify complexity of database design",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 915,
        "Question": "2. Is there any error in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee e <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> department d\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO",
            "b) YES",
            "c) DEPEND",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: There will be no error in the query, as table name “employee” is replaced by ‘e’ and table name “department” is replaced by‘d’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 916,
        "Question": "3. Is there any error in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> e <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> department <span class=\"kw1\">AS</span> d\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) NO",
            "b) YES",
            "c) DEPEND",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: There will be no error in the query, as table name “employee” is replaced by ‘e’ and table name “department” is replaced by ‘d’ by using  “AS” keyword.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 917,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “true AND Null”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Null",
            "c) Depend",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 918,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “false AND Null”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) False",
            "b) Null",
            "c) Depend",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 919,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “Null AND Null”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Null",
            "c) False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 920,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “true OR Null”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Null",
            "c) False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 921,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “false OR Null”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Null",
            "c) False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 922,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “Null OR Null”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Null",
            "c) False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 923,
        "Question": "What will be the output of the following MySQL statement “NOT (Null)”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Null",
            "c) False",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 924,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of the “WHERE” clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Filtering out unwanted rows from result set",
            "b) Filtering out unwanted columns from result set",
            "c) Filtering out unwanted rows and columns from result set",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 925,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns and rows belong to table employee",
            "b) All columns but only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title”",
            "c) All columns don’t belong to table employee",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows therefore in above query only those rows will be selected which contain title as ‘HEAD TELLER’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 926,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>start_date<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">2013</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">24</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns and rows belong to table employee",
            "b) All columns but only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title” and 2013-01-24 as a “start_date”",
            "c)  All rows belong to table employee",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows therefore in above query only those rows will be selected which contain title as ‘HEAD TELLER’ and start_date  2013-01-24.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 927,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>start_date<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">2013</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">24</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns and rows belong to table employee",
            "b) All columns but only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title” or 2013-01-24 as a “start_date”",
            "c)  All rows belong to table employee",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows therefore in above query only those rows will be selected which contain title as ‘HEAD TELLER’ or start_date  2013-01-24.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 928,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>start_date&amp;gt;<span class=\"nu0\">2013</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">24</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns and rows belong to table employee",
            "b) All columns but only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title” and start_date are greater than 2013-01-24",
            "c)  All rows belong to table employee",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows therefore in above query only those rows will be selected which contain title as ‘HEAD TELLER’ and start_date is greater than 2013-01-24.\n "
    },
    {
        "id": 929,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>start_date&amp;gt;<span class=\"nu0\">2013</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">24</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns and rows belong to table employee",
            "b) All columns but only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title” OR start_date are greater than 2013-01-24",
            "c) All rows belong to table employee",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows therefore in above query only those rows will be selected which contain title as ‘HEAD TELLER’ OR start_date is greater than 2013-01-24.\n "
    },
    {
        "id": 930,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns",
            "b) Only those columns which are mention with “SELECT” clause",
            "c)  Columns mention with “SELECT” clause and only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows and “SELECT” clause is used to select columns from table.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 931,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’ <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">2008</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">24</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns",
            "b) Only those columns which are mention with “SELECT” clause",
            "c)  Columns mention with “SELECT” clause and only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title” and start_date as 2008-11-24",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: “WHERE” clause is used to filter out unwanted rows and “SELECT” clause is used to select columns from table.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 932,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’HEAD TELLER’ <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> start_date&amp;gt;<span class=\"nu0\">2008</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">23</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All columns",
            "b) Only those columns which are mention with “SELECT” clause",
            "c) Columns mention with “SELECT” clause and only those rows which contain ‘HEAD TELLER’ as a “title” and start_date>2008-11-23",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 933,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “GROUP BY” clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Group data by column values",
            "b) Group data by row values",
            "c) Group data by column and row values",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 934,
        "Question": "Which clause is similar to “HAVING” clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SELECT",
            "b) WHERE",
            "c) FROM",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “WHERE” is also used to filter the row values in Mysql.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 935,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “HAVING” clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To filter out the row values",
            "b) To filter out the column values",
            "c) To filter out the row and column values",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 936,
        "Question": "“COUNT” keyword belongs to which categories in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregate functions",
            "b) Operators",
            "c) Clauses",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 937,
        "Question": "Which among the following belongs to an “aggregate function”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COUNT",
            "b) UPPER",
            "c) LOWER",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 938,
        "Question": "Which of the following belongs to an “aggregate function”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) COUNT",
            "b) SUM/AVG",
            "c) MIN/MAX",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 939,
        "Question": "Which clause is used with an “aggregate functions”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GROUP BY",
            "b) SELECT",
            "c) WHERE",
            "d) Both GROUP BY and WHERE"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “GROUP BY” is used with aggregate functions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 940,
        "Question": "8. What is the significance of the statement “GROUP BY d.name” in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">COUNT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>emp_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span> emp_no\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> department d <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> Employee e\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">GROUP</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aggregation of the field “name” of both table",
            "b) Aggregation of the field “name” of table “department”",
            "c) Sorting of the field “name”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “GROUP BY” clause s used for aggregation of field.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 941,
        "Question": "9. What is the significance of the statement “HAVING COUNT (emp_id)>2” in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw1\">COUNT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>emp_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span> emp_no\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> department d <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> Employee e\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">GROUP</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name\n<span class=\"kw1\">HAVING</span> <span class=\"kw1\">COUNT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>emp_id<span class=\"br0\">)</span>&amp;gt;<span class=\"nu0\">2</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Filter out all rows whose total emp_id below 2",
            "b) Selecting those rows whose total emp_id>2",
            "c) Filter out all rows whose total emp_id below 2 & Selecting those rows whose total emp_id>2",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: “HAVING” clause are worked similar as “WHERE” clause.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 942,
        "Question": "Is “GROUP BY” clause is similar to “ORDER BY” clause?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause is used for sorting while “GROUP BY” clause is used for aggregation of fields.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 943,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “ORDER BY” clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting your result set using column data",
            "b) Aggregation of fields",
            "c) Sorting your result set using row data",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 944,
        "Question": "3. What is the significance of “ORDER BY” in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data of emp_id will be sorted",
            "b) Data of emp_id will be sorted in descending order",
            "c) Data of emp_id will be sorted in ascending order",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Sorting in ascending or descending order depends on keyword “DESC” and “ASC”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 945,
        "Question": "4. What will be the order of sorting in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> emp_name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> emp_name;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting {emp_id, emp_name}",
            "b) Sorting {emp_name, emp_id}",
            "c) Sorting (emp_id} but not emp_name",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the query, first “emp_id” will be sorted then emp_name with respect to emp_id.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 946,
        "Question": "5. If  emp_id contain the following set {9, 7, 6, 4, 3, 1, 2}, what will be the output on execution of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 7, 9}",
            "b) {2, 1, 4, 3, 7, 9, 6}",
            "c) {9, 7, 6, 4, 3, 1, 2}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause sort the emp_id in the result set.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 947,
        "Question": "6. If emp_id contain the following set {1, 2, 3, 4, 1, 1}, what will be the output on execution of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {1, 1, 1, 2, 3, 4}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3, 4, 1, 1}",
            "c) {1, 1, 2, 3, 4, 1}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause sort the emp_id in the result set.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 948,
        "Question": "7. If emp_id contain the following set {1, 2, 2, 3, 3, 1}, what will be the output on execution of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {1, 1, 2, 2, 3, 3}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3, 3, 2, 1}",
            "c) {2, 2, 1, 1, 3, 3}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause sort the emp_id in the result set.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 949,
        "Question": "8. If emp_id contain the following set {-1, -2, 2, 3, -3, 1}, what will be the output on execution of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {-3, -2, -1, 1, 2, 3}",
            "b) {-1, 1, -2, 2, -3, 3}",
            "c) {1, 2, 3, -1, -2, -3}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause sort the emp_id in the result set.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 950,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used for sorting the data in descending order in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESC",
            "b) ASC",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) MODIFY"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 951,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used for sorting the data in ascending order in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) DESC",
            "b) ASC",
            "c) ALTER",
            "d) MODIFY"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 952,
        "Question": "Keyword “ASC” and “DESC” cannot be used without which clause in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ORDER BY",
            "b) GROUP BY",
            "c) SELECT",
            "d) HAVING"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “ASC” or “DESC” are used to sort the result set in ascending or descending order therefore they cannot be used without “ORDER BY” clause.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 953,
        "Question": "2. What is the significance of “ORDER BY emp_id DESC” in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">DESC</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data of emp_id will be sorted in descending order",
            "b) Data of emp_id will be sorted in ascending order",
            "c) Data of emp_id will be sorted in either ascending or descending order",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Keyword “DESC” will sort the data in descending order.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 954,
        "Question": "3. What is the significance of “ORDER BY emp_id ASC” in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">ASC</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data of emp_id will be sorted in descending order",
            "b) Data of emp_id will be sorted in ascending order",
            "c) Data of emp_id will be sorted in either ascending or descending order",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Keyword “ASC” will sort the data in ascending order.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 955,
        "Question": "4. If emp_id contain the following set {9, 7, 6, 4, 3, 1, 2}, what will be the output on execution of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">DESC</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {9, 7, 6, 4, 3, 1, 2}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 7, 9}",
            "c) {2, 1, 3, 4, 6, 7, 9}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “DESC” clause sort the emp_id in the descending order.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 956,
        "Question": "5. If emp_id contain the following set {9, 7, 6, 4, 3, 1, 2}, what will be the output on execution of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">ASC</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) {9, 7, 6, 4, 3, 1, 2}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 7, 9}",
            "c) {2, 1, 3, 4, 6, 7, 9}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “ASC” clause sort the emp_id in the ascending order.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 957,
        "Question": "Find odd one out?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GROUP BY",
            "b) DESC",
            "c) ASC",
            "d) ORDER BY"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “ORDER BY”, “DESC”, “ASC” are related to sorting whereas “GROUP BY” is not related to sorting.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 958,
        "Question": "7. Is there any error in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fed_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">RIGHT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>fed_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No error",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause can be used with expression such as fed_id, which is a social security no like 111, 111, 111, therefore, we sort it taking only three digits from right.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 959,
        "Question": "8. Is there any error in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fed_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>fed_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No error",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause can be used with an expression such as fed_id which is a social security no like 111, 111, 111, therefore, we sort it taking only three digits from left.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 960,
        "Question": "9. Is there any error in the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fed_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">ORDER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">BY</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: “ORDER BY” clause can be used with Place holders.  Here “2” represent column “title” and “5” represent “fed_id”. Therefore it looks like “ORDER BY title, fed_id”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 961,
        "Question": "Which of the following operators is/are used in “Condition Evaluation”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) AND",
            "b) OR",
            "c) NOT",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 962,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True AND true =true",
            "b) True AND false= false",
            "c) False AND false= false",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 963,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True OR true =true",
            "b) True OR false= true",
            "c) False OR false= false",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 964,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NOT(true)=false",
            "b) NOT(false)=true",
            "c) Both NOT(true)=false and NOT(false)=true",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 965,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NOT(true AND true) =false",
            "b) NOT(false AND false)=true",
            "c) NOT (true AND false)= true",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 966,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?",
        "Options": [
            "a) NOT(true OR true) = false",
            "b) NOT(false OR false)= true",
            "c) NOT (true OR false)= false",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 967,
        "Question": "7. What will be the result of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> TITLE<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ‘teller’ <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> start_date &amp;lt; ’<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only tellers who began working for the bank prior to 2007 will be included",
            "b) Any employee who is either not a teller or began working for the bank in 2007 or later will be removed from consideration",
            "c) Only tellers who began working for the bank prior to 2007 will not be included",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: The operator “AND” will evaluate only those sets which satisfy both side.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 968,
        "Question": "8. What will be the result of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> TITLE<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’teller’ <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The employee is a teller and was employed prior to 2007",
            "b) The employee is a teller and was employed after January 1, 2007",
            "c) The employee is something other than a teller but was employed prior to 2007",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: The operator “OR” will evaluate all result which satisfies either side of the query.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 969,
        "Question": "9. What will be the result of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> end_date <span class=\"kw1\">IS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span> \n<span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’teller’ <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> start_date &amp;lt; ‘<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those rows will be selected whose” end_date” should be NULL",
            "b) Only those rows are selected whose “TITLE” should be ‘teller’",
            "c) Only those employee will be selected who joined the organisation prior to 2007",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 970,
        "Question": "10. What will be the result of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> end_date <span class=\"kw1\">IS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span> \n<span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NOT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’teller’ <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> start_date &amp;lt; ‘<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The result set contains non terminated employees who both are non tellers and started working for the bank from 2007 or later",
            "b) The result set contains employees who both are tellers and started working for the bank in 2007 or later",
            "c) The result set contains employees who are only tellers",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 971,
        "Question": "Select odd one out?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equality Conditions",
            "b) Inequality Conditions",
            "c) Range condition",
            "d) Between"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: “Between” is an operator while others are conditions types.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 972,
        "Question": "2. The following MySQL query belongs to which condition types?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> title<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’TELLER’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equality condition",
            "b) Inequality condition",
            "c) Range condition",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the following query column equate to the string value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 973,
        "Question": "3. The following MySQL statement belongs to which condition types?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> fed_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’<span class=\"nu0\">111</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">111</span>’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equality condition",
            "b) Inequality condition",
            "c) Range condition",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the following query column equate to the string value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 974,
        "Question": "4. The following MySQL statement belongs to which condition types?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> dept_id<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> dept_id <span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> department <span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> names<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’s’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equality condition",
            "b) Inequality condition",
            "c) Range condition",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the following query column equate to the value returned by subquery.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 975,
        "Question": "5. Is the following MySQL statement belongs to the “Equality condition”?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> product<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> product_type <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> Product\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>Product<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’customers_accounts’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the following query there are two equality conditions “ON” and “WHERE”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 976,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “Equality Conditions”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equal to",
            "b) Not equal to",
            "c) Both Equal to and Not equal to",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer:a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 977,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “Inequality Condition”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Not equal to",
            "b) Equal to",
            "c) Both Not equal to and Equal to",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 978,
        "Question": "8. Does the following MySQL statement belong to the “Inequality condition”?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> product<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> product_type <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> Product\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>Product<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;&gt;</span>’customers_accounts’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the following query operator “<>” are inequality operator.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 979,
        "Question": "9. Does the following MySQL statement belong to the “Inequality condition”?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> product<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> product_type <span class=\"kw1\">INNER</span> <span class=\"kw1\">JOIN</span> Product\n<span class=\"kw1\">ON</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>Product<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>dept\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> product_type<span class=\"sy0\">.</span>name! <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’customers_accounts’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: In the following query operator “!=” are inequality operator.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 980,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “Range Conditions”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Expression is equal to Expression",
            "b) Expression is not equal to Expression",
            "c) Expression fall under certain range",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 981,
        "Question": "Which among the following data types can be used with “Range Condition”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Numeric data type",
            "b) Temporal data type",
            "c) String data type",
            "d) Both Numeric and Temporal data type"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 982,
        "Question": "3. The following MySQL statement belongs to which “Condition Types”?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> account\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>’<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>08’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equality conditions",
            "b) Inequality condition",
            "c) Range condition",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: In the following query expression fall under certain ranges.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 983,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> start_date <span class=\"kw1\">BETWEEN</span> ‘<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’ <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> ‘<span class=\"nu0\">2008</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees details between 2007 and 2008",
            "b) All employees details before 2008",
            "c) All employees details from 2007 to 2008",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “BETWEEN” operator is used for upper – upper limit.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 984,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> start_date<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;=</span>’<span class=\"nu0\">2007</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’ <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span>\n        Start_date<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;=</span>’<span class=\"nu0\">2005</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>01’</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees between 2007 and 2005",
            "b) All employees from 2007 to 2005",
            "c) Empty set",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 985,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> customer_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> product_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> avail_balance\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> account\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> avail_balance <span class=\"kw1\">BETWEEN</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3000</span> <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5000</span><span class=\"sy0\">.</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those details will be shown whose as available balance form 3000 to 5000",
            "b) Only those details will be shown whose available balance is more than 3000",
            "c) Only those details will be shown whose available balance is less than 5000",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: No query can have a date which is greater than ‘2007-01-01’ but less than ‘2005-01-01.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 986,
        "Question": "Which among the following operators is/are belongs to “Inequality conditions”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) <>",
            "b) !=",
            "c) =",
            "d) Both <> and !="
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 987,
        "Question": "Which among the following operators is/are belongs to “Equality conditions”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) <>",
            "b) !=",
            "c) =",
            "d) >/<"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 988,
        "Question": "Which among the following operators is/are belongs to “Range conditions”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) <>",
            "b) !=",
            "c) =",
            "d) >/<"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 989,
        "Question": "1. Find the error in the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> cust_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fed_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> customer\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> cust_id <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ’I’\n<span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> fed_id <span class=\"kw1\">BETWEEN</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5000</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>00<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>000 <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9999</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">999</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>000;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Range too high to compare",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: In the following query, there will be no error in executing as 5000-00-000 AND 9999-999-000 is “string ranges”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 990,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> account_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> product_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> cust_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> account\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> product_id <span class=\"kw1\">IN</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>‘sav’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ‘chd’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ‘mm’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those values are selected whose product_id is either ‘sav’, ‘chd’, ‘mm’",
            "b) Only those values are selected whose product_id is either ‘sav’’",
            "c) Only those values are selected whose product_id is either ‘sav’, ‘chd’",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “IN” operator is used to combine the expressions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 991,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> account_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> product_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> cust_id\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> account\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> product_id <span class=\"kw1\">NOT</span> <span class=\"kw1\">IN</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>‘sav’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ‘chd’<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ‘mm’<span class=\"br0\">)</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those values are selected whose product_id does not belong to either ‘sav’, ‘chd’, ‘mm’",
            "b) Only those values are selected whose product_id does not belong to either ‘sav’’",
            "c) Only those values are selected whose product_id does not belong to either ‘sav’, ‘chd’",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: “NOT IN” worked opposite of “IN” operator.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 992,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Only those value whose subjects are c and c++.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 993,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Only those value whose subjects are not c and c++ therefore answer is {1, 2, 3, 4}.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 994,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "6. Consider a database name “Sanfoundry” whose attributes are intern_id (primary key), subject, subject_value.",
            "Intern_id = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}",
            "Subject = {sql, oop, sql, oop, c, c++}",
            "Subject_value = {0, 0, 1, 1, 2, 2, 3, 3}",
            "If these are one to one relation then what will be the output of the following MySQL statement?"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Only those value will be selected whose subjects are c and c++. In the sub query subject_value=3 which belongs to subject {c, c++} after that this subject belong to intern_id {5, 6).\n "
    },
    {
        "id": 995,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Only those value will be selected whose subjects are c, c++, sql, oop. In the sub query subject_value=3 OR 2 which belongs to subject {c, c++, sql, oop} after that this subject belong to intern_id (1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6).\n "
    },
    {
        "id": 996,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "7. Consider a database name “Sanfoundry” whose attributes are intern_id (primary key), subject, subject_value.",
            "Intern_id = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}",
            "Subject = {sql, oop, sql, oop, c, c++}",
            "Subject_value = {0, 0, 1, 1, 2, 2, 3, 3}",
            "If these are one to one relation then what will be the output of the following MySQL statement?"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Only those value whose subjects are not {c, c++, oop} therefore answer is {1, 4}.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 997,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Only those value whose subjects are {c, c++, oop} therefore answer is {2, 4, 5, 6}.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 998,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) {1, 4}"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 999,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) {2, 4, 5, 6}"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 1000,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) {5, 6}",
            "b) {1, 2, 3}",
            "c) {3, 4}",
            "d) Empty set"
        ]
    },
    {
        "id": 1001,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’T’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those employees are selected whose last name started with ‘T’",
            "b) Only those employees are selected whose last name started with other than ‘T’",
            "c) All of the mentioned",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1002,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’F’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those employees are selected whose last name started with ‘F’",
            "b) Only those employees are selected whose last name started with other than ‘F’",
            "c) All of the mentioned",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1003,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’F’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those employees are selected whose first name started with ‘F’",
            "b) Only those employees are selected whose first name started with other than ‘F’",
            "c) All of the mentioned",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1004,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> emp_id<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>fname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’F’ <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> <span class=\"kw1\">LEFT</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>lname<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>’F’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those employees are selected whose first name and last name started with ‘F’",
            "b) Only those employees are selected whose first name started with ‘F’ but last name can be starts with any other letter",
            "c) Only those employees are selected whose first name and last name started with any other letter except ‘F’",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1005,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> ‘_a%e%’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees whose last name start with any letter but second letter should be ‘a’",
            "b) All employees whose last name start with any letter but contain at least one ‘e’ in his name",
            "c) All employees whose last name should have letter ‘a’ in second position and at least one ‘e’ in his name",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n "
    },
    {
        "id": 1006,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> ‘F%’ <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> ‘%T’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees whose last name should started with ‘F’",
            "b) All employees whose last name end with ‘T’",
            "c) All employees whose last name should started with ‘F’ and end with ‘T’",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1007,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> ‘F%’ <span class=\"kw1\">AND</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> ‘%T’;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees whose last name should started with ‘F’ and end with ‘T’",
            "b) All employees whose last name start with ‘T’ and end with ‘F’",
            "c) All employees whose last name should started with ‘F’ and end with ‘F’",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1008,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> %bas% <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> fname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> %bbs%;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees whose last name should contain substring “bas”",
            "b) All employees whose first name should contain substring “bbs”",
            "c) All employees whose last name should contain substring “bas” or first name should contain substring “bbs”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1009,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following MySQL statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> employee\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> lname <span class=\"kw1\">LIKE</span> %t%f%n%;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) All employees whose last name contain ‘t’ in the second position",
            "b) All employees whose last name contains ‘f’ in the fourth position",
            "c) All employees whose last name contains ‘n’ in second last position",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n "
    },
    {
        "id": 1010,
        "Question": "What is the meaning of “NULL” in Mysql?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Not applicable",
            "b) Value not yet known",
            "c) Value undefined",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1011,
        "Options": [
            "2. Is the following statement is true/false?",
            "“An expression can be NULL,  but can never equal to NULL”",
            "a) True",
            "b) False"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1012,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "3. Is the following statement is true/false?",
            "“Two NULL values are equal to each other”",
            "a) True",
            "b) False"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1013,
        "Question": "Which operator is used to check whether the expression is “NULL”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IS NULL",
            "b) NOT NULL",
            "c)  ON",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1014,
        "Question": "Which operator is used to check the expression is not “NULL”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) IS NULL",
            "b) NOT NULL",
            "c) ON",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1015,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">IS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those columns whose emp_id is NULL",
            "b) Only those columns whose emp_id is not NULL",
            "c) No output",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1016,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> \n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">IS</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those columns whose emp_id is NULL",
            "b) Only those columns whose emp_id is not NULL",
            "c) No output",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1017,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> emp_id <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those columns whose emp_id is NULL",
            "b) Only those columns whose emp_id is not NULL",
            "c) No output",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: An expression can never be equated to NULL that is why there will be no output.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1018,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> emp_id !<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those names whose emp_id is not equal to 6",
            "b) Only those names whose emp_id is equal to 6",
            "c) No output",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1019,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following MySQL command?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"sql\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">SELECT</span> fname\n<span class=\"kw1\">FROM</span> person\n<span class=\"kw1\">WHERE</span> emp_id !<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span> <span class=\"kw1\">OR</span> emp_id <span class=\"kw1\">IS</span>  <span class=\"kw1\">NULL</span>;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only those names whose emp_id is not equal to 6 or emp_id with NULL values",
            "b) Only those names whose emp_id is not equal to 6",
            "c) Only those names whose emp_id is equal to 6",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1020,
        "Question": "The program that copies the databases from one server to another is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) mysqldbcopy",
            "b) mysqlcopydb",
            "c) mysqlflushdb",
            "d) mysqldbflush"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The utility program ‘mysqldbcopy’ is capable of copying databases from one server to another server. It can also prepare copies to make transfers on the same servers. This can be done simply by running the program."
    },
    {
        "id": 1021,
        "Question": "Which privileges are required on the source server to use mysqldbcopy?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CREATE",
            "b) INSERT",
            "c) UPDATE",
            "d) SELECT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To use the utility program ‘mysqldbcopy’, the user must have SELECT privileges for the database(s) on the source server and have CREATE, INSERT, UPDATE on the destination server."
    },
    {
        "id": 1022,
        "Question": "Which option is used in mysqldump to make all tables in the destination databases to use a different storage engine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –next-storage-engine",
            "b) –new-storage-engine",
            "c) –clear-storage-engine",
            "d) –get-storage-engine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: While using the program ‘mysqldump’ in MySQL to copy databases from server to server, all tables in the destination databases can be directed to use a different storage engine with the –new-storage-engine option."
    },
    {
        "id": 1023,
        "Question": "The function that returns reference to hash of row values is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    },
    {
        "id": 1024,
        "Question": "The best datatype for a column that is expected to store values up to 2 million is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SMALLINT",
            "b) TINYINT",
            "c) MEDIUMINT",
            "d) BIGINT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The different numeric types used in MySQL are used to store different range of values. To store values of the order of a million, the MEDIUMINT or BIGINT datatype is sufficient."
    },
    {
        "id": 1025,
        "Question": "Which type stores the longest length of strings?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHAR",
            "b) VARCHAR",
            "c) TINYTEXT",
            "d) TEXT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: in MySQL, the different string datatypes are used to store different lenghts of the string. Here, the length would refer to the number of characters in the string. TEXT stores longer strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 1026,
        "Question": "The security context when a user creates a stored program that accesses sensitive data but forgets that other people who can invoke the object have the same access is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) bad",
            "b) good",
            "c) fare",
            "d) illegal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The security context is bad if a user creates a stored program that accesses sensitive data but forgets that other people who can invoke the object have the same access to that data as its definer."
    },
    {
        "id": 1027,
        "Question": "The number of files that each end of a client/server connection including SSL support use to set up secure communications is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: With a MySQL installation that includes SSL support the server and its clients can communicate securely. Each end of a connection uses three files to set up secure communications."
    },
    {
        "id": 1028,
        "Question": "What is the TLS protocol?",
        "Options": [
            "a) transparent layer security",
            "b) transport layer security",
            "c) transparent level security",
            "d) transport level security"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MySQL supports encrypted connections between clients and the server using the TLS protocol. It is also referred to as SSL but MySQL does not actually use the SSL protocol for encrypted connections."
    },
    {
        "id": 1029,
        "Question": "Which grant table scope columns are case insensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Host",
            "b) User",
            "c) Password",
            "d) Db"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Db’ and ‘Table_name’ values are always treated as case sensitive even though the treatment of database and table names in SQL statements depends on the filesystem case sensitivity of the host."
    },
    {
        "id": 1030,
        "Question": "The variable that checks for availability of SSL support is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) have_ssl",
            "b) has_ssl",
            "c) avail_ssl",
            "d) ssl_avail"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: After the SSL-capable server is started, to verify that it supports SSL, connection is established with ‘mysql’ and the following query is issued: SHOW VARIABLES LIKE ‘have_ssl’."
    },
    {
        "id": 1031,
        "Question": "The function that returns a reference to an array of row values is ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) fetchrow_array()",
            "b) fetchrow_arrayref()",
            "c) fetch()",
            "d) fetchrow_hashref()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In MySQL, there is no data type provided which has an optional time part. The ‘DATE’ type values never have a time part. The ‘DATETIME’ type values must have a time part in them."
    },
    {
        "id": 1032,
        "Question": "The log in which data changes received from a replication master server are written is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) error log",
            "b) general query log",
            "c) binary log",
            "d) relay log"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘fetchrow_arrayref()’ returns a reference to an array of row values. The function ‘fetchrow_hashref()’ returns reference to hash of row values. ‘fetch()’ is the same as fetchrow_arrayref()."
    }
]